[
  {
    "title": "3.1",
    "pretest": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "Let them FROLIC.",
          "answers": [
            "jump up",
            "sit still",
            "laugh loudly",
            "play merrily",
            "run fast"
          ],
          "word": "FROLIC",
          "correct": "play merrily"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Doesn't like CONGESTION.",
          "answers": [
            "joking",
            "loneliness",
            "overcrowding",
            "arguing",
            "heights"
          ],
          "word": "CONGESTION",
          "correct": "overcrowding"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "VIOLATE the rule.",
          "answers": [
            "break",
            "honor",
            "think about",
            "despise",
            "ignore"
          ],
          "word": "VIOLATE",
          "correct": "break"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The INTERMEDIATE course.",
          "answers": [
            "final",
            "middle",
            "communications",
            "easy",
            "next"
          ],
          "word": "INTERMEDIATE",
          "correct": "middle"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Tremendous RECEPTION.",
          "answers": [
            "trick",
            "sympathy",
            "welcome",
            "favor",
            "farewell"
          ],
          "word": "RECEPTION",
          "correct": "welcome"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "To STEER it.",
          "answers": [
            "plan",
            "enter",
            "laugh at",
            "finish",
            "guide"
          ],
          "word": "STEER",
          "correct": "guide"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He SUBSTITUTED it",
          "answers": [
            "started",
            "did without",
            "exchanged",
            "supported",
            "weakened"
          ],
          "word": "SUBSTITUTE",
          "correct": "exchanged"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "From the VICINITY.",
          "answers": [
            "neighborhood",
            "hotel",
            "city",
            "church",
            "devil"
          ],
          "word": "VICINITY",
          "correct": "neighborhood"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "ABRUPT decision.",
          "answers": [
            "hard",
            "sudden",
            "evil",
            "stupid",
            "important"
          ],
          "word": "ABRUPT",
          "correct": "sudden"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Quite EVIDENT.",
          "answers": [
            "true",
            "difficult",
            "unusual",
            "common",
            "clear"
          ],
          "word": "EVIDENT",
          "correct": "clear"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Wanted to BAN it.",
          "answers": [
            "forget",
            "allow",
            "collect",
            "forbid",
            "destroy"
          ],
          "word": "BAN",
          "correct": "forbid"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "We ENDURED his insults.",
          "answers": [
            "put up with",
            "hated",
            "were hurt by",
            "returned",
            "didn't listen to"
          ],
          "word": "ENDURE",
          "correct": "put up with"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Ended the FEUD.",
          "answers": [
            "long quarrel",
            "riot",
            "hatred",
            "world war",
            "tragedy"
          ],
          "word": "FEUD",
          "correct": "long quarrel"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "FRISKY pets.",
          "answers": [
            "slow",
            "lively",
            "friendly",
            "bad-tempered",
            "fast"
          ],
          "word": "FRISKY",
          "correct": "lively"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "To PAMPER her.",
          "answers": [
            "dress",
            "punish",
            "bother",
            "spoil",
            "admire"
          ],
          "word": "PAMPER",
          "correct": "spoil"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_1": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "Do people usually FROLIC at funerals?",
          "word": "FROLIC",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is there likely to be CONGESTION on a desert island?",
          "word": "CONGESTION",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Does a person VIOLATE the law when he steals something?",
          "word": "VIOLATE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would an expert have problems with something at an INTERMEDIATE level of difficulty?",
          "word": "INTERMEDIATE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can a dog give you a warm RECEPTION?",
          "word": "RECEPTION",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can a car be STEERED?",
          "word": "STEER",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is margarine used as a SUBSTITUTE for butter?",
          "word": "SUBSTITUTE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is New York City in the VICINITY of Los Angeles?",
          "word": "VICINITY",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "If a television program ended in the middle of a sentence, would its ending be ABRUPT?",
          "word": "ABRUPT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "If a person's anger is EVIDENT, is he hiding it very well?",
          "word": "EVIDENT",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "If someone tried to BAN baseball in the United States, would he be successful?",
          "word": "BAN",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would a lightning flash ENDURE for hours?",
          "word": "ENDURE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can a FEUD be stopped?",
          "word": "FEUD",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is a snail a FRISKY animal?",
          "word": "FRISKY",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do you PAMPER a small child by spanking him?",
          "word": "PAMPER",
          "correct": "false"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_2": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "The baby was laughing and splashing and FROLICKING in the bathtub.",
          "word": "FROLIC",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "There was a lot of CONGESTION about what exactly we were supposed to do.",
          "word": "CONGESTION",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The prisoner claimed that his rights were VIOLATED because he wasn't allowed to speak to a lawyer.",
          "word": "VIOLATE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Thomas had to take INTERMEDIATE-level Spanish over again.",
          "word": "INTERMEDIATE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Magicians practice for a long time to become skillful in their RECEPTIONS.",
          "word": "RECEPTION",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "She tried to STEER the conversation toward a more interesting subject, but everyone else wanted to talk about sports.",
          "word": "STEER",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The store SUBSTITUTED a cheaper brand of paper for the one we ordered.",
          "word": "SUBSTITUTE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "We couldn't see him, but we knew he was somewhere in the VICINITY.",
          "word": "VICINITY",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "She ABRUPTLY decided she didn't like the dance, and left immediately.",
          "word": "ABRUPT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "EVIDENTLY we didn't make the team; our names aren't on the list.",
          "word": "EVIDENT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "As punishment, their parents placed a BAN on watching television.",
          "word": "BAN",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "She was able to ENDURE the pain by taking aspirin three times a day.",
          "word": "ENDURE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "We refused to become involved in their silly FEUD.",
          "word": "FEUD",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The children were having a FRISKY game of tag.",
          "word": "FRISKY",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He said that even though he was ill he didn't want to be PAMPERED.",
          "word": "PAMPER",
          "correct": "true"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_3": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "FROLIC",
          "answers": [
            "play",
            "enjoy",
            "race"
          ],
          "word": "FROLIC",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "CONGESTION",
          "answers": [
            "crowding",
            "fullness",
            "finishing"
          ],
          "word": "CONGESTION",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "VIOLATE",
          "answers": [
            "break",
            "ill-treat",
            "choose"
          ],
          "word": "VIOLATE",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "INTERMEDIATE",
          "answers": [
            "middle",
            "edge",
            "center"
          ],
          "word": "INTERMEDIATE",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "RECEPTION",
          "answers": [
            "greeting",
            "admiring",
            "receiving"
          ],
          "word": "RECEPTION",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "STEER",
          "answers": [
            "stop",
            "lead",
            "drive"
          ],
          "word": "STEER",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "SUBSTITUTE",
          "answers": [
            "switch",
            "sell",
            "trade"
          ],
          "word": "SUBSTITUTE",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "VICINITY",
          "answers": [
            "sameness",
            "nearness",
            "neighborhood"
          ],
          "word": "VICINITY",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "ABRUPT",
          "answers": [
            "short",
            "sudden",
            "dangerous"
          ],
          "word": "ABRUPT",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "EVIDENT",
          "answers": [
            "plain",
            "probable",
            "obvious"
          ],
          "word": "EVIDENT",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "BAN",
          "answers": [
            "prevent",
            "forbid",
            "argue"
          ],
          "word": "BAN",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "ENDURE",
          "answers": [
            "agree",
            "continue",
            "bear"
          ],
          "word": "ENDURE",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "FEUD",
          "answers": [
            "loneliness",
            "fight",
            "anger"
          ],
          "word": "FEUD",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "FRISKY",
          "answers": [
            "powerful",
            "playful",
            "spirited"
          ],
          "word": "FRISKY",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "PAMPER",
          "answers": [
            "humor",
            "spoil",
            "respect"
          ],
          "word": "PAMPER",
          "correct": "2"
        }
      ]
    },
    "definitions": {
      "FROLIC": {
        "word": "FROLIC",
        "phonetic": "(frol'-ik)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to make merry, play happily, romp \nTo FROLIC is to play in a lighthearted, carefree way. The word is used especially about children or about people acting like children. \n\"I love to see children FROLIC at the beach.\" \n\"She FROLICKED about the yard, singing happily.\" \nFROLIC can also be used as a noun. \n\"After their FROLIC in the snow they came inside, cold but happy.\" \nUsage: The past tense of FROLIC is spelled FROLICKED."
      },
      "CONGESTION": {
        "word": "CONGESTION",
        "phonetic": "(kQn-jes'-chQn)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "overcrowding, overfullness \nTo CONGEST means to _overfill_ or _overcrowd_. \n\"The subway trains are always CONGESTED at five o'clock in the evening.\" \nCONGESTION is the state of being overcrowded or too full. \"Traffic CONGESTION\" is when there are so many cars on a street that traffic becomes blocked. \"Lung CONGESTION\" is when the lungs become so full of fluid that it is difficult to breathe. \n\"So many people crowded onto the subway platform that the CONGESTION was terrible.\" \n\"CONGESTION became so bad in the city that many people moved to the suburbs.\" \nOther forms of the word: CONGEST, v."
      },
      "VIOLATE": {
        "word": "VIOLATE",
        "phonetic": "(vl-ÔøΩIAt)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to break, interfere with, treat badly \nTo VIOLATE a law or rule is to break it, to fail to keep it. \n\"If you VIOLATE this law, you will be sent to jail.\" \n\"He VIOLATED our order to stay inside.\" \nIn another sense, VIOLATE means \"to treat in an improper manner.\" The word is used especially about non-physical things like rights or dignity. \n\"His orders VIOLATE our basic human rights.\" \n\"Bill didn't like anyone to VIOLATE his privacy.\" \nOther forms of the word: VIOLATION, n."
      },
      "INTERMEDIATE": {
        "word": "INTERMEDIATE",
        "phonetic": "(in-tÔøΩ-mE'-dE-it)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "in the middle, in between \nSee _inter-_ under Prefixes and _-ate2_ under Suffixes. The _medi_ part of INTERMEDIATE comes from the Latin word for _middle_, which is also the source of the word _medium_. Something that is INTERMEDIATE comes in the middle; it is, for example, between two stages, times, or extremes. \n\"He was too good for the beginners' group, and not good enough for the advanced group, so they put him in the INTERMEDIATE group.\" \n\"There are several INTERMEDIATE steps between starting the machine and getting the final product.\""
      },
      "RECEPTION": {
        "word": "RECEPTION",
        "phonetic": "(ri-sep'-shQn)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "a welcome, greeting \nRECEPTION is the act of receiving. It is often used about the receiving of guests. \n\"I got a cool RECEPTION from the host when I arrived two hours late.\" \nA wedding RECEPTION is the formal receiving of guests after a wedding. RECEPTION is used for other kinds of receiving as well, like the receiving of radio or television signals. \n\"We had very poor RECEPTION on our TV until we bought an antenna.\" On the Pretest, many people confuse RECEPTION with _farewell_, which is an exact opposite. \nOther forms of the word: RECEPTIVE, adj."
      },
      "STEER": {
        "word": "STEER",
        "phonetic": "(stEr)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to guide, lead, direct the course of \nTo STEER something is to guide it in a particular direction. The word can be used about physical objects like cars and boats and about conversations, interests, and the like. \n\"Jane STEERED the canoe with her paddle.\" \n\"He STEERED us quickly through the crowded station.\" \n\"You STEER a car by turning the STEERING wheel.\" \n\"We tried to STEER him toward college, but he wanted to work after high school.\""
      },
      "SUBSTITUTE": {
        "word": "SUBSTITUTE",
        "phonetic": "(suhb'-stÔøΩtUt)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to put in place of, take the place of, exchange \nSUBSTITUTE is both a verb and a noun. To SUBSTITUTE something is to put or use it in place of something else. \n\"He SUBSTITUTED the fake painting for the real one.\" \n\"You may SUBSTITUTE margarine for butter when you make this cake.\" \nWhen something SUBSTITUTES for something else, it takes the place of it. \n\"For a blind person, the other senses have to SUBSTITUTE for the sense of sight.\" \nA SUBSTITUTE is something that takes the place of something else. \n\"The coach sent Bill in as a SUBSTITUTE for the center.\" \nOther forms of the word: SUBSTITUTION, n."
      },
      "VICINITY": {
        "word": "VICINITY",
        "phonetic": "(vi-sin'-ÔøΩtE)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "neighborhood, surrounding area \nThe area surrounding a place is called the VICINITY. \"In the VICINITY of the school\" means \"near the school\" or \"in the neighborhood of the school.\" \n\"She lives in the VICINITY of the hospital. Her apartment is just across the street.\" \n\"There are several grocery stores in the VICINITY.\" \n\"The robber was seen leaving the VICINITY of the bank at two o'clock.\""
      },
      "ABRUPT": {
        "word": "ABRUPT",
        "phonetic": "(ÔøΩbruhpt')",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "sudden, unexpected; curt, blunt \nSomething that is ABRUPT happens without warning. It occurs so suddenly that it is almost unpleasant. \n\"His departure was ABRUPT, to say the least. One minute he was talking to me, the next minute he was gone.\" \nABRUPT is often used about people and their behavior. A person who is ABRUPT is brief almost to the point of rudeness in the way he acts or speaks. \n\"Mr. Ames has a rather ABRUPT manner that makes people feel he is eager to get rid of them.\""
      },
      "EVIDENT": {
        "word": "EVIDENT",
        "phonetic": "(ev'-ÔøΩdÔøΩnt)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "clear, apparent, obvious, plain \nSee _-ant_ under Suffixes. EVIDENT comes from the Latin root _vid_, which means to _see_. _Vid_ is also the source of the words _video_ and _vision_. Something that is EVIDENT is easily seen; it is plain and clear. It can be clear either to the eye or to the mind. \n\"Her anger was EVIDENT from the way she went around slamming doors.\" \n\"It became EVIDENT that our team just wasn't good enough to win.\" \n\"The man EVIDENTLY was wealthy; he lived in a mansion.\" \nOther forms of the word: EVIDENCE, n."
      },
      "BAN": {
        "word": "BAN",
        "phonetic": "(ban)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to forbid \nBAN means to _forbid_, \"to give an order that something must not be done.\" \n\"Cigarette smoking is BANNED in many restaurants.\" \n\"Jim's mother BANNED all yelling in the house.\" \nBAN is also a noun, and means \"an order forbidding something,\" a _prohibition_. \n\"The government put a BAN on buying or selling gold.\" \n\"There was a BAN on driving during the emergency.\""
      },
      "ENDURE": {
        "word": "ENDURE",
        "phonetic": "(en-dUr')",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to put up with, bear; to last, continue \nENDURE is related to the word _durable_. Both come from a Latin word that means _lasting_. ENDURE has two related meanings. The first is to _put up with_, especially with patience and for a long time. \n\"I can't ENDURE listening to his complaints again.\" \n\"Since you can't change the weather, you'll just have to ENDURE it.\" \n\"That tree has ENDURED wind and rain and snow, and still it has survived.\" \nThe second meaning is \"to continue to exist\" for a long time, to _last_. \n\"His desire to learn ENDURED throughout his life.\" \n\"The belief that the Earth was the center of the universe ENDURED for centuries.\" \nOther forms of the word: ENDURANCE, n."
      },
      "FEUD": {
        "word": "FEUD",
        "phonetic": "(fyUd)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "a long, bitter quarrel \nNote the pronunciation. A FEUD is a quarrel that goes on over a long period of time. It is always bitter and sometimes violent. \n\"They had forgotten what started the FEUD, but they were still angry with each other twenty years later.\" \n\"The FEUD between the two families was never really settled.\" \nFEUD can also be used as a verb. \n\"The two neighbors FEUDED over the location of the fence.\" \n\"He FEUDED with his brothers over his share of the inheritance.\""
      },
      "FRISKY": {
        "word": "FRISKY",
        "phonetic": "(fris'-kE)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "lively, playful, energetic \nOne meaning of the verb to FRISK is \"to move about playfully.\" \n\"The puppies FRISKED about on the lawn.\" \nFRISKY means \"given to FRISKING,\" _lively_, _playful_. See _-y_ under Suffixes. \n\"They thought the pony was too FRISKY, so they bought a slower, quieter one instead.\" \n\"The old man started to feel a bit FRISKY on the bright spring morning.\" \nFRISKY is often confused with _friendly_, perhaps because the two words look alike. A pet or person could be both FRISKY and _friendly_, but the two words do not have the same meaning. \nOther forms of the word: FRISK, v."
      },
      "PAMPER": {
        "word": "PAMPER",
        "phonetic": "(pam'-pÔøΩr)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to spoil, indulge, humor, coddle \nTo PAMPER someone is to treat him or her with too much care and attention, to be excessively kind. The word almost always suggests that this is a bad thing, and that the person who is PAMPERED may become spoiled as a result. \n\"They PAMPER their children. They let them stay up late and eat nothing but desserts.\" \n\"She decided to PAMPER herself and stay in bed till noon.\" \n\"She was PAMPERED as a child, and now she can't do anything for herself.\""
      }
    }
  },
  {
    "title": "3.2",
    "pretest": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "Saw him CRINGE.",
          "answers": [
            "bow",
            "fall down",
            "shrink back",
            "rise up",
            "give up"
          ],
          "word": "CRINGE",
          "correct": "shrink back"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Continues to PLAGUE me.",
          "answers": [
            "need",
            "support",
            "avoid",
            "torment",
            "hate"
          ],
          "word": "PLAGUE",
          "correct": "torment"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "These are SACRED.",
          "answers": [
            "evil",
            "holy",
            "related",
            "ancient",
            "beautiful"
          ],
          "word": "SACRED",
          "correct": "holy"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "PROVOKE a riot.",
          "answers": [
            "join",
            "stop",
            "plan",
            "stir up",
            "call off"
          ],
          "word": "PROVOKE",
          "correct": "stir up"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "What can we SALVAGE?",
          "answers": [
            "sell",
            "throw out",
            "destroy",
            "improve",
            "save"
          ],
          "word": "SALVAGE",
          "correct": "save"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Suddenly he SHUDDERED.",
          "answers": [
            "trembled",
            "stopped",
            "yelled",
            "hid",
            "moaned"
          ],
          "word": "SHUDDER",
          "correct": "trembled"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "We EXHAUSTED the supply.",
          "answers": [
            "reduced",
            "added to",
            "released",
            "cleaned up",
            "used up"
          ],
          "word": "EXHAUST",
          "correct": "used up"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "It was CONTAGIOUS.",
          "answers": [
            "ugly",
            "catching",
            "disgraceful",
            "safe",
            "dangerous"
          ],
          "word": "CONTAGIOUS",
          "correct": "catching"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "SPRAWL on the floor.",
          "answers": [
            "spread out",
            "slide",
            "run",
            "crawl",
            "sit down"
          ],
          "word": "SPRAWL",
          "correct": "spread out"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "LEAN men.",
          "answers": [
            "fat",
            "thin",
            "tired",
            "healthy",
            "old"
          ],
          "word": "LEAN",
          "correct": "thin"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Everyone was BEFUDDLED.",
          "answers": [
            "confused",
            "improved",
            "soiled",
            "tired",
            "amused"
          ],
          "word": "BEFUDDLE",
          "correct": "confused"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "They will CONSENT.",
          "answers": [
            "leave",
            "refuse",
            "agree",
            "decide",
            "improve"
          ],
          "word": "CONSENT",
          "correct": "agree"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Started to DESCEND.",
          "answers": [
            "argue",
            "come up",
            "go down",
            "take off",
            "go away"
          ],
          "word": "DESCEND",
          "correct": "go down"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "ENCHANTING plays.",
          "answers": [
            "excellent",
            "terrible",
            "exciting",
            "boring",
            "charming"
          ],
          "word": "ENCHANTING",
          "correct": "charming"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Started to DOMINATE them.",
          "answers": [
            "know",
            "obey",
            "hate",
            "rule",
            "destroy"
          ],
          "word": "DOMINATE",
          "correct": "rule"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_1": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "Do some people CRINGE at the sight of blood?",
          "word": "CRINGE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do people try to avoid PLAGUES?",
          "word": "PLAGUE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would SACRED things usually be thrown away?",
          "word": "SACRED",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would a slap in the face PROVOKE most people?",
          "word": "PROVOKE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can SALVAGE be valuable?",
          "word": "SALVAGE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would a person usually SHUDDER with joy?",
          "word": "SHUDDER",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is a gallon of milk EXHAUSTED when most of it is gone?",
          "word": "EXHAUST",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is a broken arm CONTAGIOUS?",
          "word": "CONTAGIOUS",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do skaters sometimes SPRAWL when they lose their balance?",
          "word": "SPRAWL",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Does LEAN meat have a lot of fat on it?",
          "word": "LEAN",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would a person who is BEFUDDLED give clear directions?",
          "word": "BEFUDDLE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would most people CONSENT to being given a raise?",
          "word": "CONSENT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Does a rock DESCEND when you drop it?",
          "word": "DESCEND",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do most students find homework ENCHANTING?",
          "word": "ENCHANTING",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Are palm trees the DOMINANT form of life at the North Pole?",
          "word": "DOMINATE",
          "correct": "false"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_2": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "The dog CRINGED when he saw that his master was angry with him.",
          "word": "CRINGE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "She was PLAGUED by doubts about her ability to sing in public.",
          "word": "PLAGUE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "In ancient times they considered this tree to be SACRED and offered sacrifices to it.",
          "word": "SACRED",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He had his license PROVOKED for three years.",
          "word": "PROVOKE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "They SALVAGED what they could from the office after it had been robbed.",
          "word": "SALVAGE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "It makes me SHUDDER to think of how close we all came to drowning.",
          "word": "SHUDDER",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Spring house cleaning left us all EXHAUSTED.",
          "word": "EXHAUST",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He was a rather CONTAGIOUS person, always getting angry at people for no reason.",
          "word": "CONTAGIOUS",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He SPRAWLED as quickly as he could from one side of the room to the other.",
          "word": "SPRAWL",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He kept himself LEAN by not overeating.",
          "word": "LEAN",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Sally was delighted when the most popular girl in the class BEFUDDLED her.",
          "word": "BEFUDDLE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The farmer said he would never CONSENT to sell his land.",
          "word": "CONSENT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The skier DESCENDED quickly to the bottom of the mountain.",
          "word": "DESCEND",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He wrote ENCHANTING stories which little children loved to read.",
          "word": "ENCHANTING",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Plans for escaping DOMINATED the thoughts of the prisoners.",
          "word": "DOMINATE",
          "correct": "true"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_3": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "CRINGE",
          "answers": [
            "bow",
            "shout",
            "cower"
          ],
          "word": "CRINGE",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "PLAGUE",
          "answers": [
            "bother",
            "torture",
            "fear"
          ],
          "word": "PLAGUE",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "SACRED",
          "answers": [
            "religious",
            "holy",
            "necessary"
          ],
          "word": "SACRED",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "PROVOKE",
          "answers": [
            "produce",
            "anger",
            "prevent"
          ],
          "word": "PROVOKE",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "SALVAGE",
          "answers": [
            "recover",
            "rescue",
            "release"
          ],
          "word": "SALVAGE",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "SHUDDER",
          "answers": [
            "eat",
            "fear",
            "disgust"
          ],
          "word": "SHUDDER",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "EXHAUST",
          "answers": [
            "use up",
            "tire out",
            "overdo"
          ],
          "word": "EXHAUST",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "CONTAGIOUS",
          "answers": [
            "worsening",
            "spreading",
            "catching"
          ],
          "word": "CONTAGIOUS",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "SPRAWL",
          "answers": [
            "stop",
            "fall",
            "spread"
          ],
          "word": "SPRAWL",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "LEAN",
          "answers": [
            "uncommon",
            "slim",
            "scarce"
          ],
          "word": "LEAN",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "BEFUDDLE",
          "answers": [
            "sadden",
            "confuse",
            "puzzle"
          ],
          "word": "BEFUDDLE",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "CONSENT",
          "answers": [
            "allow",
            "approve",
            "affect"
          ],
          "word": "CONSENT",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "DESCEND",
          "answers": [
            "soften",
            "lower",
            "go down"
          ],
          "word": "DESCEND",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "ENCHANTING",
          "answers": [
            "lovely",
            "delightful",
            "musical"
          ],
          "word": "ENCHANTING",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "DOMINATE",
          "answers": [
            "enjoy",
            "control",
            "overshadow"
          ],
          "word": "DOMINATE",
          "correct": "0"
        }
      ]
    },
    "definitions": {
      "CRINGE": {
        "word": "CRINGE",
        "phonetic": "(krinj)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to shrink back, huddle, crouch down \nTo CRINGE is to draw back from something, to huddle or crouch down in fear. \n\"The shy child CRINGED at the sight of the stranger.\" \n\"The thief CRINGED fearfully as the huge attack dog lunged at his neck.\" \nCRINGE sometimes suggests a total lack of self-respect. \n\"The beggar CRINGED as he saw the powerful nobleman approach.\""
      },
      "PLAGUE": {
        "word": "PLAGUE",
        "phonetic": "(plAg)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to torment, annoy, trouble, afflict \nNote the pronunciation. A PLAGUE is some kind of evil that causes widespread harm, especially a disease that spreads rapidly and causes fever and death. \n\"Millions died when the PLAGUE swept across Europe in the Middle Ages.\" \n\"The rising number of robberies is a PLAGUE upon the nation.\" \nAs a verb, PLAGUE means to _trouble_ or _torment_ as if with a PLAGUE. \n\"Bad luck seemed to PLAGUE him throughout life.\" \n\"The project was PLAGUED with delays and problems.\" \n\"Poor health PLAGUED her as she tried to study for her exams.\""
      },
      "SACRED": {
        "word": "SACRED",
        "phonetic": "(sA'-krid)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "holy, divine \nSomething that is SACRED is dedicated or set apart for some reason. \n\"This field is SACRED to the memory of our soldiers who have fallen in battle.\" \nSACRED is usually used about things that are set apart for religious purposes; in this sense it means just about the same as _holy_. \n\"These SACRED books may be opened only by the high priest.\" \n\"I made a SACRED promise. It would be a sin to break it.\" \nUsage: SACRED is sometimes followed by _to_."
      },
      "PROVOKE": {
        "word": "PROVOKE",
        "phonetic": "(prÔøΩv-Ok')",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to stir up, call forth; to make angry \nSee _pro-_ under Prefixes. The _voke_ part of the word means _call_. To PROVOKE is to call forth or stir up. \n\"His jokes managed to PROVOKE a smile.\" \n\"Her suggestion PROVOKED a long debate.\" \nVery often PROVOKE means \"to call forth _anger_.\" To PROVOKE someone is to make him upset or angry. \n\"Don't PROVOKE the cat or it will scratch you.\" \n\"His enemy's insults PROVOKED him into starting a fight.\" \nOn the Pretest, many people choose _stop_ as the meaning of PROVOKE. The two words are actually just about opposites. The confusion may be due to the similarity between PROVOKE and _revoke_, which means to _cancel_. \nOther forms of the word: PROVOCATION, n. PROVOCATIVE, adj."
      },
      "SALVAGE": {
        "word": "SALVAGE",
        "phonetic": "(sat'-vij)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to save, rescue \nTo SALVAGE something is to save it, especially from loss or ruin. The word was originally used in shipping, where people would be paid for saving, or SALVAGING, cargo from a shipwreck. Now the word is also used about saving from any kind of loss or wreckage. \n\"We managed to SALVAGE most of our furniture from the fire.\" \n\"All our records were ruined in the flood. Nothing could be SALVAGED.\" \nSALVAGE is also a noun. It is the act of saving: \n\"The SALVAGE of the ship was a difficult operation.\" \nOr the things that have been saved: \n\"They piled up the ship's SALVAGE on the beach.\""
      },
      "SHUDDER": {
        "word": "SHUDDER",
        "phonetic": "(shuhd'-ÔøΩr)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to tremble, shake, shiver \nTo SHUDDER is to tremble or shake. When people SHUDDER, it is usually from fear or disgust. \n\"She SHUDDERED when she heard the strange noises outside the room.\" \n\"They SHUDDERED with horror at the sight of the dead bodies.\" \nPhysical objects can also SHUDDER. \n\"The whole house seemed to SHUDDER when the big trucks came roaring by.\" \nSHUDDER is also a noun, and means a _trembling_ or _shaking_. \n\"A SHUDDER passed through him at the thought of the coming battle.\" \nMany people think SHUDDER means _moan_. These words might be used in the same situation—about a person who is afraid or in pain—but they do not have the same meaning."
      },
      "EXHAUST": {
        "word": "EXHAUST",
        "phonetic": "(eg-zost'",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to use up; to tire \nEXHAUST has two common meanings. The basic meaning of EXHAUST is \"to use up so that there's nothing left.\" \n\"Our supply of gasoline was almost EXHAUSTED, so we had to stop and buy some more.\" \n\"The children's shouting finally EXHAUSTED her patience, and she told them to be quiet.\" \nWhen used about people, EXHAUST suggests that their strength or energy is all used up, so the word means to _tire_ or _wear out_. \n\"The long drive totally EXHAUSTED him.\" \n\"Even when she's EXHAUSTED she seems to find the strength to stay up and watch the late show.\" \nOther forms of the word: EXHAUSTION, n."
      },
      "CONTAGIOUS": {
        "word": "CONTAGIOUS",
        "phonetic": "(kan-tA'-jas)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "catching \nCONTAGIOUS is primarily used about diseases, and means \"spreading by contact.\" Scarlet fever is a CONTAGIOUS disease; you can come down with it by touching a person who has it. Diabetes is not a CONTAGIOUS disease; it is not spread by contact. \n\"We stayed away from Jimmy when he had the chicken pox, because we were afraid the disease might be CONTAGIOUS.\" \nOther forms of the word: CONTAGION, n."
      },
      "SPRAWL": {
        "word": "SPRAWL",
        "phonetic": "(sprol)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to spread out \nThe verb to SPRAWL means \"to spread out loosely, with arms and legs flung apart.\" \n\"He was SPRAWLED on the bed\"—that is, he was lying down with his arms and legs carelessly spread out. \n\"The boy SPRAWLED on the sofa, with one leg dangling over its arm.\" \nSPRAWL can also be used about anything that is spread out in a loose or irregular way. \n\"As more and more people came to the campground, tents SPRAWLED all over the place.\" \nSPRAWL is also a noun; a SPRAWL is the position you take when you SPRAWL. \n\"She tripped and fell in a SPRAWL.\" \nMany people choose _crawl_ as the meaning of SPRAWL, probably because they sound alike, and both can take place on the floor. But _crawling_ is a way of moving, while SPRAWLING is a way of falling or lying."
      },
      "LEAN": {
        "word": "LEAN",
        "phonetic": "(IEn)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "thin, lacking fat; scarce, scanty \nWhen used about people or animals, LEAN means _thin_, \"without much fat.\" \n\"She eats very little so that she can have a LEAN figure.\" \n\"He buys LEAN meat, because he believes that eating a lot of fat is bad for you.\" \nWhen used about other things, LEAN means \"lacking in fullness or quantity,\" _unproductive_, _scarce_. \n\"It was a LEAN harvest this year. We only got half as much corn as we expected.\" \n\"There will be LEAN years ahead unless we all work harder.\" \nLEAN is confused by some people with _healthy_. A LEAN person might also be _healthy_, but the two words do not have the same meaning."
      },
      "BEFUDDLE": {
        "word": "BEFUDDLE",
        "phonetic": "(bi-fuhd'-1)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to confuse, puzzle, muddle \nTo BEFUDDLE someone is to confuse him so that he can't understand what is going on. \n\"He BEFUDDLED his son by giving him several orders one right after the other.\" \n\"She was in a BEFUDDLED state for several hours after the operation; finally the drug wore off and her mind cleared.\" \n\"Sally was completely BEFUDDLED by the strong opposition to her reasonable suggestion.\" \n\"Liquor is known to BEFUDDLE people. They can't walk or think straight.\" \n_Amuse_ is the most commonly chosen wrong answer on the Pretest, perhaps because BEFUDDLE is a funny sounding word."
      },
      "CONSENT": {
        "word": "CONSENT",
        "phonetic": "(k::,n-sent')",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to agree, give permission \nCONSENT means \"to give permission or approval.\" The word suggests going along with a request or an idea; it does not necessarily suggest enthusiastic support for it. \n\"The teacher CONSENTED to the suggestion that she delay the test.\" \n\"He would not CONSENT to let them go out alone after dark.\" \n\"I wanted to go to the movies, but my parents would not CONSENT.\" \nCONSENT is also a noun. \n\"The committee gave their CONSENT to the plan.\" \nThe most commonly chosen incorrect answer is _decide_, probably because you must decide whether or not you want something to happen before you CONSENT to it. \nUsage: CONSENT is often followed by _to_."
      },
      "DESCEND": {
        "word": "DESCEND",
        "phonetic": "(di-send')",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to go down, come down \nSee _de-_ under Prefixes. To DESCEND is to go from a higher level to a lower one. The word can be used about real heights: \n\"She DESCENDED the stairs very slowly.\" \nOr about things that are like heights: \n\"The book started brilliantly, then DESCENDED into stupidity.\" \nMany people choose _go away_ as the meaning of DESCEND, but DESCEND always has the idea of going _down_. \nThe opposite of DESCEND is _ascend_, to _go up_. \n\"He _ascended_ the mountain in the morning and DESCENDED it in the afternoon.\" \nOther forms of the word: DESCENT, n."
      },
      "ENCHANTING": {
        "word": "ENCHANTING",
        "phonetic": "(en-chan'-ting",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "charming, delightful, fascinating, bewitching \nTo ENCHANT is to lay under a magic spell, to _charm_: \n\"the ENCHANTED castle\"; \"the ENCHANTED forest.\" ENCHANTING is the adjective from ENCHANT and means _charming_, \"so pleasant and delightful that it seems like magic.\" \n\"The music was ENCHANTING. It held us in its spell.\" \n\"She had an ENCHANTING smile that made everyone fall in love with her.\" \nMany people choose _exciting_ as the meaning of ENCHANTING. ENCHANTING suggests pleasure and delight, however, not excitement. \nOther forms of the word: ENCHANT, v. ENCHANTMENT, n."
      },
      "DOMINATE": {
        "word": "DOMINATE",
        "phonetic": "(dom'-::,.-nAt)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to rule, hold power over, control, overshadow \nSee _-ate1_ under Suffixes. The _domin_ part of the word comes from a Latin word meaning _lord_ or _master_. To DOMINATE something is to have control over it, to be so powerful or so numerous that nothing or no one else has a chance. \n\"He was such a great player that he DOMINATED tennis for many years.\" \n\"That one huge tree DOMINATED the entire landscape.\" \n\"Three automakers DOMINATE the entire industry.\" \n\"He DOMINATED the conversation; no one else had a chance to speak.\" \nSomeone or something that has this kind of control is DOMINANT. \n\"The DOMINANT activity around here is farming.\" \n\"When the senator died, his replacement became the DOMINANT figure in the party.\" \nOther forms of the word: DOMINANT, adj. DOMINATION, n."
      }
    }
  },
  {
    "title": "3.3",
    "pretest": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "Looked at the ROSTER.",
          "answers": [
            "book",
            "letter",
            "sign",
            "ruler",
            "list"
          ],
          "word": "ROSTER",
          "correct": "list"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "INTERSECTED it.",
          "answers": [
            "cut across",
            "entered",
            "studied",
            "drove by",
            "opened"
          ],
          "word": "INTERSECT",
          "correct": "cut across"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "To ENVELOP them.",
          "answers": [
            "need",
            "leave",
            "search for",
            "surround",
            "approach"
          ],
          "word": "ENVELOP",
          "correct": "surround"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "FEEBLE voice.",
          "answers": [
            "loud",
            "frightened",
            "famous",
            "weak",
            "musical"
          ],
          "word": "FEEBLE",
          "correct": "weak"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "SITE of the library.",
          "answers": [
            "view",
            "lay out",
            "location",
            "size",
            "section"
          ],
          "word": "SITE",
          "correct": "location"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "If they INQUIRED.",
          "answers": [
            "wrote",
            "asked",
            "worried about",
            "replied",
            "decided"
          ],
          "word": "INQUIRE",
          "correct": "asked"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He is the FOE.",
          "answers": [
            "boss",
            "old friend",
            "unhappy man",
            "foreigner",
            "enemy"
          ],
          "word": "FOE",
          "correct": "enemy"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "INTENSE interest.",
          "answers": [
            "extreme",
            "little",
            "future",
            "usual",
            "steady"
          ],
          "word": "INTENSE",
          "correct": "extreme"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Picked up the JAVELIN.",
          "answers": [
            "sword",
            "hammer",
            "arrow",
            "spear",
            "knife"
          ],
          "word": "JAVELIN",
          "correct": "spear"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "They will PERISH.",
          "answers": [
            "grow",
            "die",
            "live",
            "weaken",
            "give up"
          ],
          "word": "PERISH",
          "correct": "die"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Who will LIBERATE us?",
          "answers": [
            "pay",
            "rule",
            "free",
            "love",
            "allow"
          ],
          "word": "LIBERATE",
          "correct": "free"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Willing to PLEAD.",
          "answers": [
            "say",
            "suggest",
            "listen",
            "deny",
            "beg"
          ],
          "word": "PLEAD",
          "correct": "beg"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Expect it to RUPTURE.",
          "answers": [
            "leak",
            "close",
            "burn",
            "burst",
            "hurt"
          ],
          "word": "RUPTURE",
          "correct": "burst"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "SANITARY conditions.",
          "answers": [
            "healthful",
            "filthy",
            "proper",
            "calm",
            "wonderful"
          ],
          "word": "SANITARY",
          "correct": "healthful"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Increased VIGOR.",
          "answers": [
            "weakness",
            "power",
            "difficulty",
            "beauty",
            "size"
          ],
          "word": "VIGOR",
          "correct": "power"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_1": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "Could a ROSTER be put on a bulletin board?",
          "word": "ROSTER",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do parallel lines INTERSECT each other?",
          "word": "INTERSECT",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is a burning log ENVELOPED in flames?",
          "word": "ENVELOP",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Does a person with FEEBLE eyesight need glasses?",
          "word": "FEEBLE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is New York City the SITE of the White House?",
          "word": "SITE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do the police INQUIRE into crimes?",
          "word": "INQUIRE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would you trust a FOE with your money?",
          "word": "FOE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can a toothache cause INTENSE pain?",
          "word": "INTENSE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can you carry a JAVELIN in your hands?",
          "word": "JAVELIN",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do flowers PERISH?",
          "word": "PERISH",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is a rat in a cage LIBERATED?",
          "word": "LIBERATE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can you PLEAD for something you are not supposed to have?",
          "word": "PLEAD",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Could too much weight inside cause a bag to RUPTURE?",
          "word": "RUPTURE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is garbage SANITARY?",
          "word": "SANITARY",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Does eating good food and exercising help to increase your VIGOR?",
          "word": "VIGOR",
          "correct": "true"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_2": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "The club added his name to the ROSTER when he paid his dues.",
          "word": "ROSTER",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "They're building a motel close to the INTERSECTION of the two highways.",
          "word": "INTERSECT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The scientist ENVELOPED a new method for making steel.",
          "word": "ENVELOP",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Tom's FEEBLE attempt at humor didn't make anyone laugh.",
          "word": "FEEBLE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He climbed up the SITE of the house to the roof.",
          "word": "SITE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He INQUIRED if there were any seats left on the airplane.",
          "word": "INQUIRE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Although they were FOES they respected each other.",
          "word": "FOE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Bill was worried for a while, but then he became INTENSE when they told him everything was all right.",
          "word": "INTENSE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The warrior pulled back on the bow and shot the JAYELIN into the air.",
          "word": "JAVELIN",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "These vegetables are PERISHABLE; you must eat them soon or they will go bad.",
          "word": "PERISH",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The cruel king LIBERATED his nation with an iron hand.",
          "word": "LIBERATE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "We PLEADED with the teacher not to give us any homework.",
          "word": "PLEAD",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Nothing anyone could say or do could mend the RUPTURE between them.",
          "word": "RUPTURE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "After years of treatment in the mental hospital he became SANITARY once again.",
          "word": "SANITARY",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Bill VIGOROUSLY denied having taken the money.",
          "word": "VIGOR",
          "correct": "true"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_3": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "ROSTER",
          "answers": [
            "name",
            "list",
            "idea"
          ],
          "word": "ROSTER",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "INTERSECT",
          "answers": [
            "cross",
            "widen",
            "cut"
          ],
          "word": "INTERSECT",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "ENVELOP",
          "answers": [
            "wrap",
            "cover",
            "lose"
          ],
          "word": "ENVELOP",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "FEEBLE",
          "answers": [
            "weak",
            "disgusted",
            "sick"
          ],
          "word": "FEEBLE",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "SITE",
          "answers": [
            "purpose",
            "place",
            "position"
          ],
          "word": "SITE",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "INQUIRE",
          "answers": [
            "ask",
            "wonder",
            "question"
          ],
          "word": "INQUIRE",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "FOE",
          "answers": [
            "rival",
            "friend",
            "enemy"
          ],
          "word": "FOE",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "INTENSE",
          "answers": [
            "mild",
            "strong",
            "high"
          ],
          "word": "INTENSE",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "JAVELIN",
          "answers": [
            "spear",
            "lance",
            "knife"
          ],
          "word": "JAVELIN",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "PERISH",
          "answers": [
            "decay",
            "end",
            "refuse"
          ],
          "word": "PERISH",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "LIBERATE",
          "answers": [
            "free",
            "delight",
            "release"
          ],
          "word": "LIBERATE",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "PLEAD",
          "answers": [
            "ask",
            "demand",
            "beg"
          ],
          "word": "PLEAD",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "RUPTURE",
          "answers": [
            "stain",
            "divide",
            "tear"
          ],
          "word": "RUPTURE",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "SANITARY",
          "answers": [
            "cleanliness",
            "beauty",
            "health"
          ],
          "word": "SANITARY",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "VIGOR",
          "answers": [
            "energy",
            "strength",
            "desire"
          ],
          "word": "VIGOR",
          "correct": "2"
        }
      ]
    },
    "definitions": {
      "ROSTER": {
        "word": "ROSTER",
        "phonetic": "(ros'-t:;,r)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "a list of names \nA ROSTER is a _list_, especially a list of persons (as in the army) and the turns of duty each one will take. \n\"He studied the ROSTER to find out when he had to work that week.\" \nROSTER can be used about any list of names. \n\"We are proud to add his name to our membership ROSTER.\" \n\"They accidentally left his name off the team ROSTER.\""
      },
      "INTERSECT": {
        "word": "INTERSECT",
        "phonetic": "(in-tÔøΩ-sekt')",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to cross, cut across \nSee _inter-_ under Prefixes. The _sect_ part of the word comes from a Latin word meaning to _cut_. To _bisect_ something is to cut it in half. To _dissect_ something is to cut it apart. To INTERSECT something is to cut across it, to divide it by passing across it. \n\"The river INTERSECTS the state.\" \nTwo things INTERSECT when they cross at a point. \n\"The two roads INTERSECTED just north of the city.\" \nAn INTERSECTION is a place where two things, especially roads, meet and cross. \n\"It was a dangerous INTERSECTION, with cars traveling quickly along both roads.\" \nOther forms of the word: INTERSECTION, n."
      },
      "ENVELOP": {
        "word": "ENVELOP",
        "phonetic": "(en-vel'-ÔøΩ)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to surround, enclose \nTo ENVELOP something is to surround it completely, usually with clothing or a non-solid material. \n\"Thick smoke ENVELOPED the burning building, and we couldn't see a thing.\" \n\"She was completely ENVELOPED in blankets to keep from catching cold.\" \n\"Dark clouds ENVELOPED the tops of the mountains.\" \nAn ENVELOPE is what you put a letter in to mail it. Its basic meaning is \"something that ENVELOPS,\" a _wrapper_ or _container_. \nOther forms of the word: ENVELOPE, n."
      },
      "FEEBLE": {
        "word": "FEEBLE",
        "phonetic": "(fE'-bÔøΩI)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "weak, frail; dim \nFEEBLE means _very weak_, \"lacking strength or energy.\" The word is usually used about people and their actions. \n\"He became very FEEBLE in his old age and couldn't do anything for himself.\" \n\"She made a FEEBLE attempt to smile.\" \n\"His arguments were extremely FEEBLE. Anyone could have pointed out the errors in his reasoning.\" \nWhen used about things, FEEBLE means _dim_, _faint_. \n\"The old record player could only produce a very FEEBLE sound.\""
      },
      "SITE": {
        "word": "SITE",
        "phonetic": "(sit)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "location, position \nThe SITE of something is the exact place where it was, is, or will be located. \n\"They visited the SITE of the Battle of Gettysburg.\" \n\"No one was allowed near the construction SITE while the building was going up.\" \n\"This will be the SITE of the new city hall.\" \nOn the Pretest, a common choice as a synonym for SITE is _view_. This is the result of confusion between SITE and _sight_, which sound the same but have different meanings. The _sight_ of something is a _view_ of it; the SITE of something is where it is located."
      },
      "INQUIRE": {
        "word": "INQUIRE",
        "phonetic": "(in-kwlr')",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to ask, ask about \nINQUIRE means to _ask_ or _ask about_, usually in a formal way about something specific. \n\"I wanted to INQUIRE about the job that was advertised in the newspaper.\" \n\"She INQUIRED about my health.\" \nWhen used with _into_, INQUIRE means \"to make an investigation.\" \n\"The man from the insurance company INQUIRED into the condition of the car before the accident.\" \nAn INQUIRY is the act of INQUIRING. \n\"When his polite INQUIRY brought no response, he demanded that his questions be answered.\" \nOther forms of the word: INQUIRY, n."
      },
      "FOE": {
        "word": "FOE",
        "phonetic": "(fO)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "an enemy, opponent, adversary \nFOE and _enemy_ have just about the same meaning. _Enemy_ is the more common word. FOE sometimes suggests a more actively dangerous person than _enemy_. \n\"We met our FOE in a fierce battle and we were victorious.\" \n\"Even his greatest FOES admitted he was a generous man.\" \n\"She was a bitter FOE of injustice.\""
      },
      "INTENSE": {
        "word": "INTENSE",
        "phonetic": "(in-tens')",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "extreme, high in degree \nINTENSE comes from a Latin word meaning _stretched out_, _strained_, also the source of the English words _tense_ and _tension_. INTENSE means \"existing in an extreme or strained degree.\" The word can be used in many different ways. \n\"The INTENSE light bothered his eyes.\" \n\"There was an INTENSE hatred between the two men.\" \n\"The cold was so INTENSE that we began to shiver.\" \nINTENSE is also used about people who are full of strong feelings. \n\"Jim is a very INTENSE young man. He is always getting excited about something.\" \nOther forms of the word: INTENSIFY, v. INTENSITY, n."
      },
      "JAVELIN": {
        "word": "JAVELIN",
        "phonetic": "(jav'-lÔøΩn",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "a light spear \nA JAVELIN is a light spear; it was originally used in hunting and in war, but now it is thrown for distance in track and field meets. \n\"He set a new world's record for throwing the JAVELIN.\" \nMany people confuse JAVELIN with _knife_, probably because both are weapons."
      },
      "PERISH": {
        "word": "PERISH",
        "phonetic": "(per'-ish)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to die, be destroyed, pass away completely \nTo PERISH is to come to an end, to be destroyed, often in a violent way. The word is usually used about living things. \n\"Hundreds of small birds and animals PERISHED in the forest fire.\" \n\"The entire group of mountain climbers PERISHED from the cold winds.\" \n\"My cousin's herd of horses PERISHED during the hurricane.\" \nPERISHABLE is the adjective from PERISH and means _easily ruined_, _quick to decay_. Generally, this form of the word is used when talking about food. \n\"Supermarkets must keep PERISHABLE items, such as milk and butter, in refrigerated cases.\" \nOther forms of the word: PERISHABLE, adj."
      },
      "LIBERATE": {
        "word": "LIBERATE",
        "phonetic": "(lib'-ÔøΩrAt)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to free, set free \nSee _-ate1_ under Suffixes. LIBERATE comes from the same Latin word as _liberal_ and _liberty_. All have to do with _freedom_. To LIBERATE someone is to _free_ him. \n\"President Abraham Lincoln LIBERATED the slaves in the United States.\" \n\"Winning this money will LIBERATE us from all our worries.\" \nMany people pick _rule_ as the meaning of LIBERATE. _Rule_ means just about the opposite of LIBERATE. \nOther forms of the word: LIBERATION, n."
      },
      "PLEAD": {
        "word": "PLEAD",
        "phonetic": "(plEd)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to beg, appeal, implore, claim \nThe basic use of PLEAD is in law. To PLEAD in law is to make an answer to a legal charge: \"to plead innocent,\" \"to plead insanity.\" From this it has come to mean \"to offer as an excuse.\" \n\"When asked for an explanation of his behavior, he PLEADED ignorance.\" \nIn a related sense PLEAD means \"to argue strongly or ask earnestly,\" to _beg_. \n\"He PLEADED for a little more time to finish the test.\" \n\"Mary PLEADED with them to let her and her sister join the club.\" \nOther forms of the word: PLEA, n."
      },
      "RUPTURE": {
        "word": "RUPTURE",
        "phonetic": "(ruhp'-chor)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to burst, break \nTo RUPTURE something is to burst it, to break it apart. \n\"She RUPTURED a blood vessel and was rushed to the hospital.\" \nThe word is often used about a break in the friendly relations between people or countries. \n\"The president's angry speech RUPTURED the relations between the two countries.\" \nWhen something RUPTURES, it bursts. \n\"The weight of the water caused the dam to RUPTURE.\" \n\"Her appendix RUPTURED, so the doctor operated immediately.\" \nRUPTURE is also a noun, meaning a _breaking apart_ or _bursting_. \n\"The bitter disagreement caused a RUPTURE between the brothers that lasted for years.\""
      },
      "SANITARY": {
        "word": "SANITARY",
        "phonetic": "(san'-o-ter-E)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "healthful, clean \nSANITARY means \"of or relating to health.\" The word is especially used about things that are free of impurities that might cause disease. \n\"The hospital room must be completely SANITARY.\" \n\"Conditions are not very SANITARY around here. We must clean everything thoroughly.\""
      },
      "VIGOR": {
        "word": "VIGOR",
        "phonetic": "(vig'-or)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "power, strength, energy, pep \nVIGOR is strength or energy that comes from good health. \n\"He attacked the problem with VIGOR.\" \n\"Her constant VIGOR makes others tired; they wonder how she keeps it up.\" \nThe adjective form of VIGOR is VIGOROUS, which means _strong_ or _forceful_. \n\"The VIGOROUS series of exercises left her gasping for breath.\" \nOther forms of the word: VIGOROUS, adj."
      }
    },
    "reviewTest": {
      "wordList": [
        "ABRUPT",
        "CRINGE",
        "ENVELOP",
        "INTERSECT",
        "PLAGUE",
        "BAN",
        "DESCEND",
        "EVIDENT",
        "LEAN",
        "PLEAD",
        "BEFUDDLE",
        "DOMINATE",
        "FEEBLE",
        "LIBERATE",
        "SPRAWL",
        "CONTAGIOUS",
        "ENDURE",
        "FEUD",
        "PAMPER",
        "STEER",
        "CONGESTION",
        "FRISKY",
        "JAVELIN",
        "RUPTURE",
        "SITE",
        "CONSENT",
        "FROLIC",
        "PERISH",
        "SACRED",
        "SUBSTITUTE",
        "ENCHANTING",
        "INQUIRE",
        "PROVOKE",
        "SALVAGE",
        "VICINITY",
        "EXHAUST",
        "INTENSE",
        "RECEPTION",
        "SANITARY",
        "VIGOR",
        "FOE",
        "INTERMEDIATE",
        "ROSTER",
        "SHUDDER",
        "VIOLATE"
      ],
      "questions": [
        {
          "part1": "They found the murdered man",
          "part2": "face down on the floor.",
          "answer": "sprawled"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The plane started to",
          "part2": "as it came in for a landing.",
          "answer": "descend"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Grandmother",
          "part2": "the children when they stay with her; she lets them watch television all the time.",
          "answer": "pampers"
        },
        {
          "part1": "A series of minor injuries",
          "part2": "him throughout his career as a ballplayer.",
          "answer": "plagued"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The soldiers were able to capture the prison-of-war camp and",
          "part2": "the men held there.",
          "answer": "liberate"
        },
        {
          "part1": "It was a close game for a while, but then the other team began to",
          "part2": "us, and we lost quite badly.",
          "answer": "dominate"
        },
        {
          "part1": "You can see on the map where the railroad and the highway",
          "part2": ".",
          "answer": "intersect"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The starving family",
          "part2": "for a little more food.",
          "answer": "pleaded"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The woman was forced to",
          "part2": "great hardships for many years.",
          "answer": "endure"
        },
        {
          "part1": "A thick mist began to",
          "part2": "us as we walked into the valley.",
          "answer": "envelop"
        },
        {
          "part1": "It was",
          "part2": "that Art couldn't win the election, so he dropped out of the race.",
          "answer": "evident"
        },
        {
          "part1": "His speech was",
          "part2": "and to the point: he told us we were all fired.",
          "answer": "abrupt"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Although Andy is very strong, he has a surprisingly",
          "part2": "handshake.",
          "answer": "feeble"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The",
          "part2": "began with a simple misunderstanding between the two families and lasted for many years.",
          "answer": "feud"
        },
        {
          "part1": "After the window was broken, the principal",
          "part2": "all ball playing in the schoolyard.",
          "answer": "banned"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The other team was completely",
          "part2": "by our trick plays. They didn't know what was going on.",
          "answer": "befuddled"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Her disease was",
          "part2": "; before long we were all sick.",
          "answer": "contagious"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The boat was difficult to",
          "part2": "; it seemed to want to go anywhere but where you wanted it to go.",
          "answer": "steer"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The man",
          "part2": "and started begging for his life when he saw the bully come toward him.",
          "answer": "cringed"
        },
        {
          "part1": "He was very",
          "part2": "as a youth, but he put on weight as he grew older.",
          "answer": "lean"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The entire family",
          "part2": "in the car crash.",
          "answer": "perished"
        },
        {
          "part1": "We knew that when our supply of food was",
          "part2": "we'd have to buy some more.",
          "answer": "exhausted"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The fight between the border guards",
          "part2": "a full-scale battle between the two nations.",
          "answer": "provoked"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The court ruled that their actions",
          "part2": "the man's civil rights.",
          "answer": "violated"
        },
        {
          "part1": "All of his",
          "part2": "were happy to see him go to jail.",
          "answer": "foes"
        },
        {
          "part1": "On this very",
          "part2": "the Declaration of Independence was signed in 1776.",
          "answer": "site"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The",
          "part2": "kitten kept jumping at the sleeping dog's tail.",
          "answer": "frisky"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The dog liked to",
          "part2": "on the shore, dashing in and out of the water.",
          "answer": "frolic"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The astronauts were given a huge",
          "part2": "when they returned from their space journey.",
          "answer": "reception"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The increasing pressure of the water finally caused the dam to",
          "part2": ".",
          "answer": "rupture"
        },
        {
          "part1": "His",
          "part2": "desire to win the contest drove everything else out of his mind.",
          "answer": "intense"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Kathy would",
          "part2": "uncontrollably whenever she remembered the night she was robbed.",
          "answer": "shudder"
        },
        {
          "part1": "A new singer",
          "part2": "for the one who was supposed to sing.",
          "answer": "substituted"
        },
        {
          "part1": "This church is a(n)",
          "part2": "place. One should be very quiet and respectful in it.",
          "answer": "sacred"
        },
        {
          "part1": ". Alice",
          "part2": "about the possibility of working at the library.",
          "answer": "inquired"
        },
        {
          "part1": "There are two parks in the",
          "part2": "of the school where the children can go at lunchtime.",
          "answer": "vicinity"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The divers tried to",
          "part2": "some of the precious cargo from the sunken ship.",
          "answer": "salvage"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Jim's parents",
          "part2": "when he asked if he could take the car.",
          "answer": "consented"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Between the start and the finish of the project there were many",
          "part2": "steps.",
          "answer": "intermediate"
        },
        {
          "part1": "There was considerable",
          "part2": "in the small room as dozens of people jammed into it.",
          "answer": "congestion"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Walter is a very energetic person, full of",
          "part2": ".",
          "answer": "vigor"
        },
        {
          "part1": "All the equipment should be",
          "part2": "; we don't want anyone catching a disease.",
          "answer": "sanitary"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The melody of that song is",
          "part2": ". I could listen to it forever.",
          "answer": "enchanting"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Jack found his name on the",
          "part2": "of those assigned to guard duty.",
          "answer": "roster"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The warrior threw the",
          "part2": "so hard that it stuck deep in a tree.",
          "answer": "javelin"
        }
      ]
    }
  },
  {
    "title": "3.4",
    "pretest": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "To make HEADWAY.",
          "answers": [
            "sense",
            "progress",
            "time",
            "excuses",
            "trouble"
          ],
          "word": "HEADWAY",
          "correct": "progress"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "ACCUMULATE the books.",
          "answers": [
            "buy",
            "give away",
            "count",
            "receive",
            "gather"
          ],
          "word": "ACCUMULATE",
          "correct": "gather"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "To GOUGE holes.",
          "answers": [
            "dig out",
            "cover over",
            "fill",
            "find",
            "count"
          ],
          "word": "GOUGE",
          "correct": "dig out"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "She ANTICIPATED the problem.",
          "answers": [
            "created",
            "ignored",
            "started",
            "expected",
            "solved"
          ],
          "word": "ANTICIPATE",
          "correct": "expected"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "COMPREHEND easily.",
          "answers": [
            "read",
            "understand",
            "avoid",
            "write",
            "hold back"
          ],
          "word": "COMPREHEND",
          "correct": "understand"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Different APPAREL.",
          "answers": [
            "clothing",
            "behavior",
            "decorations",
            "gifts",
            "furniture"
          ],
          "word": "APPAREL",
          "correct": "clothing"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Always CONFRONTS him.",
          "answers": [
            "helps",
            "escapes",
            "faces",
            "disturbs",
            "reads"
          ],
          "word": "CONFRONT",
          "correct": "faces"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Wanted to CONGREGATE.",
          "answers": [
            "remain",
            "depart",
            "worship",
            "proceed",
            "assemble"
          ],
          "word": "CONGREGATE",
          "correct": "assemble"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Mentioned many INSTANCES.",
          "answers": [
            "needs",
            "examples",
            "demands",
            "journeys",
            "ideas"
          ],
          "word": "INSTANCE",
          "correct": "examples"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "FELINE movements.",
          "answers": [
            "cat-like",
            "clumsy",
            "bird-like",
            "secret",
            "clever"
          ],
          "word": "FELINE",
          "correct": "cat-like"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Ignored the CONTROVERSY.",
          "answers": [
            "charge",
            "agreement",
            "letter",
            "dispute",
            "punishment"
          ],
          "word": "CONTROVERSY",
          "correct": "dispute"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The FOREMOST authority.",
          "answers": [
            "new",
            "worst",
            "chief",
            "past",
            "usual"
          ],
          "word": "FOREMOST",
          "correct": "chief"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The place was HABITABLE.",
          "answers": [
            "typical",
            "filthy",
            "comfortable",
            "livable",
            "inexpensive"
          ],
          "word": "HABITABLE",
          "correct": "livable"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "FREAKISH appearance.",
          "answers": [
            "shy",
            "common",
            "stupid",
            "odd",
            "excited"
          ],
          "word": "FREAKISH",
          "correct": "odd"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The IMMENSE building.",
          "answers": [
            "huge",
            "narrow",
            "dirty",
            "noisy",
            "crowded"
          ],
          "word": "IMMENSE",
          "correct": "huge"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_1": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "Can a rowboat make a lot of HEADWAY during a storm?",
          "word": "HEADWAY",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Does a stamp collector ACCUMULATE stamps?",
          "word": "ACCUMULATE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do people like to be GOUGED?",
          "word": "GOUGE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would it be helpful if you could ANTICIPATE what a teacher was going to ask on a test?",
          "word": "ANTICIPATE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Does skipping pages increase a person's COMPREHENSION of a book?",
          "word": "COMPREHEND",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is a shirt a piece of APPAREL?",
          "word": "APPAREL",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can you always avoid a problem by CONFRONTING it?",
          "word": "CONFRONT",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can a person CONGREGATE by himself?",
          "word": "CONGREGATE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would fifteen people in a phone booth be an INSTANCE of overcrowding?",
          "word": "INSTANCE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is a wild dog a FELINE?",
          "word": "FELINE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Could a person get angry during a CONTROVERSY?",
          "word": "CONTROVERSY",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would the FOREMOST students usually get poor grades?",
          "word": "FOREMOST",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is Hawaii HABITABLE?",
          "word": "HABITABLE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is a two-legged person a FREAK?",
          "word": "FREAKISH",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is an ant IMMENSE?",
          "word": "IMMENSE",
          "correct": "false"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_2": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "Although they have made some HEADWAY, scientists still have a long way to go in finding a cure for the disease.",
          "word": "HEADWAY",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He was ACCUMULATED by the police as a suspect in the robbery.",
          "word": "ACCUMULATE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "We GOUGED ourselves on donuts.",
          "word": "GOUGE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "I ANTICIPATE that there will be no problem in getting him to agree.",
          "word": "ANTICIPATE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "She found it difficult to COMPREHEND the meaning of the poem.",
          "word": "COMPREHEND",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Among the APPAREL in the laboratory were test tubes and microscopes.",
          "word": "APPAREL",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "She CONFRONTED for him so that no one knew he had missed work.",
          "word": "CONFRONT",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "A flock of pigeons started to CONGREGATE around the bread crumbs.",
          "word": "CONGREGATE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "We saw many INSTANCES of poverty in the slums.",
          "word": "INSTANCE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "With FELINE grace she jumped from rock to rock along the shore.",
          "word": "FELINE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The whole town liked the CONTROVERSIAL plan to build a new police station.",
          "word": "CONTROVERSY",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "First and FOREMOST we must remember that other people are depending on us.",
          "word": "FOREMOST",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "A coat of paint helped to make the place a little more HABITABLE.",
          "word": "HABITABLE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "It was a FREAKISH dream: I was sitting in an igloo playing the piano.",
          "word": "FREAKISH",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The diamond was IMMENSE; it was almost the size of a golf ball.",
          "word": "IMMENSE",
          "correct": "true"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_3": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "HEADWAY",
          "answers": [
            "proof",
            "continuation",
            "advancement"
          ],
          "word": "HEADWAY",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "ACCUMULATE",
          "answers": [
            "save",
            "collect",
            "need"
          ],
          "word": "ACCUMULATE",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "GOUGE",
          "answers": [
            "drop",
            "cheat",
            "cut"
          ],
          "word": "GOUGE",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "ANTICIPATE",
          "answers": [
            "recall",
            "plan",
            "foresee"
          ],
          "word": "ANTICIPATE",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "COMPREHEND",
          "answers": [
            "perceive",
            "refuse",
            "grasp"
          ],
          "word": "COMPREHEND",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "APPAREL",
          "answers": [
            "umbrella",
            "raincoat",
            "boots"
          ],
          "word": "APPAREL",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "CONFRONT",
          "answers": [
            "challenge",
            "follow",
            "meet"
          ],
          "word": "CONFRONT",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "CONGREGATE",
          "answers": [
            "see",
            "meet",
            "gather"
          ],
          "word": "CONGREGATE",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "INSTANCE",
          "answers": [
            "result",
            "example",
            "case"
          ],
          "word": "INSTANCE",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "FELINE",
          "answers": [
            "polite",
            "graceful",
            "swift"
          ],
          "word": "FELINE",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "CONTROVERSY",
          "answers": [
            "consideration",
            "dispute",
            "disagreement"
          ],
          "word": "CONTROVERSY",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "FOREMOST",
          "answers": [
            "former",
            "leading",
            "front"
          ],
          "word": "FOREMOST",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "HABITABLE",
          "answers": [
            "livable",
            "inhabitable",
            "usable"
          ],
          "word": "HABITABLE",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "FREAKISH",
          "answers": [
            "strange",
            "abnormal",
            "unhealthy"
          ],
          "word": "FREAKISH",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "IMMENSE",
          "answers": [
            "large",
            "wonderful",
            "huge"
          ],
          "word": "IMMENSE",
          "correct": "1"
        }
      ]
    },
    "definitions": {
      "HEADWAY": {
        "word": "HEADWAY",
        "phonetic": "(hed'-wA)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "progress, advance, movement forward \nHEADWAY is usually used in the phrase \"to make HEADWAY,\" which means \"to make progress, to move forward,\" like a ship making its way through the water. \n\"We couldn't make any HEADWAY with the strong wind blowing against us.\" \n\"They reported making some HEADWAY in convincing both sides to agree to stop fighting.\" \n\"I hope to make some HEADWAY in my math project this afternoon.\""
      },
      "ACCUMULATE": {
        "word": "ACCUMULATE",
        "phonetic": "(:>-kyUm'-y:>-IAt)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to gather, amass, pile up \nTo ACCUMULATE is to _heap up_, to increase gradually into a larger quantity. People can ACCUMULATE things, and things can ACCUMULATE. \n\"He has ACCUMULATED a large collection of early American paintings.\" \n\"Water ACCUMULATED in the cellar when the drain became blocked.\" \nACCUMULATED is frequently used about money. \n\"She ACCUMULATED a fortune in the stock market.\" \nThe noun form is ACCUMULATION, which means \"things that are piled up,\" or \"the act of piling up.\" \n\"The ACCUMULATION of knowledge is a worthwhile goal.\" \n\"What an ACCUMULATION of junk!\" \nOther forms of the word: ACCUMULATION, n."
      },
      "GOUGE": {
        "word": "GOUGE",
        "phonetic": "(gowj)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to dig out, force out \nA GOUGE is a tool for digging out grooves or channels in wood. To GOUGE something is to cut it with, or as if with, a GOUGE. The word suggests something done roughly or crudely. \n\"The boy GOUGED a hole in the table with his knife.\" \n\"He GOUGED his initials in the tree trunk.\" \nTo GOUGE someone's eye is to poke a thumb or finger into it. In a special sense, GOUGE can mean to _over-charge_ or _swindle_—that is, to force money from a person. \n\"He GOUGED an extra twenty dollars from them because he knew they couldn't get anyone else to do the job.\""
      },
      "ANTICIPATE": {
        "word": "ANTICIPATE",
        "phonetic": "(an-tis'-:>-pAt)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to expect, foresee \nTo ANTICIPATE something is to expect or foresee that it will happen, or to deal with it in advance. \n\"She ANTICIPATED our arrival and fixed up the guest room for us.\" \n\"He ANTICIPATED that we would refuse at first, so he prepared still more arguments to persuade us.\" \n\"He is very unpredictable; you can never ANTICIPATE what he's going to do next.\" \nOther forms of the word: ANTICIPATION, n."
      },
      "COMPREHEND": {
        "word": "COMPREHEND",
        "phonetic": "(kom-pri-hend')",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to understand, perceive \nTo COMPREHEND something is to grasp it mentally, to understand it. The word often suggests a thorough understanding, a complete grasp of an idea or a subject. \n\"No one can really COMPREHEND what it means to live forever.\" \n\"We cannot COMPREHEND his refusal to take such a good job.\" \n\"She was able to COMPREHEND written French, but she could never speak it very well.\" \nThe noun form of COMPREHEND is COMPREHENSION, _understanding_. \n\"The intricate workings of an automobile are beyond his COMPREHENSION.\" \nOther forms of the word: COMPREHENSION, n. COMPREHENSIBLE, adj."
      },
      "APPAREL": {
        "word": "APPAREL",
        "phonetic": "(:>-par'-ÔøΩI)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "clothing, dress, attire \nAPPAREL is a rather fancy word for a person's clothing. \n\"She put on her finest APPAREL for the dance that evening.\" \n\"Everyone laughed at the strange APPAREL he wore to school that day.\" \nAPPAREL is also a verb, meaning to _clothe_ or _dress_. \n\"The king was APPARELED in his costliest robes for the ceremony.\""
      },
      "CONFRONT": {
        "word": "CONFRONT",
        "phonetic": "(kÔøΩn-fruhnt')",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to face, encounter \nTo CONFRONT something is to have it in _front_ of you, to be or come face to face with it. \n\"When we turned the corner a huge wall suddenly CONFRONTED us.\" \n\"They were CONFRONTED with several difficult problems at once.\" \nOften CONFRONT has the sense of a person facing something defiantly or without flinching. \n\"The enemies CONFRONTED each other in the doorway, and neither one would step aside.\" \nTo CONFRONT someone _with_ something is to bring him face to face with it. In this sense CONFRONT often suggests forcing the person to face something he doesn't want to face. \n\"They CONFRONTED the prisoner with so much evidence that he was forced to confess.\" \nOther forms of the word: CONFRONTATION, n."
      },
      "CONGREGATE": {
        "word": "CONGREGATE",
        "phonetic": "(kong'-grQ-gAt)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to come together, assemble, gather \nSee _con-_ under Prefixes and _-ate1_ under Suffixes. The _greg_ part of the word comes from the Latin word for a _flock_. To CONGREGATE is to come or bring together in a particular place, to flock together like birds or sheep. \n\"The teacher CONGREGATED her students in one corner of the schoolyard.\" \n\"People began to CONGREGATE around the musicians playing on the street corner.\" \nA CONGREGATION is a gathering or assembly of people, especially people gathering in church to worship together. \n\"Everyone in the CONGREGATION rose to sing the hymn.\" \nOther forms of the word: CONGREGATION, n."
      },
      "INSTANCE": {
        "word": "INSTANCE",
        "phonetic": "(ins'-tÔøΩns)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "an example, case, illustration \nAn INSTANCE is an example or case, especially one given in support of some general statement or truth. \n\"She couldn't forgive this latest INSTANCE of disobedience.\" \n\"He brought up many INSTANCES of our being late for school.\" \n\"This is only one INSTANCE of many that I could have mentioned.\" \nThe common phrase \"for INSTANCE\" means \"as an example.\" \n\"He has trouble with math. For INSTANCE, he didn't get any problems right on this test.\""
      },
      "FELINE": {
        "word": "FELINE",
        "phonetic": "(fE'-lln)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "like a cat, pertaining to cats \nFELINE comes from the Latin word for _cat_. The word can mean \"of or pertaining to the cat family.\" Or it can mean \"like a cat,\" having the qualities usually associated with cats, such as gracefulness and quickness. \n\"He moved with FELINE grace along the dance floor.\" \n\"She dropped from the ledge with FELINE quickness.\" \nFELINE can also be used as a noun to mean _cat_ or \"a member of the cat family.\" \n\"FELINES are noted for their swiftness.\""
      },
      "CONTROVERSY": {
        "word": "CONTROVERSY",
        "phonetic": "(kon'-trQ-ver-sE)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "a dispute, argument, debate \nA CONTROVERSY is a disagreement or dispute that can last for a long time and involve many people. The word usually suggests that a more important issue is being discussed than in an argument. \n\"The plan to raise taxes created a CONTROVERSY.\" \n\"Great CONTROVERSY surrounded the decision to build a new high school.\" \n\"The two doctors engaged in a long CONTROVERSY over the value of the medicine.\" \nSomething that is CONTROVERSIAL causes CONTROVERSY or debate. \n\"The CONTROVERSIAL book suggests that no one should have to go to school.\" \nOther forms of the word: CONTROVERSIAL, adj."
      },
      "FOREMOST": {
        "word": "FOREMOST",
        "phonetic": "(for'-mOst)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "chief, best, first \n_Fore-_ at the beginning of a word usually means _at the front_, _before_. Something that is FOREMOST is in front of everything else; it is the first in order, importance, value, etc. \n\"He is one of the league's FOREMOST pitchers.\" \n\"She is the nation's FOREMOST expert on health care.\" \nThe phrase \"first and FOREMOST\" means _most important_, \"before anything else.\" \n\"First and FOREMOST, let me explain why I have brought you here tonight.\""
      },
      "HABITABLE": {
        "word": "HABITABLE",
        "phonetic": "(hab'-ÔøΩtÔøΩbQI)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "livable, fit to be inhabited \nTo _inhabit_ a place is to live in it. A place that is HABITABLE is able to be lived in. See _-able_ under Suffixes. HABITABLE does not suggest that a place is very beautiful or comfortable, only that people can live in it. \n\"The house has no plumbing, heat, or electricity; it just isn't HABITABLE.\" \n\"The room isn't fancy, but it is HABITABLE.\" \n\"Tests showed that the planet had an atmosphere like the Earth's; it was probably HABITABLE.\""
      },
      "FREAKISH": {
        "word": "FREAKISH",
        "phonetic": "(frE'-kish)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "odd, abnormal \nThe basic meaning of FREAK is \"a sudden change or turn of the mind.\" From this it has come to be used about a thing or person who is extremely strange or abnormal. \n\"The snowstorm in July was really a FREAK. We'll never see another one like it.\" \nFREAKISH is the adjective from FREAK. See _-ish_ under Suffixes. It means _unusual_, _bizarre_, _extremely strange_. \n\"No one could understand his FREAKISH behavior lately.\" \n\"He had a FREAKISH talent for remembering every phone number he ever heard.\" \n\"It was a FREAKISH potato: it was almost the size of a basketball.\" \nMany people think FREAKISH means _stupid_. Someone who is or appears to be out of the ordinary is not necessarily _stupid_, however. \nOther forms of the word: FREAK, n."
      },
      "IMMENSE": {
        "word": "IMMENSE",
        "phonetic": "(i-mens')",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "huge, vast, extremely large \nIMMENSE means \"so big or great that you can hardly measure it.\" The word is used about size, numbers, amounts, and so on. \n\"The museum was IMMENSE. It would take you weeks to see everything that's in it.\" \n\"There was an IMMENSE crowd on the beach that day.\" \n\"There is an IMMENSE amount of work to be done before we will be finished.\" \nOther forms of the word: IMMENSITY, n."
      }
    }
  },
  {
    "title": "3.5",
    "pretest": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "INTERCEPT the messenger.",
          "answers": [
            "hide",
            "help",
            "replace",
            "tie up",
            "cut off"
          ],
          "word": "INTERCEPT",
          "correct": "cut off"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Used to MEDDLE.",
          "answers": [
            "butt in",
            "drop in",
            "weave",
            "let alone",
            "show off"
          ],
          "word": "MEDDLE",
          "correct": "butt in"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "I have MISGIVINGS.",
          "answers": [
            "hopes",
            "doubts",
            "pains",
            "thoughts",
            "needs"
          ],
          "word": "MISGIVING",
          "correct": "doubts"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "They were MUTE.",
          "answers": [
            "small",
            "loud",
            "silent",
            "useless",
            "empty"
          ],
          "word": "MUTE",
          "correct": "silent"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "They will NEGOTIATE with us.",
          "answers": [
            "meet",
            "never speak",
            "become friends",
            "travel",
            "bargain"
          ],
          "word": "NEGOTIATE",
          "correct": "bargain"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Necessary PRECAUTION.",
          "answers": [
            "sign",
            "risk",
            "decision",
            "safeguard",
            "inspection"
          ],
          "word": "PRECAUTION",
          "correct": "safeguard"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Wanted to REFORM them.",
          "answers": [
            "destroy",
            "correct",
            "twist",
            "pray for",
            "protect"
          ],
          "word": "REFORM",
          "correct": "correct"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "They will finally RESUME.",
          "answers": [
            "begin again",
            "finish",
            "decide",
            "show up",
            "try"
          ],
          "word": "RESUME",
          "correct": "begin again"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "It was SERVICEABLE.",
          "answers": [
            "ordinary",
            "impossible",
            "useful",
            "understandable",
            "wonderful"
          ],
          "word": "SERVICEABLE",
          "correct": "useful"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Quite TRANQUIL.",
          "answers": [
            "easy",
            "excited",
            "peaceful",
            "secret",
            "grateful"
          ],
          "word": "TRANQUIL",
          "correct": "peaceful"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Remained ANONYMOUS.",
          "answers": [
            "dangerous",
            "well known",
            "mysterious",
            "nameless",
            "far away"
          ],
          "word": "ANONYMOUS",
          "correct": "nameless"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Asked for the APPARATUS.",
          "answers": [
            "plan",
            "equipment",
            "container",
            "clothing",
            "assistant"
          ],
          "word": "APPARATUS",
          "correct": "equipment"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "To CAPSIZE the boat.",
          "answers": [
            "save",
            "overturn",
            "enlarge",
            "build",
            "sink"
          ],
          "word": "CAPSIZE",
          "correct": "overturn"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "We must COLLABORATE.",
          "answers": [
            "work together",
            "give up",
            "fight",
            "meet",
            "become better",
            null
          ],
          "word": "COLLABORATE",
          "correct": "work together"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "COMMEND them.",
          "answers": [
            "love",
            "scold",
            "protect",
            "select",
            "praise"
          ],
          "word": "COMMEND",
          "correct": "praise"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_1": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "Can a train be INTERCEPTED?",
          "word": "INTERCEPT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do people usually like someone who MEDDLES in their affairs?",
          "word": "MEDDLE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would people enjoy having MISGIVINGS?",
          "word": "MISGIVING",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Are some deaf people also MUTE?",
          "word": "MUTE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can you NEGOTIATE with someone you don't like?",
          "word": "NEGOTIATE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is wearing a seatbelt in a car a PRECAUTION?",
          "word": "PRECAUTION",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do all criminals REFORM?",
          "word": "REFORM",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can you RESUME an activity that you haven't done for a long time?",
          "word": "RESUME",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is a burnt-out light bulb SERVICEABLE?",
          "word": "SERVICEABLE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is a hurricane TRANQUIL?",
          "word": "TRANQUIL",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is William Shakespeare ANONYMOUS?",
          "word": "ANONYMOUS",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is water an APPARATUS?",
          "word": "APPARATUS",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can a boat CAPSIZE with people in it?",
          "word": "CAPSIZE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can a person COLLABORATE by himself?",
          "word": "COLLABORATE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would a person usually be COMMENDED for stealing money?",
          "word": "COMMEND",
          "correct": "false"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_2": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "The river INTERCEPTED the city right down the middle.",
          "word": "INTERCEPT",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "I don't like to MEDDLE, but I think you should listen to my advice.",
          "word": "MEDDLE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "She always has MISGIVINGS after she agrees to do something difficult.",
          "word": "MISGIVING",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He stood MUTE with wonder before the brilliant painting.",
          "word": "MUTE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The two lawyers NEGOTIATED a settlement in the case, so it never came to trial.",
          "word": "NEGOTIATE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He received a PRECAUTION from the teacher about his poor behavior.",
          "word": "PRECAUTION",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "She was in the habit of telling lies, but she REFORMED when she realized the trouble she caused.",
          "word": "REFORM",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "I RESUME that everyone will want to come to the beach with us.",
          "word": "RESUME",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The mechanic didn't make the car as good as new, but at least it was SERVICEABLE.",
          "word": "SERVICEABLE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "After several years of living in the busy city, she longed for the TRANQUILITY of life in the country.",
          "word": "TRANQUIL",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He got several ANONYMOUS messages saying he would be killed if he talked to the police.",
          "word": "ANONYMOUS",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "They used a complicated APPARATUS to help him breathe after the operation.",
          "word": "APPARATUS",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "They managed to hold onto the boat that had CAPSIZED until they were saved.",
          "word": "CAPSIZE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "No one wanted to COLLABORATE with the enemy soldiers when they conquered the city.",
          "word": "COLLABORATE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The principal COMMENDED them for their fine record in school.",
          "word": "COMMEND",
          "correct": "true"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_3": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "INTERCEPT",
          "answers": [
            "stop",
            "interrupt",
            "destroy"
          ],
          "word": "INTERCEPT",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "MEDDLE",
          "answers": [
            "bother",
            "interfere",
            "threaten"
          ],
          "word": "MEDDLE",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "MISGIVING",
          "answers": [
            "hatred",
            "worry",
            "suspicion"
          ],
          "word": "MISGIVING",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "MUTE",
          "answers": [
            "open",
            "silent",
            "wordless"
          ],
          "word": "MUTE",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "NEGOTIATE",
          "answers": [
            "expect",
            "discuss",
            "confer"
          ],
          "word": "NEGOTIATE",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "PRECAUTION",
          "answers": [
            "preparation",
            "rejection",
            "care"
          ],
          "word": "PRECAUTION",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "REFORM",
          "answers": [
            "improve",
            "repair",
            "approve"
          ],
          "word": "REFORM",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "RESUME",
          "answers": [
            "consider",
            "restart",
            "continue"
          ],
          "word": "RESUME",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "SERVICEABLE",
          "answers": [
            "satisfactory",
            "wonderful",
            "helpful"
          ],
          "word": "SERVICEABLE",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "TRANQUIL",
          "answers": [
            "quiet",
            "pretty",
            "gentle"
          ],
          "word": "TRANQUIL",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "ANONYMOUS",
          "answers": [
            "unknown",
            "unusual",
            "secret"
          ],
          "word": "ANONYMOUS",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "APPARATUS",
          "answers": [
            "tool",
            "motor",
            "rock"
          ],
          "word": "APPARATUS",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "CAPSIZE",
          "answers": [
            "upset",
            "leak",
            "overturn"
          ],
          "word": "CAPSIZE",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "COLLABORATE",
          "answers": [
            "laugh",
            "work",
            "join"
          ],
          "word": "COLLABORATE",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "COMMEND",
          "answers": [
            "approve",
            "applaud",
            "improve"
          ],
          "word": "COMMEND",
          "correct": "2"
        }
      ]
    },
    "definitions": {
      "INTERCEPT": {
        "word": "INTERCEPT",
        "phonetic": "(in-tÔøΩr-sept')",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to cut off, interrupt the course of \nSee _inter-_ under Prefixes. \nTo INTERCEPT something is to stop or catch it on its way from one place to another. In football, when someone INTERCEPTS a pass, he catches it before it reaches the person for whom it was intended. To INTERCEPT a message is to overhear or see it while it is going from the sender to the receiver. \n\"We tried to INTERCEPT the enemy's planes before they reached their targets.\" \nOther forms of the word: INTERCEPTION, n."
      },
      "MEDDLE": {
        "word": "MEDDLE",
        "phonetic": "(med'-1)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to interfere, butt in \nTo MEDDLE is to involve yourself in something without being asked or without having the right. \n\"People would get angry with him because he liked to MEDDLE in their private business.\" \n\"Please don't MEDDLE with these papers. They're too important.\" \n\"They accused him of MEDDLING, but he said he had every right to know what was going on.\" \nUsage: MEDDLE is usually followed by _with_ or _in_."
      },
      "MISGIVING": {
        "word": "MISGIVING",
        "phonetic": "(mis-giv'-ing)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "a doubt, suspicion \nTo have MISGIVINGS about something is to feel doubt or suspicion about it, to be unsure that it is right or that it will work. \n\"I had MISGIVINGS about this project from the start. I'm not surprised that it has failed completely.\" \n\"My mind was full of MISGIVINGS. I wasn't sure I wanted to do this at all.\" \n\"She had MISGIVINGS about hiring Bob. He didn't look honest to her.\" \nUsage: MISGIVING is usually used in the plural, MISGIVINGS."
      },
      "MUTE": {
        "word": "MUTE",
        "phonetic": "(myUt)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "silent, speechless, unable to speak \nA MUTE is someone who is unable to speak, usually because he was born deaf and has never heard spoken sounds. As an adjective, MUTE means _silent_, _not talking_. A person can be MUTE not only because he can't speak, but because he doesn't choose to speak. \n\"He remained MUTE while his mother scolded him.\" \n\"She took the food with MUTE thanks.\" \nMUTE is also a verb which means \"to muffle or soften the sound of.\" \n\"He MUTED the trumpet.\""
      },
      "NEGOTIATE": {
        "word": "NEGOTIATE",
        "phonetic": "(ni-gO'-shE-At)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to bargain, try to come to an agreement \nNEGOTIATE is especially used in business, law, and diplomacy. It can mean to _carry out_ or _conduct_. \n\"She NEGOTIATED an important business deal.\" \nUsually, though, its meaning is \"to arrange for or settle by bargaining or discussion.\" \n\"The union NEGOTIATED a new contract.\" \n\"He NEGOTIATED a peace treaty between the enemies.\" \nOther forms of the word: NEGOTIATION, n."
      },
      "PRECAUTION": {
        "word": "PRECAUTION",
        "phonetic": "(pri-ko'-sh:;,,n)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "a safeguard; foresight \nSee _pre-_ under Prefixes. _Caution_ is _care_, _carefulness_. PRECAUTION is care taken ahead of time in order to avoid something bad happening. \n\"He told them to use PRECAUTION when they were sailing in rough seas.\" \nA PRECAUTION is an act of caution done ahead of time. \n\"She took an umbrella as a PRECAUTION in case it rained later.\" \n\"You must take every PRECAUTION before clearing the mine field.\" \nOther forms of the word: PRECAUTIONARY, adj."
      },
      "REFORM": {
        "word": "REFORM",
        "phonetic": "(ri-form')",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to correct, improve, change for the better \nREFORM basically means \"to form something over again.\" See _re-_ under Prefixes. Usually REFORM has the sense of changing something for the better by removing faults or evil ways. \n\"The business promised to REFORM its sales practices so that it wouldn't mislead people.\" \n\"The kindly teacher managed to REFORM the rough boys by his good example.\" \nWhen someone REFORMS,he corrects bad habits and improves his character. \n\"I used to be an alcoholic,but I've REFORMED and now I never take a drink.\" \nA REFORM school or REFORMATORY is a place which tries to REFORM children who have broken the law. \nOther forms of the word: REFORMATION, n. REFORMATORY,n."
      },
      "RESUME": {
        "word": "RESUME",
        "phonetic": "(ri-zUm')",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to begin again, start anew \nSee _re-_ under Prefixes.To RESUME something is to take it up again after having stopped for a time. \n\"After a year of rest she RESUMED working.\" \n\"He came back twenty minutes later and RESUMED the story exactly where he had left off.\" \n\"I RESUMED playing tennis when the doctor said I should get more exercise.\" \nWhen something RESUMES it starts over again. \n\"The show RESUMED after the commercial.\" \nOther forms of the word: RESUMPTION,n."
      },
      "SERVICEABLE": {
        "word": "SERVICEABLE",
        "phonetic": "(ser'-vis-ÔøΩb:;,I)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "useful, helpful, able to be used, fit for use \nSERVICEABLE means \"able to be of SERVICE,\" _useful_. See _-able_ under Suffixes. If you make something SERVICEABLE, you fix it so that it can be used. \n\"His shoes were repaired so that they were SERVICEABLE for everyday use.\" \nSERVICEABLE often suggests that something is good enough for use without being outstanding. A SERVICEABLE object may not be the best or newest, but it will do the job. \n\"The pot was dented,but it was SERVICEABLE.\" \nOther forms of the word: SERVE, v. SERVICE, n."
      },
      "TRANQUIL": {
        "word": "TRANQUIL",
        "phonetic": "(trang'-kwÔøΩI)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "peaceful,calm,serene, unruffled \nTRANQUIL means \"free from anything that bothers or excites,\" peaceful. \n\"They live in a TRANQUIL little village, far from the noise and rush of the city.\" \n\"He remained TRANQUIL while everyone else ran about in confusion.\" \n\"The TRANQUIL stream became a noisy waterfall when it dropped off the cliff.\" \nThe noun from TRANQUIL is TRANQUILITY,which means _peacefulness_ or _calmness_. \n\"The nation's TRANQUILITY was disturbed by rumors of war.\" \n\"The TRANQUILITY of the afternoon was suddenly shattered by peals of thunder.\" \nOther forms of the word: TRANQUILITY, n. TRANQUILIZER, n."
      },
      "ANONYMOUS": {
        "word": "ANONYMOUS",
        "phonetic": "(ÔøΩnon'-ÔøΩm:;,s)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "nameless, of unknown name \nANONYMOUS means \"without a name.\" The word is used about a person whose name is not known or has not been revealed. \n\"The person who sent the gift wishes to remain ANONYMOUS.\" \n\"The composer of this ancient song is ANONYMOUS.\" \nIt is also used to mean \"of unknown source or origin.\" \n\"He received an ANONYMOUS phone call telling him where the bomb was located.\" \nANONYMITY is the state of being ANONYMOUS. \n\"The author tried to preserve his ANONYMITY by signing a false name to the article.\" \nMany people think ANONYMOUS means _mysterious_. An ANONYMOUS person might be mysterious, but for a specific reason: because his name is unknown. \nOther forms ofthe word: ANONYMITY,n."
      },
      "APPARATUS": {
        "word": "APPARATUS",
        "phonetic": "(ap-ÔøΩra'-tÔøΩs",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "equipment, mechanism \nAn APPARATUS is a set of instruments, materials, appliances, or machinery designed to work together for a specific purpose. In the human body it is a group of organs that work together toward one end. \n\"The skindiver's breathing APPARATUS was faulty. The oxygen tank did not connect properly with the nose mask.\" \nA fire truck is commonly called a fire APPARATUS because of all the various instruments it has that serve in fighting a fire. \n\"The building's powerful heating APPARATUS consists of a huge furnace and dozens of ducts that carry hot air circulated by fans.\""
      },
      "CAPSIZE": {
        "word": "CAPSIZE",
        "phonetic": "(kap'-slz)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to overturn, upset \nCAPSIZE is used especially about boats. The word means \"to turn upside down from a safe to a dangerous position.\" A boat can CAPSIZE, or something can CAPSIZE a boat. \n\"The little rowboat CAPSIZED in the rough waters of the bay.\" \n\"A huge wave CAPSIZED the canoe.\" \nOn the Pretest, _sink_ is a common choice as the meaning of CAPSIZE. When a boat CAPSIZES, however, it just turns over in the water. It is in danger of sinking, but it will not necessarily sink."
      },
      "COLLABORATE": {
        "word": "COLLABORATE",
        "phonetic": "(kÔøΩlab'-ÔøΩrAt)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to work together, cooperate \nSee _con-_ under Prefixes and _-ate1_ under Suffixes. Notice the word _labor_ in the middle of COLLABORATE. To COLLABORATE is to _labor_ or _work together_. \n\"Other scientists COLLABORATED with him in carrying out the research.\" \nThe word is often used about works of literature. \n\"The two authors COLLABORATED on a novel.\" \nIn a special sense, COLLABORATE often is used to mean \"to work with an enemy of one's country.\" \n\"After the war he was accused of COLLABORATING with the enemy forces.\" \nOther forms of the word: COLLABORATION, n. COLLABORATOR, n."
      },
      "COMMEND": {
        "word": "COMMEND",
        "phonetic": "(kÔøΩmend')",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to praise, recommend; to entrust \nTo COMMEND someone is to speak favorably of him, to praise him. \n\"I COMMEND you for your honesty.\" \n\"Bill's mother COMMENDED his handling of the emergency.\" \nOften the word suggests praising someone or something to someone else. In this sense COMMEND is close in meaning to _recommend_. \n\"The critic COMMENDED the book to anyone interested in fine writing.\" \nIn another sense, COMMEND means to _entrust_ or _commit_. \n\"The dying man COMMENDED his soul to God.\" \nThe most commonly chosen wrong answer is _scold_, which is just about the opposite of COMMEND. \nOther forms of the word: COMMENDABLE, adj. COMMENDATION, n."
      }
    }
  },
  {
    "title": "3.6",
    "pretest": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "To REFINE it.",
          "answers": [
            "spoil",
            "discover",
            "purify",
            "remove",
            "add to"
          ],
          "word": "REFINE",
          "correct": "purify"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Very INTRICATE.",
          "answers": [
            "simple",
            "complicated",
            "thin",
            "dangerous",
            "large"
          ],
          "word": "INTRICATE",
          "correct": "complicated"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "DENSE fog.",
          "answers": [
            "gray",
            "slight",
            "huge",
            "thick",
            "early"
          ],
          "word": "DENSE",
          "correct": "thick"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "How does this PERTAIN?",
          "answers": [
            "help",
            "relate",
            "continue",
            "end",
            "differ"
          ],
          "word": "PERTAIN",
          "correct": "relate"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "CORRUPT officials.",
          "answers": [
            "blunt",
            "upright",
            "dishonest",
            "political",
            "weak"
          ],
          "word": "CORRUPT",
          "correct": "dishonest"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Spoke of his DELINQUENCY.",
          "answers": [
            "negligence",
            "need",
            "anger",
            "cleverness",
            "sorrow"
          ],
          "word": "DELINQUENCY",
          "correct": "negligence"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Impressed by the ENSEMBLE.",
          "answers": [
            "size",
            "group",
            "similarity",
            "beginning",
            "width"
          ],
          "word": "ENSEMBLE",
          "correct": "group"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The man is very FRAIL.",
          "answers": [
            "old",
            "great",
            "frightened",
            "small",
            "weak"
          ],
          "word": "FRAIL",
          "correct": "weak"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "EXTENSIVE areas.",
          "answers": [
            "new",
            "narrow",
            "beautiful",
            "broad",
            "different"
          ],
          "word": "EXTENSIVE",
          "correct": "broad"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Saw the GLIMMER.",
          "answers": [
            "dim light",
            "dark cloud",
            "signal",
            "fire",
            "shadow"
          ],
          "word": "GLIMMER",
          "correct": "dim light"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "INSTANTANEOUS results.",
          "answers": [
            "slow",
            "immediate",
            "unexpected",
            "new",
            "wonderful"
          ],
          "word": "INSTANTANEOUS",
          "correct": "immediate"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "NOTABLE women.",
          "answers": [
            "lovely",
            "ordinary",
            "outstanding",
            "friendly",
            "modern"
          ],
          "word": "NOTABLE",
          "correct": "outstanding"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "They PENETRATED the jungle.",
          "answers": [
            "entered into",
            "escaped",
            "burned",
            "cut down",
            "approached"
          ],
          "word": "PENETRATE",
          "correct": "entered into"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The REEK of tobacco.",
          "answers": [
            "strong smell",
            "pleasure",
            "danger",
            "hatred",
            "bad taste"
          ],
          "word": "REEK",
          "correct": "strong smell"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Let us RETAIN it.",
          "answers": [
            "pack",
            "sell",
            "fix",
            "keep",
            "enjoy"
          ],
          "word": "RETAIN",
          "correct": "keep"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_1": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "Does a REFINED person have bad manners?",
          "word": "REFINE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is a hammer an INTRICATE tool?",
          "word": "INTRICATE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would it be difficult to walk through a DENSE jungle?",
          "word": "DENSE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can evidence PERTAIN to a crime?",
          "word": "PERTAIN",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would a CORRUPT police department be effective in fighting crime?",
          "word": "CORRUPT",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can old people be accused of DELINQUENCY?",
          "word": "DELINQUENCY",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is there more than one item in an ENSEMBLE?",
          "word": "ENSEMBLE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would a FRAIL person be a weightlifting champion?",
          "word": "FRAIL",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is there much wrong with something that has been EXTENSIVELY damaged?",
          "word": "EXTENSIVE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is it easy to see a GLIMMER?",
          "word": "GLIMMER",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do people learn to read INSTANTANEOUSLY?",
          "word": "INSTANTANEOUS",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Was George Washington a NOTABLE American?",
          "word": "NOTABLE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can a feather PENETRATE a rock?",
          "word": "PENETRATE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can a sewer REEK?",
          "word": "REEK",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can you RETAIN something that you have never had?",
          "word": "RETAIN",
          "correct": "false"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_2": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "The teacher REFINED the boy for stealing the book.",
          "word": "REFINE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The operation was so INTRICATE that it took several doctors many hours to complete it.",
          "word": "INTRICATE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The DENSE clouds meant that there might be a storm coming.",
          "word": "DENSE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "I do not understand how your remarks PERTAIN to the subject we are discussing.",
          "word": "PERTAIN",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The congressman was CORRUPTED by the expensive gifts he received from foreign agents.",
          "word": "CORRUPT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "If you are DELINQUENT in handing in this paper you won't pass the course.",
          "word": "DELINQUENCY",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "We listened to a small ENSEMBLE playing music from the turn of the century.",
          "word": "ENSEMBLE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The door was so FRAIL that a person could easily kick it in.",
          "word": "FRAIL",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The boss felt rather EXTENSIVE, so he took everyone in the office to dinner.",
          "word": "EXTENSIVE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "They watched the fireflies GLIMMERING in the twilight.",
          "word": "GLIMMER",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The people were INSTANTANEOUS to me, but I had a good time anyway.",
          "word": "INSTANTANEOUS",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The play was NOTABLE for its beautiful costumes.",
          "word": "NOTABLE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "They found it hard to PENETRATE the mysteries of this ancient civilization.",
          "word": "PENETRATE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "I couldn't stand the REEK of his cheap cigars.",
          "word": "REEK",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "It's hard to RETAIN your sense of humor when everyone is yelling at you.",
          "word": "RETAIN",
          "correct": "true"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_3": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "REFINE",
          "answers": [
            "clean",
            "settle",
            "improve"
          ],
          "word": "REFINE",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "INTRICATE",
          "answers": [
            "puzzling",
            "tangled",
            "false"
          ],
          "word": "INTRICATE",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "DENSE",
          "answers": [
            "strong",
            "thick",
            "close"
          ],
          "word": "DENSE",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "PERTAIN",
          "answers": [
            "solve",
            "connect",
            "relate"
          ],
          "word": "PERTAIN",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "CORRUPT",
          "answers": [
            "wicked",
            "angry",
            "dishonest"
          ],
          "word": "CORRUPT",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "DELINQUENCY",
          "answers": [
            "neglect",
            "rudeness",
            "crime"
          ],
          "word": "DELINQUENCY",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "ENSEMBLE",
          "answers": [
            "list",
            "group",
            "chorus"
          ],
          "word": "ENSEMBLE",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "FRAIL",
          "answers": [
            "weak",
            "sad",
            "ill"
          ],
          "word": "FRAIL",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "EXTENSIVE",
          "answers": [
            "necessary",
            "broad",
            "long"
          ],
          "word": "EXTENSIVE",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "GLIMMER",
          "answers": [
            "blaze",
            "gleam",
            "glow"
          ],
          "word": "GLIMMER",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "INSTANTANEOUS",
          "answers": [
            "eager",
            "quick",
            "sudden"
          ],
          "word": "INSTANTANEOUS",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "NOTABLE",
          "answers": [
            "famous",
            "outstanding",
            "clean"
          ],
          "word": "NOTABLE",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "PENETRATE",
          "answers": [
            "enter",
            "stop",
            "understand"
          ],
          "word": "PENETRATE",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "REEK",
          "answers": [
            "odor",
            "stink",
            "evil"
          ],
          "word": "REEK",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "RETAIN",
          "answers": [
            "keep",
            "return",
            "hold"
          ],
          "word": "RETAIN",
          "correct": "1"
        }
      ]
    },
    "definitions": {
      "REFINE": {
        "word": "REFINE",
        "phonetic": "(ri-fln')",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to purify \nTo REFINE something is to _purify_ it, to remove other substances from it so that it is pure and unmixed. Products like iron, oil, and sugar are REFINED before they are sold. To REFINE a person is to improve his manners, speech, and so on, to make him more elegant and cultivated. In this sense, the adjective REFINED means _polished_, _cultured_, \"free from coarseness or vulgarity.\" \n\"He is a very REFINED gentleman. He is always very polite and attentive.\" \nOther forms of the word: REFINEMENT, n. REFINERY, n."
      },
      "INTRICATE": {
        "word": "INTRICATE",
        "phonetic": "(in'-tri-kit)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "complicated, complex, involved \nINTRICATE comes from a Latin word meaning to _entangle_. Something that is INTRICATE has so many parts and connections working together in such complicated ways that it becomes difficult to follow or understand. \n\"We marveled at how long it must have taken to weave the INTRICATE pattern in the rug.\" \n\"It was hard to make sense of the INTRICATE plot of the spy novel.\" \n\"This INTRICATE machinery can only be fixed by an expert.\" \nOther forms of the word: INTRICACY, n."
      },
      "DENSE": {
        "word": "DENSE",
        "phonetic": "(dens)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "thick, compact \nDENSE means \"crowded closely together,\" _thick_. \n\"The trees were very DENSE in that part of the forest. It was very difficult to make your way through them.\" \n\"It was impossible to see anyone or anything in the DENSE fog.\" \n\"There was a DENSE crowd around the man playing the guitar.\" \nThe noun from DENSE is DENSITY, _thickness_. \n\"There were flowers everywhere, but they were at their greatest DENSITY right in the middle of the garden.\" \nOther forms of the word: DENSITY, n."
      },
      "PERTAIN": {
        "word": "PERTAIN",
        "phonetic": "(p::>r-tAn')",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to relate, belong as a part, be connected \nPERTAIN means \"to have to do with.\" PERTAIN does not necessarily suggest a strong or close connection, but would often be used about things that belong properly or fittingly to a particular subject or situation. \n\"None of his suggestions PERTAINED to the particular problem they were facing.\" \n\"We understand most of the circumstances that PERTAIN to her illness.\" \nUsage: PERTAIN is usually followed by _to_."
      },
      "CORRUPT": {
        "word": "CORRUPT",
        "phonetic": "(kÔøΩuhpt')",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "dishonest, immoral \nTo be CORRUPT is to be dishonest, immoral, or bad. The word is often used about public officials who take bribes and sell political favors. \n\"The mayor was so CORRUPT that the townspeople had him thrown out of office.\" \n\"Some people are CORRUPT in small ways, but can be very honest about other things.\" \nCORRUPT is also a verb that means \"to make dishonest or impure.\" \n\"They tried unsuccessfully to CORRUPT him. They offered him large bribes to falsify the records, but he refused them.\" \nOther forms of the word: CORRUPTION, n."
      },
      "DELINQUENCY": {
        "word": "DELINQUENCY",
        "phonetic": "(di-ling'-kw::>n-sE)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "negligence, wrongdoing \nTo be DELINQUENT is to do wrong, often by failing to do a duty. \n\"He was DELINQUENT in paying his taxes.\" \nDELINQUENCY is the state of being DELINQUENT. It is wrongdoing or neglect of duty. \n\"As a result of his DELINQUENCY in making the payments, the bank took the car away from him.\" \n\"Juvenile DELINQUENCY\" is wrongdoing by youths. \n\"The police could not handle the increase in juvenile DELINQUENCY.\" \nOther forms of the word: DELINQUENT, adj., n."
      },
      "ENSEMBLE": {
        "word": "ENSEMBLE",
        "phonetic": "(ahn-sahm'-bÔøΩI)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "a group; a general effect \nNote the pronunciation. ENSEMBLE is a French word meaning _together_, and the English pronunciation is almost the same as the French. In English, an ENSEMBLE is a group of people or things that act together to produce some result. The word is used about a group of musicians who play together. It is also used about items of clothing that go together to form a complete outfit. \n\"The complete ENSEMBLE costs much less when purchased all at once.\" \nENSEMBLE is also used about the general effect of something taken as a whole. \n\"Viewed individually the parts of the building were all beautiful, but the ENSEMBLE was somehow unsatisfying.\""
      },
      "FRAIL": {
        "word": "FRAIL",
        "phonetic": "(frAI)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "weak, lacking strength, easily broken, fragile \nFRAIL comes from the same Latin word as _fragile_. Both mean _weak_, _easily broken_. FRAIL is most often used about health and physical makeup. \n\"Tim is a very FRAIL little boy; he should not be forced to play rough sports.\" \n\"She is in FRAIL health; a sudden shock might do her great harm.\" \nFRAIL is sometimes used about other things as well. \n\"He thought the bridge looked rather FRAIL, so he decided not to drive his truck over it.\" \nThe noun from FRAIL is FRAILTY. \n\"As he grew older, his FRAILTY increased.\" \n\"This one little problem showed the FRAILTY of the entire system.\" \nMany people think FRAIL means _old_. An _old_ person is not necessarily FRAIL, however. \nOther forms of the word: FRAILTY, n."
      },
      "EXTENSIVE": {
        "word": "EXTENSIVE",
        "phonetic": "(ek-sten'-siv)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "wide, broad, far-reaching, thorough \nTo EXTEND means to _stretch out_ or _reach_. \n\"This desert EXTENDS for miles in every direction.\" \nSomething which is EXTENSIVE EXTENDS far, has a wide range. See _-ive_ under Suffixes. \n\"He owns an EXTENSIVE farm which covers most of the county.\" \n\"She has traveled EXTENSIVELY throughout the world.\" \n\"Jane has an EXTENSIVE knowledge of history.\" \n\"The car needed EXTENSIVE repairs.\" \nOther forms of the word: EXTEND, v. EXTENSION, n."
      },
      "GLIMMER": {
        "word": "GLIMMER",
        "phonetic": "(glim'-ÔøΩ)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "a dim, unsteady light; a faint idea, vague indication \nGLIMMER is related to the word _gleam_. Both are kinds of light. A _gleam_ is a flash of light, not very bright and usually not lasting very long. A GLIMMER is an even weaker light, so faint and unsteady that you are just able to see it. \n\"He saw the GLIMMER of their flashlights far up on the mountain.\" \nGLIMMER is also used as a verb. \n\"The campfire GLIMMERED in the distance.\" \nGLIMMER is also used to apply to ideas, hopes, possibilities, and other things that may be very faint. \n\"There was only a GLIMMER of hope left that any of them would make it.\" \n\"She didn't show a GLIMMER of the talent she was supposed to have.\""
      },
      "INSTANTANEOUS": {
        "word": "INSTANTANEOUS",
        "phonetic": "(in-stÔøΩn-tA'-nE-ÔøΩs)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "done in an INSTANT, immediate \nAn INSTANT is a very short space of time. \n\"He will be back in an INSTANT.\" \nINSTANTANEOUS comes from INSTANT and means \"done or happening in an INSTANT.\" \n\"He pulled the switch, and the explosion was INSTANTANEOUS.\" \n\"Their response to his suggestion was almost INSTANTANEOUS. They agreed right away.\" \n\"He never suffered. Death was INSTANTANEOUS.\" \n_Unexpected_ is often chosen as the meaning of INSTANTANEOUS, probably because you do not always expect something to happen immediately. \nOther forms of the word: INSTANT, n."
      },
      "NOTABLE": {
        "word": "NOTABLE",
        "phonetic": "(nOt'-ÔøΩbÔøΩI)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "worthy of note, remarkable, outstanding, striking \nNOTABLE means \"deserving to be noted or noticed,\" _remarkable_. The word is usually used in a good sense about someone who deserves to be famous because of his excellence. \n\"She was NOTABLE for her great skating ability.\" \n\"Many NOTABLE men and women were invited to dine with the president.\" \n\"Putting a man on the moon was a NOTABLE achievement.\""
      },
      "PENETRATE": {
        "word": "PENETRATE",
        "phonetic": "(pen'-ÔøΩtrAt)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to enter into, pass into or through \nTo PENETRATE something is to enter or pass into it. \n\"They PENETRATED deeper into the cave than anyone had before.\" \n\"The needle just barely PENETRATED the skin.\" \n\"We must PENETRATE into enemy territory before dawn.\" \nPENETRATE is also used in a general sense about seeing into or understanding something. \n\"How far can scientists PENETRATE into the secrets of nature?\" \nOther forms of the word: PENETRATION, n."
      },
      "REEK": {
        "word": "REEK",
        "phonetic": "(rEk)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "a strong smell \nA REEK is a strong, usually unpleasant smell. \n\"We could smell the REEK of rotting fish.\" \n\"The REEK of garlic was almost overpowering.\" \nREEK is also a verb meaning \"to give off a strong, unpleasant odor.\" \n\"The locker room REEKED with sweat.\" \n\"The closet REEKED of stale perfume.\" \nUsage: As a verb, REEK is usually followed by _of_ or _with_."
      },
      "RETAIN": {
        "word": "RETAIN",
        "phonetic": "(ri-tAn')",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to keep, continue to have; to keep in place \nTo RETAIN something is to hold onto it, to continue to have it. It is related to other words like _obtain_ and _contain_ which have to do with getting and holding. \n\"Despite the other team's rally, we RETAINED the lead at halftime.\" \n\"She RETAINS all the energy and enthusiasm she had when she was much younger.\" \nRETAIN also means \"to keep in place.\" \n\"A dam was built to RETAIN the water.\" \n\"Female kangaroos RETAIN their young in pouches on their abdomens.\""
      }
    },
    "reviewTest": {
      "wordList": [
        "ANTICIPATE",
        "CONGREGATE",
        "GOUGE",
        "INTRICATE",
        "PRECAUTION",
        "APPARATUS",
        "CONTROVERSY",
        "HEADWAY",
        "MISGIVING",
        "REFINE",
        "COLLABORATE",
        "DENSE",
        "INSTANTANEOUS",
        "PENETRATE",
        "RESUME",
        "COMMEND",
        "FOREMOST",
        "INTERCEPT",
        "PERTAIN",
        "RETAIN",
        "CONFRONT",
        "ACCUMULATE",
        "CORRUPT",
        "FRAIL",
        "INSTANCE",
        "REEK",
        "ANONYMOUS",
        "DELINQUENCY",
        "FREAKISH",
        "MEDDLE",
        "REFORM",
        "APPAREL",
        "ENSEMBLE",
        "GLIMMER",
        "MUTE",
        "SERVICEABLE",
        "CAPSIZE",
        "EXTENSIVE",
        "HABITABLE",
        "NEGOTIATE",
        "TRANQUIL",
        "COMPREHEND",
        "FELINE",
        "IMMENSE",
        "NOTABLE"
      ],
      "questions": [
        {
          "part1": "After taking a long vacation, she was able to",
          "part2": "working as if she'd never been away.",
          "answer": "resume"
        },
        {
          "part1": "He lost his money when his business failed, but he was able to",
          "part2": "his house and car.",
          "answer": "retain"
        },
        {
          "part1": "If you have any",
          "part2": "about what we are going to do, please tell us before we begin.",
          "answer": "misgivings"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The general",
          "part2": "the soldiers for their bravery during the battle.",
          "answer": "commended"
        },
        {
          "part1": "We began to",
          "part2": "the wine by straining it through a filter to get rid of the grape skins and seeds.",
          "answer": "refine"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The pattern of the streets is so",
          "part2": "in that part of town that we always get lost there.",
          "answer": "intricate"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The ground was so hard that the shovel couldn't",
          "part2": "it.",
          "answer": "penetrate"
        },
        {
          "part1": "I tried to",
          "part2": "with him on the project, but he couldn't stand to have anyone work with him.",
          "answer": "collaborate"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Hundreds of people",
          "part2": "in the park to hear the mayor's speech.",
          "answer": "congregated"
        },
        {
          "part1": "They didn't know that their mail was being",
          "part2": "and opened before they got it.",
          "answer": "intercepted"
        },
        {
          "part1": "He advised us to take every",
          "part2": "beforehand if we were going to drive in the blizzard.",
          "answer": "precaution"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The smoke was so",
          "part2": "in the room that none of us could breathe.",
          "answer": "dense"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Most of his speech",
          "part2": "to foreign affairs, but once in a while he also mentioned local problems.",
          "answer": "pertained"
        },
        {
          "part1": "It is hard to",
          "part2": "how he will react. He might be pleased, or he might be angry.",
          "answer": "anticipate"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Computers are designed to give nearly",
          "part2": "replies to requests for information.",
          "answer": "instantaneous"
        },
        {
          "part1": "I",
          "part2": "him with this new information and demanded that he explain what it meant.",
          "answer": "confronted"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The plan to build another highway caused a tremendous",
          "part2": "in the town; both sides debated the proposal for months.",
          "answer": "controversy"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The dentist's",
          "part2": "consists of drills, probes, mirrors, and other instruments.",
          "answer": "apparatus"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The professor is the world's",
          "part2": "authority on the history of Spain.",
          "answer": "foremost"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The cat",
          "part2": "a hole in the rug with its claw.",
          "answer": "gouged"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Tim's English grades have been improving, so it seems that he's making some",
          "part2": "in his understanding of grammar.",
          "answer": "headway"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Your",
          "part2": "in filing your tax returns may result in a fine.",
          "answer": "delinquency"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The statue of the Egyptian cat-goddess has a human body and a",
          "part2": "head.",
          "answer": "feline"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Some",
          "part2": "people have graduated from this school, including a president of the United States.",
          "answer": "notable"
        },
        {
          "part1": "He watched the taillights of their car until they were just a",
          "part2": "in the distance.",
          "answer": "glimmer"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Because he made fun of powerful people in his book, the author wanted to be",
          "part2": ".",
          "answer": "anonymous"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The skirt, blouse, and shoes went together to form a fine",
          "part2": "for the fall season.",
          "answer": "ensemble"
        },
        {
          "part1": "We had hoped for a new television, but the used set that we got is still",
          "part2": ".",
          "answer": "serviceable"
        },
        {
          "part1": "It is almost impossible to",
          "part2": "a thief who doesn't want to change.",
          "answer": "reform"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Can you give me one",
          "part2": "when I didn't do what you asked?",
          "answer": "instance"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The book has a(n)",
          "part2": "index which makes it easy to find whatever information you are looking for.",
          "answer": "extensive"
        },
        {
          "part1": "I don't know how she stays so",
          "part2": "with all the problems and annoyances she has.",
          "answer": "tranquil"
        },
        {
          "part1": "I hate the",
          "part2": "of frying onions. I have to leave the kitchen whenever they're being cooked.",
          "answer": "reek"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The little girl was so",
          "part2": "that even walking a few steps made her feel tired.",
          "answer": "frail"
        },
        {
          "part1": "She wore her fanciest",
          "part2": "to the expensive restaurant.",
          "answer": "apparel"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The agent",
          "part2": "a new contract at a higher salary for the baseball pitcher.",
          "answer": "negotiated"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Pam always",
          "part2": "in things that are none of her business.",
          "answer": "meddles"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The newspaper claimed that everyone in the town government was",
          "part2": "and becoming rich at the taxpayers' expense.",
          "answer": "corrupt"
        },
        {
          "part1": "It was a(n)",
          "part2": "accident. I've never seen one quite like it.",
          "answer": "freakish"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The mountain is so",
          "part2": "that it would take us weeks to climb it.",
          "answer": "immense"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Some people won't throw anything away; they",
          "part2": "lots of worthless stuff.",
          "answer": "accumulate"
        },
        {
          "part1": "I never could",
          "part2": "why she decided to quit school.",
          "answer": "comprehend"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The rough seas caused the motorboat to",
          "part2": ".",
          "answer": "capsize"
        },
        {
          "part1": "After the house was flooded, we lived in a motel until it was made",
          "part2": "again.",
          "answer": "habitable"
        },
        {
          "part1": "They nodded silently to each other in",
          "part2": "agreement.",
          "answer": "mute"
        }
      ]
    }
  },
  {
    "title": "3.7",
    "pretest": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "EXTRACT the thing.",
          "answers": [
            "pull out",
            "press against",
            "loosen",
            "work on",
            "leave"
          ],
          "word": "EXTRACT",
          "correct": "pull out"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "ROVING performers.",
          "answers": [
            "local",
            "wandering",
            "mad",
            "swimming",
            "constant"
          ],
          "word": "ROVING",
          "correct": "wandering"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Saw the FUGITIVE.",
          "answers": [
            "thief",
            "guard",
            "foreigner",
            "runaway",
            "drunk"
          ],
          "word": "FUGITIVE",
          "correct": "runaway"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Their COMPETENT king.",
          "answers": [
            "old",
            "dumb",
            "pleasant",
            "able",
            "tall"
          ],
          "word": "COMPETENT",
          "correct": "able"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He sought SECLUSION.",
          "answers": [
            "escape",
            "company",
            "privacy",
            "enjoyment",
            "information"
          ],
          "word": "SECLUSION",
          "correct": "privacy"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "SEEK them.",
          "answers": [
            "hide",
            "find",
            "search for",
            "talk about",
            "look at"
          ],
          "word": "SEEK",
          "correct": "search for"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "New SENSATION.",
          "answers": [
            "effect",
            "feeling",
            "meaning",
            "knowledge",
            "understanding"
          ],
          "word": "SENSATION",
          "correct": "feeling"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Examined the TEXTILE.",
          "answers": [
            "fur",
            "factory",
            "book",
            "machine",
            "cloth"
          ],
          "word": "TEXTILE",
          "correct": "cloth"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Found the SNARE.",
          "answers": [
            "nest",
            "key",
            "torch",
            "hole",
            "trap"
          ],
          "word": "SNARE",
          "correct": "trap"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Another CONSPIRACY.",
          "answers": [
            "threat",
            "discovery",
            "disaster",
            "plot",
            "robbery"
          ],
          "word": "CONSPIRACY",
          "correct": "plot"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Almost ready to SQUABBLE.",
          "answers": [
            "eat",
            "make up",
            "quarrel",
            "fall apart",
            "make noise"
          ],
          "word": "SQUABBLE",
          "correct": "quarrel"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "His STANCE.",
          "answers": [
            "looks",
            "position",
            "speech",
            "ability",
            "importance"
          ],
          "word": "STANCE",
          "correct": "position"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Constant EXERTION.",
          "answers": [
            "effort",
            "rest",
            "worry",
            "danger",
            "fear"
          ],
          "word": "EXERTION",
          "correct": "effort"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "It FATIGUES me.",
          "answers": [
            "tires",
            "interests",
            "saddens",
            "calms",
            "bores"
          ],
          "word": "FATIGUE",
          "correct": "tires"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "GRATIFIES him.",
          "answers": [
            "excites",
            "criticizes",
            "dislikes",
            "involves",
            "pleases"
          ],
          "word": "GRATIFY",
          "correct": "pleases"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_1": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "Can a splinter be EXTRACTED?",
          "word": "EXTRACT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is an animal that is kept in a cage able to ROVE?",
          "word": "ROVING",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Are FUGITIVES always evil?",
          "word": "FUGITIVE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is a baby COMPETENT to drive a car?",
          "word": "COMPETENT",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is a SECLUDED house far away from other houses?",
          "word": "SECLUSION",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do athletes SEEK to be champions?",
          "word": "SEEK",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would a talking horse cause a SENSATION?",
          "word": "SENSATION",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is cotton a TEXTILE?",
          "word": "TEXTILE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can a mouse be SNARED?",
          "word": "SNARE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can there be just one person in a CONSPIRACY?",
          "word": "CONSPIRACY",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can people like each other and still SQUABBLE?",
          "word": "SQUABBLE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would a person who has no opinions take many STANCES on issues?",
          "word": "STANCE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would most people EXERT themselves in running ten miles?",
          "word": "EXERTION",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Does a good night's sleep FATIGUE you?",
          "word": "FATIGUE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Does a thirsty person find a drink of water GRATIFYING?",
          "word": "GRATIFY",
          "correct": "true"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_2": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "We were EXTRACTED from buying a new car by the high price.",
          "word": "EXTRACT",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Our ROVING days came to an end when we settled down in a small valley.",
          "word": "ROVING",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The guards searched the woods for the FUGITIVE.",
          "word": "FUGITIVE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "I was impressed by his COMPETENCE at typing.",
          "word": "COMPETENT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He was constantly going to parties to find SECLUSION.",
          "word": "SECLUSION",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "They were SEEKING a good place to vacation.",
          "word": "SEEK",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He had a strange SENSATION that someone was following him.",
          "word": "SENSATION",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "They use only the highest quality TEXTILES in making these suits.",
          "word": "TEXTILE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "We shot the pigeons with a SNARE.",
          "word": "SNARE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The reporter discovered a CONSPIRACY to hide the truth about the plane crash.",
          "word": "CONSPIRACY",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "It was just a minor SQUABBLE. No one got very angry.",
          "word": "SQUABBLE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The president was praised for his STANCE on foreign aid.",
          "word": "STANCE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Everyone ignored his EXERTIONS to the team to try harder.",
          "word": "EXERTION",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Just watching them work so hard almost makes me feel FATIGUED.",
          "word": "FATIGUE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He GRATIFIED us that we had to go with him or we would be punished.",
          "word": "GRATIFY",
          "correct": "false"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_3": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "EXTRACT",
          "answers": [
            "show",
            "pull",
            "get"
          ],
          "word": "EXTRACT",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "ROVING",
          "answers": [
            "straying",
            "marching",
            "roaming"
          ],
          "word": "ROVING",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "FUGITIVE",
          "answers": [
            "runaway",
            "escapee",
            "thief"
          ],
          "word": "FUGITIVE",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "COMPETENT",
          "answers": [
            "skillful",
            "qualified",
            "lovely"
          ],
          "word": "COMPETENT",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "SECLUSION",
          "answers": [
            "extra",
            "alone",
            "apart"
          ],
          "word": "SECLUSION",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "SEEK",
          "answers": [
            "search",
            "look",
            "recover"
          ],
          "word": "SEEK",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "SENSATION",
          "answers": [
            "feel",
            "excite",
            "remember"
          ],
          "word": "SENSATION",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "TEXTILE",
          "answers": [
            "cloth",
            "silk",
            "copper"
          ],
          "word": "TEXTILE",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "SNARE",
          "answers": [
            "hold",
            "catch",
            "free"
          ],
          "word": "SNARE",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "CONSPIRACY",
          "answers": [
            "secret",
            "foreign",
            "illegal"
          ],
          "word": "CONSPIRACY",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "SQUABBLE",
          "answers": [
            "lonely",
            "angry",
            "annoyed"
          ],
          "word": "SQUABBLE",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "STANCE",
          "answers": [
            "position",
            "behavior",
            "attitude"
          ],
          "word": "STANCE",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "EXERTION",
          "answers": [
            "struggle",
            "wait",
            "try"
          ],
          "word": "EXERTION",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "FATIGUE",
          "answers": [
            "destroy",
            "wear out",
            "exhaust"
          ],
          "word": "FATIGUE",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "GRATIFY",
          "answers": [
            "delight",
            "satisfy",
            "allow"
          ],
          "word": "GRATIFY",
          "correct": "2"
        }
      ]
    },
    "definitions": {
      "EXTRACT": {
        "word": "EXTRACT",
        "phonetic": "(ek-strakt')",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to pull out, draw forth, obtain \nSee _ex-_ under Prefixes. To EXTRACT something is to pull it out of something else. The word usually suggests that force or effort was necessary. \n\"The dentist EXTRACTED the tooth.\" \n\"The doctor EXTRACTED the bullet from his shoulder.\" \nEXTRACT also often suggests pulling something out against someone's will. \n\"Before we left, we EXTRACTED a promise from him that he would behave.\" \n\"After three days of torturing the prisoner they managed to EXTRACT the information from him.\" \nEXTRACT is also used for the process of obtaining juice or some other substance by squeezing, crushing, or boiling something. \n\"They EXTRACTED the oil from the peanuts.\" \nOther forms of the word: EXTRACTION, n."
      },
      "ROVING": {
        "word": "ROVING",
        "phonetic": "(rO'-ving)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "wandering, roaming \nTo ROVE is to move about a large area, usually without a specific purpose. ROVING means \"moving here and there,\" _wandering_. \n\"A ROVING band of gypsies passed by our town last week.\" \n\"There are ROVING wolves out there in the wilderness.\" \nOther forms of the word: ROVE, v."
      },
      "FUGITIVE": {
        "word": "FUGITIVE",
        "phonetic": "(fyU'-jÔøΩtiv)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "a runaway, one who flees \nA FUGITIVE is a person who runs away. Usually the word is used about escaped criminals or prisoners, but it can be used about anyone who flees. \n\"The FUGITIVES who had escaped from prison last night were last seen headed for the mountains.\" \n\"We captured the FUGITIVE after a long chase.\" \nFUGITIVE is also an adjective. \n\"The FUGITIVE slaves were caught and returned to their masters.\" \nAs an adjective, FUGITIVE often means _fleeting_, _passing quickly_. \n\"These FUGITIVE dreams were difficult to recall afterwards.\" \n_Thief_ is often chosen as the meaning of FUGITIVE on the Pretest. A FUGITIVE may be a criminal or someone who has done something wrong, but he is not necessarily a _thief_."
      },
      "COMPETENT": {
        "word": "COMPETENT",
        "phonetic": "(kom'-pÔøΩtÔøΩnt)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "able, capable, well qualified \nSomeone who is COMPETENT can do what is required in a particular job. COMPETENT does not suggest outstanding ability, but ability that is satisfactory or adequate for what has to be done. \n\"Ted thinks he's a wonderful drummer, but I think he's just barely COMPETENT.\" \n\"Now that he's fourteen, we think he's COMPETENT to take care of his little sister.\" \n\"She is COMPETENT in math and chemistry, but she has never been any good at languages.\" \nThe noun from COMPETENT is COMPETENCE, which means _ability_ or _skill_. \n\"No one would question his COMPETENCE as a teacher. His students really learn the subject.\" \nCOMPETENT is often thought to mean _pleasant_. A person can be COMPETENT, however, without being pleasant at all. \nOther forms of the word: COMPETENCE, n."
      },
      "SECLUSION": {
        "word": "SECLUSION",
        "phonetic": "(si-klU'-zhÔøΩn)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "privacy, aloneness, isolation \nSECLUSION is the noun form of the verb SECLUDE. To SECLUDE something is to keep it away from others. \n\"She led a SECLUDED life far away from the rest of humanity.\" \nSECLUSION means _privacy_, _isolation_. A person or thing that is in SECLUSION is cut off from others, either willingly or unwillingly. \n\"He searched for SECLUSION from the noise and bustle of the city, so he moved to a village in Vermont.\" \n\"We kept the cat in SECLUSION until she had her kittens.\" \nOther forms of the word: SECLUDE, v."
      },
      "SEEK": {
        "word": "SEEK",
        "phonetic": "(sEk)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to search for, look for, try to find; to try, attempt \nTo SEEK something is to look for it, to try to find it. \n\"The young man went to London to SEEK a job.\" \n\"She was SEEKING shelter from the wind while she waited for the bus.\" \nWhen followed by _to_, SEEK means to _try_ or _attempt_. \n\"She SEEKS to become the first person to climb that mountain.\" \nMany people think SEEK means _find_. But someone who SEEKS something may not _find_ it. \n\"He SOUGHT wealth, but remained poor.\" \nUsage: The past tense of SEEK is SOUGHT."
      },
      "SENSATION": {
        "word": "SENSATION",
        "phonetic": "(sen-sA'-shQn)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "a feeling, awareness; excitement \nTo SENSE is to have feeling, to have an awareness of something through your SENSES. \n\"The dog SENSED that someone was coming\"—that is, it heard, smelled, or saw that someone was coming. \nSENSATION is a noun from SENSE. Its basic meaning is a _feeling_, an _awareness_ of some kind. \n\"He felt a slight tickling SENSATION on his skin.\" \n\"It was a wonderful SENSATION to sink into the warm bath.\" \nSENSATION is also used for a state of excited feelings occurring among a group of people. \n\"Her appearance caused quite a SENSATION at the party.\" \nThe word can also stand for a person or thing causing the SENSATION. \n\"Her new dress was the SENSATION of the party.\" \nOther forms of the word: SENSE, v., n. SENSATIONAL, adj."
      },
      "TEXTILE": {
        "word": "TEXTILE",
        "phonetic": "(teks'-tll)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "a cloth, fabric, material \nA TEXTILE is a cloth or some material that can be woven into a cloth. Silk, wool, and cotton are examples of TEXTILES. \n\"The TEXTILE for the king's robe has threads of gold in it.\" \n\"Many towns in New England used to have TEXTILE mills.\" \n\"His company specializes in TEXTILES that are used for curtains.\" \nMany people choose _factory_ as the meaning of TEXTILE, probably because TEXTILES are made in factories."
      },
      "SNARE": {
        "word": "SNARE",
        "phonetic": "(snair)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "a trap \nA SNARE is a trap which is used to catch animals. It is usually made of wire or cord formed into a loop. \n\"The trapper set out several SNARES for rabbits.\" \nThe word can also be used in a general sense about anything that traps. \n\"They found themselves caught in the SNARES of the sick man's evil plans.\" \nSNARE is also a verb meaning to _trap_, _entangle_, or _catch_. \n\"He was SNARED in the tangles of his lies.\""
      },
      "CONSPIRACY": {
        "word": "CONSPIRACY",
        "phonetic": "(kQn-spir'-ÔøΩsE)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "a plot, secret plan \nSee _con-_ under Prefixes. To CONSPIRE is to plot together secretly, usually to do something illegal. \n\"Those men CONSPIRED to steal thousands of dollars from the government.\" \nA CONSPIRACY is this act of plotting, or the people who do the plotting. \n\"There is a CONSPIRACY in the company to cover up their illegal actions.\" \n\"He joined a CONSPIRACY which was out to overthrow the government.\" \nA \"CONSPIRACY of silence\" is a secret agreement not to talk publicly about something. \n\"There was a CONSPIRACY of silence about the possible dangerous side effects of the new drug.\" \nOther forms of the word: CONSPIRATOR, n. CONSPIRATORIAL, adj. CONSPIRE, v."
      },
      "SQUABBLE": {
        "word": "SQUABBLE",
        "phonetic": "(skwob'-ÔøΩI)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to quarrel, argue, fight, bicker \nTo SQUABBLE is to quarrel or argue about something unimportant. The word does not suggest very bitter or angry feelings. \n\"They often SQUABBLE over what to eat for supper.\" \n\"He SQUABBLED with his neighbors over who was supposed to fix the fence.\" \nSQUABBLE is also a noun and means \"a small, unimportant quarrel.\" \n\"They had a SQUABBLE over which TV program to watch.\" \nMany people think to SQUABBLE means to _make noise_, probably because SQUABBLES are often noisy."
      },
      "STANCE": {
        "word": "STANCE",
        "phonetic": "(stans)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "a position, stand, attitude \nA person's STANCE is his position when standing up. \n\"In the painting the king had an unusual STANCE, leaning back against his horse.\" \n\"The golfer took up his STANCE next to the ball and prepared to hit it.\" \nSTANCE can also be used about a mental position or attitude. \n\"He never changed his firm STANCE on the uselessness of exercise.\" \n\"Once his father took a STANCE on something, he never changed his mind.\""
      },
      "EXERTION": {
        "word": "EXERTION",
        "phonetic": "(eg-zer'-shÔøΩn)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "effort, vigorous action, exercise, struggle \nTo EXERT means to _bring into use_, to _put forth_. \n\"He EXERTED all his strength to move the refrigerator.\" \n\"Janet EXERTED her influence to help her friend get a job.\" \nTo EXERT yourself is to put forth effort in doing something. EXERTION is the act of EXERTING. EXERTION is usually difficult and requires a great deal of effort. \n\"In spite of all his EXERTIONS he couldn't move the piano.\" \n\"She was worn out from the EXERTION of trying to teach her students.\" \nMental EXERTION is effort that uses the mind. \n\"His job involved much running around, but little mental EXERTION.\" \nOther forms of the word: EXERT, v."
      },
      "FATIGUE": {
        "word": "FATIGUE",
        "phonetic": "(fa-tEg')",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to tire, weary, exhaust \nFATIGUE is both a verb and a noun. FATIGUE is _tiredness_, usually caused by working too hard, either physically or mentally. \n\"After four hours of digging they were overcome by FATIGUE and had to rest.\" \nTo become FATIGUED is to tire out. \n\"Cleaning the house quickly FATIGUED him.\" \n\"They were too FATIGUED to swim any further.\" \nMany people think that to be FATIGUED is to be _bored_. Sometimes the words may be close in meaning, as in the sentence \"His constant talking began to FATIGUE her.\" But the words do not have the same meaning."
      },
      "GRATIFY": {
        "word": "GRATIFY",
        "phonetic": "(grat'-ÔøΩfl)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to please, satisfy, indulge \nSee _-fy_ under Suffixes. GRATIFY comes from a Latin word meaning _pleasing_, _thankful_, also the source of the words _grateful_ and _gratitude_. Someone who is _grateful_ is pleased about something, is thankful for it. To GRATIFY someone is to make him pleased, to give him pleasure by satisfying his desires. \n\"Your decision to go on to college GRATIFIES me tremendously.\" \n\"We are all GRATIFIED with the results.\" \n\"I am GRATIFIED to learn that you are finally earning some money.\" \nOther forms of the word: GRATIFICATION, n. GRATIFYING, adj."
      }
    }
  },
  {
    "title": "3.8",
    "pretest": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "ACUTE pain.",
          "answers": [
            "dull",
            "sharp",
            "constant",
            "widespread",
            "increasing"
          ],
          "word": "ACUTE",
          "correct": "sharp"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Saw the TYPHOON.",
          "answers": [
            "hurricane",
            "snowstorm",
            "island",
            "monster",
            "whirlpool"
          ],
          "word": "TYPHOON",
          "correct": "hurricane"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Quietly REVIVE.",
          "answers": [
            "lower",
            "murder",
            "replace",
            "live",
            "renew"
          ],
          "word": "REVIVE",
          "correct": "renew"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The MEMENTO of our trip.",
          "answers": [
            "story",
            "planning",
            "enjoyment",
            "reminder",
            "result"
          ],
          "word": "MEMENTO",
          "correct": "reminder"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "ILLITERATE people.",
          "answers": [
            "lazy",
            "clever",
            "uneducated",
            "insane",
            "working"
          ],
          "word": "ILLITERATE",
          "correct": "uneducated"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "LOFTY places.",
          "answers": [
            "windy",
            "high",
            "low",
            "dirty",
            "wonderful"
          ],
          "word": "LOFTY",
          "correct": "high"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Her speech was INCOMPARABLE.",
          "answers": [
            "stupid",
            "similar",
            "unequaled",
            "very long",
            "interesting"
          ],
          "word": "INCOMPARABLE",
          "correct": "unequaled"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "PHENOMENAL success.",
          "answers": [
            "extraordinary",
            "usual",
            "so-called",
            "dangerous",
            "immediate"
          ],
          "word": "PHENOMENAL",
          "correct": "extraordinary"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "INFALLIBLE treatments.",
          "answers": [
            "important",
            "doubtful",
            "helpful",
            "unbearable",
            "unfailing"
          ],
          "word": "INFALLIBLE",
          "correct": "unfailing"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "INSTRUMENTAL advice.",
          "answers": [
            "welcome",
            "harmful",
            "remembered",
            "useful",
            "excellent"
          ],
          "word": "INSTRUMENTAL",
          "correct": "useful"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "In charge of the MANEUVER.",
          "answers": [
            "skillful move",
            "escape route",
            "headquarters",
            "sneak attack",
            "takeover"
          ],
          "word": "MANEUVER",
          "correct": "skillful move"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The land is PARCHED.",
          "answers": [
            "sandy",
            "soaked",
            "curved",
            "divided",
            "dry"
          ],
          "word": "PARCHED",
          "correct": "dry"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "RELUCTANT to leave.",
          "answers": [
            "eager",
            "unwilling",
            "pleased",
            "trying",
            "unable"
          ],
          "word": "RELUCTANT",
          "correct": "unwilling"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Tried to THRUST it.",
          "answers": [
            "crush",
            "pull",
            "push",
            "catch",
            "kick"
          ],
          "word": "THRUST",
          "correct": "push"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He was the TRAITOR.",
          "answers": [
            "spy",
            "patriot",
            "soldier",
            "robber",
            "betrayer"
          ],
          "word": "TRAITOR",
          "correct": "betrayer"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_1": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "Would a blind person have ACUTE vision?",
          "word": "ACUTE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do TYPHOONS occur at the North Pole?",
          "word": "TYPHOON",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can doctors sometimes REVIVE patients whose hearts have stopped beating?",
          "word": "REVIVE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Could a flower be a MEMENTO?",
          "word": "MEMENTO",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Are you ILLITERATE?",
          "word": "ILLITERATE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is the presidency a LOFTY position?",
          "word": "LOFTY",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would a dull TV show be called INCOMPARABLE?",
          "word": "INCOMPARABLE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is getting up in the morning a PHENOMENAL action?",
          "word": "PHENOMENAL",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is the president of the United States INFALLIBLE?",
          "word": "INFALLIBLE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is reading INSTRUMENTAL in increasing your vocabulary?",
          "word": "INSTRUMENTAL",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can a MANEUVER be graceful?",
          "word": "MANEUVER",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would grass be PARCHED after a blizzard?",
          "word": "PARCHED",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would a RELUCTANT reader be likely to go to the library often?",
          "word": "RELUCTANT",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can you THRUST a mountain?",
          "word": "THRUST",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Was George Washington a TRAITOR to the United States?",
          "word": "TRAITOR",
          "correct": "false"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_2": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "Didn't the baby look ACUTE in her pretty pink bonnet!",
          "word": "ACUTE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "A warm TYPHOON blew softly in from the sea.",
          "word": "TYPHOON",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The other team's dirty play REVIVED our determination to win.",
          "word": "REVIVE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Jim wrote himself a MEMENTO about going to the store after school.",
          "word": "MEMENTO",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He was so ILLITERATE that he wouldn't even lend his own mother a dollar.",
          "word": "ILLITERATE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Ed had a LOFTY opinion of himself. He thought he was one of the greatest men in the world.",
          "word": "LOFTY",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He is an INCOMPARABLE painter; no one is quite as great as he is.",
          "word": "INCOMPARABLE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He was a PHENOMENAL athlete. He starred in every sport he tried.",
          "word": "PHENOMENAL",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "No one has yet found an INFALLIBLE way to cure all diseases.",
          "word": "INFALLIBLE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "I hope I can be INSTRUMENTAL in helping you with this project.",
          "word": "INSTRUMENTAL",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He MANEUVERED his way up close to the famous actor.",
          "word": "MANEUVER",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The huge explosion PARCHED the house.",
          "word": "PARCHED",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He is very RELUCTANT; something always goes wrong with things he tries to do.",
          "word": "RELUCTANT",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "She THRUST her hand into the hole and felt around for the lost ring.",
          "word": "THRUST",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "She was blackmailed into becoming a TRAITOR to her country.",
          "word": "TRAITOR",
          "correct": "true"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_3": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "ACUTE",
          "answers": [
            "severe",
            "average",
            "keen"
          ],
          "word": "ACUTE",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "TYPHOON",
          "answers": [
            "snow",
            "rain",
            "storm"
          ],
          "word": "TYPHOON",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "REVIVE",
          "answers": [
            "refresh",
            "release",
            "renew"
          ],
          "word": "REVIVE",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "MEMENTO",
          "answers": [
            "decision",
            "keepsake",
            "remembrance"
          ],
          "word": "MEMENTO",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "ILLITERATE",
          "answers": [
            "untaught",
            "ignorant",
            "unreasonable"
          ],
          "word": "ILLITERATE",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "LOFTY",
          "answers": [
            "noble",
            "pretty",
            "high"
          ],
          "word": "LOFTY",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "INCOMPARABLE",
          "answers": [
            "sad",
            "matchless",
            "great"
          ],
          "word": "INCOMPARABLE",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "PHENOMENAL",
          "answers": [
            "wonderful",
            "unusual",
            "new"
          ],
          "word": "PHENOMENAL",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "INFALLIBLE",
          "answers": [
            "necessary",
            "sure",
            "certain"
          ],
          "word": "INFALLIBLE",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "INSTRUMENTAL",
          "answers": [
            "useful",
            "helpful",
            "additional"
          ],
          "word": "INSTRUMENTAL",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "MANEUVER",
          "answers": [
            "trick",
            "movement",
            "battle"
          ],
          "word": "MANEUVER",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "PARCHED",
          "answers": [
            "hot",
            "dry",
            "tired"
          ],
          "word": "PARCHED",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "RELUCTANT",
          "answers": [
            "hesitant",
            "cautious",
            "impatient"
          ],
          "word": "RELUCTANT",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "THRUST",
          "answers": [
            "throw",
            "force",
            "stop"
          ],
          "word": "THRUST",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "TRAITOR",
          "answers": [
            "deserter",
            "merchant",
            "betrayer"
          ],
          "word": "TRAITOR",
          "correct": "1"
        }
      ]
    },
    "definitions": {
      "ACUTE": {
        "word": "ACUTE",
        "phonetic": "(ÔøΩkyUt')",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "sharp, extreme, severe, keen \nACUTE can be used in several slightly different ways, all with the basic meaning of _sharp_. When the word is used to describe the senses, feelings, or the mind it means _sharp_, _keen_, _quick_. \n\"The doctor advised him that an ACUTE pain in his chest could be due to a heart attack.\" \n\"Dogs have an ACUTE sense of smell.\" \n\"We hired the man because of his ACUTE mind.\" \nA situation can be ACUTE when it is severe, urgent, and demanding of attention. \n\"There was an ACUTE shortage of housing after the war.\" \n\"This information is of ACUTE importance.\" \nAn ACUTE triangle in geometry is a sharp angle, one that is less than 90°."
      },
      "TYPHOON": {
        "word": "TYPHOON",
        "phonetic": "(tl-fUn')",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "a hurricane, storm \nA TYPHOON is a violent storm or hurricane that occurs in the Pacific Ocean around Southeast Asia. During a TYPHOON there are usually huge waves and high winds. \n\"The ship was caught in the TYPHOON, but managed to survive the storm.\" \n\"During the TYPHOON many beach houses were swept away by the angry waters.\" \n\"TYPHOONS usually build up in the late summer.\""
      },
      "REVIVE": {
        "word": "REVIVE",
        "phonetic": "(ri-vlv')",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to bring back to life, renew \nTo REVIVE is to come or bring back to life. See _re-_ under Prefixes. REVIVE can be used about actual life or consciousness. \n\"The doctors managed to REVIVE the patient after his heart attack.\" \n\"She fainted when she heard the news, but quickly REVIVED.\" \nThe word can also be used about things that have become weak, unused, or inactive. \n\"Her arrival REVIVED a party that had become dull.\" \n\"They REVIVED a play that hadn't been staged in forty years.\" \n\"My interest in the subject REVIVED when I read this new book.\" \nOther forms of the word: REVIVAL, n."
      },
      "MEMENTO": {
        "word": "MEMENTO",
        "phonetic": "(mÔøΩmen'-tO)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "a reminder, keepsake, souvenir \nMEMENTO comes from the Latin word for _remember_, also the source of the word _memory_. A MEMENTO is an object that is kept in memory of a certain person or event. \n\"She kept the ticket stub as a MEMENTO of their evening together.\" \n\"They presented him with the football as a MEMENTO of the victory.\" \n\"She liked to keep MEMENTOS of all the happy occasions of her life.\""
      },
      "ILLITERATE": {
        "word": "ILLITERATE",
        "phonetic": "{i-lit'-ÔøΩrit)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "uneducated, unable to read or write \nThe word _literate_ comes from the Latin word for _letter_. A _literate_ person is educated; specifically, he knows the alphabet, he knows how to read and write. \n\"He was barely _literate_. It took him a long time to read just one sentence.\" \nThe opposite of _literate_ is ILLITERATE. See _in-2_ under Prefixes and _-ate2_ under Suffixes. ILLITERATE means \"unable to read and write.\" \n\"He was totally ILLITERATE. He had no idea what a book was for.\" \n\"How many students are ILLITERATE when they graduate from high school?\" \nOther forms of the word: ILLITERACY, n."
      },
      "LOFTY": {
        "word": "LOFTY",
        "phonetic": "(lof'-tE)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "high, towering; elevated, noble, stately \nAn old meaning of the word _loft_ was the _upper regions_, the _sky_. This meaning is still found in the word _aloft_, which means _in the air_. LOFTY is also related to _loft_ and means _very high_, _towering_. See _-y_ under Suffixes. \n\"We were all impressed by the LOFTY mountains.\" \n\"The eagle was in its LOFTY nest.\" \nLOFTY always includes a sense of dignity and impressiveness. The word is often used about ideas, people, speeches, and so on. \n\"He expressed his LOFTY thoughts in equally noble language.\" \n\"She achieved her LOFTY position through hard work and talent.\""
      },
      "INCOMPARABLE": {
        "word": "INCOMPARABLE",
        "phonetic": "(in-kom'-pÔøΩr-ÔøΩbÔøΩI)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "beyond compare, unequaled, matchless \nSee _in-2_ under Prefixes and _-able_ under Suffixes. To _compare_ things is to judge how much alike they are. INCOMPARABLE means \"not able to be compared with anything else.\" INCOMPARABLE is almost always used about good qualities. Something that is INCOMPARABLE is so wonderful or great that nothing else even comes close. \n\"Her cookies were good, her pies were delicious, but her cakes were INCOMPARABLE.\" \n\"His ability to add numbers in his head was INCOMPARABLE.\" \n\"Her INCOMPARABLE charm made us all like her.\""
      },
      "PHENOMENAL": {
        "word": "PHENOMENAL",
        "phonetic": "(fi-nom'-ÔøΩnÔøΩI)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "extraordinary, outstanding, remarkable \nThe basic meaning of the noun PHENOMENON is \"an observable fact or event,\" but in common use, PHENOMENON is generally applied to _extraordinary_ facts, events, or people. \n\"This young basketball player is a PHENOMENON. He scores forty points every game.\" \nPHENOMENAL is the adjective from PHENOMENON. See _-al_ under Suffixes. Something that is PHENOMENAL is very surprising or extraordinary. \n\"He had PHENOMENAL success in the stock market.\" \n\"She made a PHENOMENAL recovery and came home only three days after the operation.\" \n\"A PHENOMENAL number of people voted in the last election; an all-time record was set.\" \nOther forms of the word: PHENOMENON, n."
      },
      "INFALLIBLE": {
        "word": "INFALLIBLE",
        "phonetic": "(in-fal'-ÔøΩbÔøΩI)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "not capable of making a mistake, unfailing, unerring \nSee _in-2_ under Prefixes. Someone who is _fallible_ is capable of error. \n\"You'll have to excuse his occasional mistakes. He's only _fallible_, after all.\" \nSomeone who is INFALLIBLE is never wrong, cannot make a mistake. \n\"He has an INFALLIBLE eye for talent.\" \n\"She is INFALLIBLE at predicting the winners of football games.\" \nSomething that is INFALLIBLE never fails; it is certain to succeed. \n\"He had an INFALLIBLE cure for hiccups.\" \n\"He claimed he had discovered an INFALLIBLE method for getting rich quick.\" \nOther forms of the word: INFALLIBILITY, n."
      },
      "INSTRUMENTAL": {
        "word": "INSTRUMENTAL",
        "phonetic": "{in-strÔøΩment-ÔøΩI)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "useful, helpful \nThe basic meaning of the noun INSTRUMENT is \"a means by which something is done.\" A surgical INSTRUMENT is a tool that is useful in performing surgery. A musical INSTRUMENT is an object with which you make music. \nINSTRUMENTAL means \"serving as an INSTRUMENT or means.\" See _-al_ under Suffixes. \n\"His suggestion was INSTRUMENTAL in solving the problem; without it I don't know what I would have done.\" \n\"His spectacular fielding was INSTRUMENTAL to our victory.\" \nOther forms of the word: INSTRUMENT, n. \nUsage: INSTRUMENTAL is often followed by _in_ or _to_."
      },
      "MANEUVER": {
        "word": "MANEUVER",
        "phonetic": "(mÔøΩ-nU'-vÔøΩr)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "a planned movement of troops; a skillful move \nThe basic meaning of MANEUVER is \"a military or naval movement,\" carried out with regard to the position of the enemy, the condition of the land, and so on. \n\"The general carried out a skillful MANEUVER which brought our troops around to the rear of the enemy.\" \nFrom this the word has come to be used about any skillful move or plan designed to win something, do something, or escape from something. \n\"He used a clever MANEUVER to get them both in the same room together.\" \n\"The newspaper criticized the tricky MANEUVERS he had used to win the election.\" \nMANEUVER is also a verb. \n\"She MANEUVERED her way through the crowd.\" \n\"He MANEUVERED them into agreeing with his position.\""
      },
      "PARCHED": {
        "word": "PARCHED",
        "phonetic": "(pahrcht)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "dry, dried out, scorched \nTo PARCH something is to dry it out, especially through too much heat. \n\"Three straight months of sunlight PARCHED the corn.\" \nSomething that is PARCHED is dried out. \n\"Nothing will grow in this PARCHED land. It's almost a desert.\" \n\"After running a mile in the heat his throat was PARCHED. He longed for a drink of water.\" \nOther forms of the word: PARCH, v."
      },
      "RELUCTANT": {
        "word": "RELUCTANT",
        "phonetic": "(ri-luhk'-tÔøΩnt)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "unwilling, disinclined \nSomeone who is RELUCTANT to do something doesn't want to do it. He may do it, but it would be done against his will. \n\"I was RELUCTANT to enter the haunted house.\" \n\"June was RELUCTANT to go to the party at first, but we talked her into it.\" \n\"Bill convinced his RELUCTANT father to let him have the car.\" \nMany people think RELUCTANT means _eager_, which is an exact opposite. \nOther forms of the word: RELUCTANCE, n."
      },
      "THRUST": {
        "word": "THRUST",
        "phonetic": "(thruhst)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to push, shove \nTo THRUST something is to push or shove it forward with great force or suddenness. \n\"She THRUST the money at the cab driver and didn't wait for change.\" \n\"The soldier THRUST his sword into the man's side.\" \n\"He THRUST his hands into his pockets to keep them warm.\" \nTHRUST is also a noun which means a _push_ or _shove_. \n\"The army's THRUST into enemy territory was pushed back.\" \nOn the Pretest, the most common wrong answer for the meaning of THRUST is _pull_, which is an exact opposite. \nUsage: The past tense of THRUST is the same as the present tense: THRUST."
      },
      "TRAITOR": {
        "word": "TRAITOR",
        "phonetic": "(trA'-tÔøΩ)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "a betrayer \nA TRAITOR is a person who is not loyal to his own country or side. A TRAITOR betrays the people who trust him. \n\"Benedict Arnold was a TRAITOR to the United States when he gave secrets to the British.\" \n\"He is the worst kind of TRAITOR, because he betrayed his friends for money.\" \nMany people confuse TRAITOR with _spy_. A spy is a person who tries to obtain secret information. He may work for his own country or for someone else's, so a spy is not necessarily a TRAITOR. \nOther forms of the word: TRAITOROUS, adj."
      }
    }
  },
  {
    "title": "3.9",
    "pretest": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "FOOLHARDY youths.",
          "answers": [
            "careful",
            "reckless",
            "strong",
            "tricky",
            "brave"
          ],
          "word": "FOOLHARDY",
          "correct": "reckless"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "We shall ALTER it.",
          "answers": [
            "stop",
            "keep",
            "change",
            "start",
            "increase"
          ],
          "word": "ALTER",
          "correct": "change"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Another CONCEPT.",
          "answers": [
            "feeling",
            "decision",
            "mistake",
            "choice",
            "idea"
          ],
          "word": "CONCEPT",
          "correct": "idea"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "PERSISTENT efforts.",
          "answers": [
            "lasting",
            "occasional",
            "successful",
            "useless",
            "necessary"
          ],
          "word": "PERSISTENT",
          "correct": "lasting"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "DOMESTIC life.",
          "answers": [
            "real",
            "foreign",
            "exciting",
            "animal",
            "home"
          ],
          "word": "DOMESTIC",
          "correct": "home"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "PATHETIC children.",
          "answers": [
            "tiny",
            "admirable",
            "friendly",
            "pitiful",
            "lonely"
          ],
          "word": "PATHETIC",
          "correct": "pitiful"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The door was AJAR.",
          "answers": [
            "partly open",
            "locked",
            "boarded up",
            "huge",
            "swinging"
          ],
          "word": "AJAR",
          "correct": "partly open"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "A different PIGMENT.",
          "answers": [
            "soap",
            "design",
            "fairytale",
            "layer",
            "coloring"
          ],
          "word": "PIGMENT",
          "correct": "coloring"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Too RIGID.",
          "answers": [
            "soft",
            "heavy",
            "cold",
            "stiff",
            "quick"
          ],
          "word": "RIGID",
          "correct": "stiff"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "They were AUTHENTIC.",
          "answers": [
            "old",
            "real",
            "huge",
            "fake",
            "excellent"
          ],
          "word": "AUTHENTIC",
          "correct": "real"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "FRANK statements.",
          "answers": [
            "loud",
            "secret",
            "awful",
            "open",
            "good"
          ],
          "word": "FRANK",
          "correct": "open"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The empty CHAMBER.",
          "answers": [
            "prison",
            "garden",
            "room",
            "barrel",
            "hallway"
          ],
          "word": "CHAMBER",
          "correct": "room"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "We EMBRACED.",
          "answers": [
            "hugged",
            "wept",
            "stood still",
            "kissed",
            "held hands"
          ],
          "word": "EMBRACE",
          "correct": "hugged"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Another JUVENILE.",
          "answers": [
            "student",
            "criminal",
            "youth",
            "assistant",
            "actor"
          ],
          "word": "JUVENILE",
          "correct": "youth"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "They beat us HANDILY.",
          "answers": [
            "easily",
            "with difficulty",
            "with help",
            "by luck",
            "fairly"
          ],
          "word": "HANDILY",
          "correct": "easily"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_1": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "Is it usually FOOLHARDY to attack someone who is pointing a gun at you?",
          "word": "FOOLHARDY",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "When something is ALTERED, it is always better?",
          "word": "ALTER",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Are CONCEPTS always true?",
          "word": "CONCEPT",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "If a person spends two hours trying to open a stuck window, is he being PERSISTENT?",
          "word": "PERSISTENT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would DOMESTIC cigars have to be brought into the country?",
          "word": "DOMESTIC",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Could a PATHETIC sight make a person cry?",
          "word": "PATHETIC",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can something get in through a door that is AJAR?",
          "word": "AJAR",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do artists use PIGMENTS?",
          "word": "PIGMENT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is wool RIGID?",
          "word": "RIGID",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can something new have any AUTHENTICITY?",
          "word": "AUTHENTIC",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is a liar FRANK?",
          "word": "FRANK",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would a CHAMBERMAID be a maid who cleans bedrooms?",
          "word": "CHAMBER",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do people who are in love like to EMBRACE?",
          "word": "EMBRACE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do most JUVENILES go to school?",
          "word": "JUVENILE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "If a football team won by sixty points, did it win HANDILY?",
          "word": "HANDILY",
          "correct": "true"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_2": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "This new lock is FOOLHARDY; I guarantee it will never fail.",
          "word": "FOOLHARDY",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "We shouldn't ALTER the arrangement of furniture in the room.",
          "word": "ALTER",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Long ago scientists disproved the popular CONCEPT that Earth was the center of the universe.",
          "word": "CONCEPT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "If you PERSIST in making noise you won't get any dessert tonight.",
          "word": "PERSISTENT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Although he was always getting into trouble at work, his DOMESTIC life was calm and peaceful.",
          "word": "DOMESTIC",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The boy started crying PATHETICALLY when he realized he was lost.",
          "word": "PATHETIC",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "We locked the doors and made sure they were completely AJAR.",
          "word": "AJAR",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He wanted to get a darker blue, so he used a different PIGMENT.",
          "word": "PIGMENT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "They put steel rods into the pole to keep it RIGID.",
          "word": "RIGID",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "We tried to be AUTHENTIC about his mistake, but we were just too upset by it.",
          "word": "AUTHENTIC",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Their FRANK admiration of his work made him feel good.",
          "word": "FRANK",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "They held their meetings in a large CHAMBER on the second floor.",
          "word": "CHAMBER",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "They EMBRACED her by telling her everything was going to be all right.",
          "word": "EMBRACE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Although my father is almost fifty, he's still pretty JUVENILE in some ways.",
          "word": "JUVENILE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The lamp fell off the shelf and broke HANDILY on the floor.",
          "word": "HANDILY",
          "correct": "false"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_3": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "FOOLHARDY",
          "answers": [
            "daring",
            "intelligent",
            "foolish"
          ],
          "word": "FOOLHARDY",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "ALTER",
          "answers": [
            "adjust",
            "change",
            "oppose"
          ],
          "word": "ALTER",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "CONCEPT",
          "answers": [
            "belief",
            "memory",
            "theory"
          ],
          "word": "CONCEPT",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "PERSISTENT",
          "answers": [
            "stubborn",
            "eager",
            "constant"
          ],
          "word": "PERSISTENT",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "DOMESTIC",
          "answers": [
            "common",
            "native",
            "family"
          ],
          "word": "DOMESTIC",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "PATHETIC",
          "answers": [
            "awful",
            "weird",
            "sad"
          ],
          "word": "PATHETIC",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "AJAR",
          "answers": [
            "open",
            "unclosed",
            "shut"
          ],
          "word": "AJAR",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "PIGMENT",
          "answers": [
            "brush",
            "color",
            "paint"
          ],
          "word": "PIGMENT",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "RIGID",
          "answers": [
            "unpleasant",
            "firm",
            "strict"
          ],
          "word": "RIGID",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "AUTHENTIC",
          "answers": [
            "true",
            "original",
            "huge"
          ],
          "word": "AUTHENTIC",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "FRANK",
          "answers": [
            "direct",
            "faithful",
            "sincere"
          ],
          "word": "FRANK",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "CHAMBER",
          "answers": [
            "bedroom",
            "study",
            "yard"
          ],
          "word": "CHAMBER",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "EMBRACE",
          "answers": [
            "destroy",
            "hug",
            "accept"
          ],
          "word": "EMBRACE",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "JUVENILE",
          "answers": [
            "young",
            "stupid",
            "childish"
          ],
          "word": "JUVENILE",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "HANDILY",
          "answers": [
            "expertly",
            "nearly",
            "easily"
          ],
          "word": "HANDILY",
          "correct": "1"
        }
      ]
    },
    "definitions": {
      "FOOLHARDY": {
        "word": "FOOLHARDY",
        "phonetic": "(fUI'-hahr-dE)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "reckless, foolishly brave \nOne meaning of the word _hardy_ is _brave_, _daring_. \n\"The _hardy_ adventurers set off to explore the jungle.\" \nFOOLHARDY means _foolishly hardy_. Someone who is FOOLHARDY takes unnecessary risks and lacks judgment in facing danger. \n\"They were FOOLHARDY to try to swim across the flooding river.\" \n\"The FOOLHARDY boy tried to walk a tightrope between the two buildings.\" \nMany people think FOOLHARDY means _brave_. But in FOOLHARDY the emphasis is on being _foolishly_ brave. \n\"He thought he was brave to attack the enemy headquarters singlehandedly, but everyone else thought he was FOOLHARDY.\""
      },
      "ALTER": {
        "word": "ALTER",
        "phonetic": "(al'-tÔøΩr)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to change \nTo ALTER something is to make it different without changing it completely. \n\"We ALTERED the schedule to allow the principal to speak first.\" \n\"The book made him ALTER his ideas on many subjects.\" \n\"The house looked greatly ALTERED as a result of the redecorating.\" \nOther forms of the word: ALTERATION, n."
      },
      "CONCEPT": {
        "word": "CONCEPT",
        "phonetic": "(kon'-sept)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "an idea, thought, notion \nCONCEPT is related to the word CONCEIVE, which means to _think_ or _imagine_. \n\"I cannot CONCEIVE of a better way to spend the day.\" \nA CONCEPT is an _idea_, especially a general idea. \n\"The CONCEPT of gravity is not an easy one to understand.\" \n\"He agreed with the CONCEPT that all men are created equal.\" \n\"The teacher tried to teach him the CONCEPT of fractions.\" \nOther forms of the word: CONCEPTION, n. CONCEPTUAL, adj."
      },
      "PERSISTENT": {
        "word": "PERSISTENT",
        "phonetic": "(pÔøΩ-sis'-tÔøΩnt)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "continuing, lasting, enduring \nPERSIST means to _keep on_ or _continue_. \n\"The rain will PERSIST through the weekend.\" \nWhen someone PERSISTS in doing something, he keeps on doing it despite opposition. \n\"He PERSISTED in trying to open the door even after we told him it was nailed shut.\" \nSomeone or something that is PERSISTENT is inclined to PERSIST. See _-ant_ under Suffixes. \n\"He is a very PERSISTENT salesman. He just won't take no for an answer.\" \n\"She's had that PERSISTENT cough for over a week now. I think she should see a doctor.\" \n\"The reporter's PERSISTENT questions finally uncovered the truth.\" \n\"The PERSISTENT increase in prices has everyone worried.\" \nOther forms of the word: PERSIST, v. PERSISTENCE, n."
      },
      "DOMESTIC": {
        "word": "DOMESTIC",
        "phonetic": "(dÔøΩmes'-tik)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "of the home or family; native \nDOMESTIC comes from the Latin word for _house_. DOMESTIC means \"of the home, family, or house.\" \n\"The man's DOMESTIC problems interfered with his work.\" \n\"When he became rich he hired a butler, a maid, and other DOMESTIC help.\" \n\"He never achieved DOMESTIC happiness; he was divorced three times.\" \nIn a broader sense, DOMESTIC can mean \"of one's own country\" and is the opposite of _foreign_ or _imported_. \n\"He said that some DOMESTIC wines are as good as the best imported French wines.\" \n\"The president's DOMESTIC policy stressed lower taxes and less crime.\" \nOther forms of the word: DOMESTICATE, v. DOMESTICITY, n."
      },
      "PATHETIC": {
        "word": "PATHETIC",
        "phonetic": "(po-thet'-ik)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "pitiful, pitiable, sad, sorrowful \nSomething that is PATHETIC stirs up the emotions of pity and sympathy in people. \n\"The housing inspector told the reporter that the living conditions in the slum were PATHETIC.\" \n\"A PATHETIC little dog was roaming around our neighborhood last night, crying for its owner.\" \n\"The actress who had been so proud and beautiful in her youth was now old and PATHETIC.\" \nSometimes PATHETIC stresses how bad or inadequate something is. In this sense, something that is PATHETIC stirs up contempt more than pity. \n\"Our basketball team's performance was just PATHETIC last night. We lost by fifty points.\" \nOther forms of the word: PATHOS, n."
      },
      "AJAR": {
        "word": "AJAR",
        "phonetic": "(ÔøΩjahr')",
        "pos": "adj., adv.",
        "deftext": "partially open \nAJAR means _slightly open_. AJAR is used about anything that can be opened and closed, but it is used mainly about doors. \n\"She left the door AJAR so that a little light came in.\" \n\"The burglar found a window that was AJAR, so he climbed in through it.\""
      },
      "PIGMENT": {
        "word": "PIGMENT",
        "phonetic": "(pig'-mÔøΩnt)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "coloring, coloring matter \nPIGMENT is the part of paint or other material that gives it its color. \n\"The artist mixed several PIGMENTS together to get the color he wanted.\" \n\"Many PIGMENTS are made of natural materials.\" \nOther forms of the word: PIGMENTATION, n."
      },
      "RIGID": {
        "word": "RIGID",
        "phonetic": "(rij'-id)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "stiff, unbending; strict, inflexible \nSomething that is RIGID is hard to bend; it is stiff and unyielding. \n\"These poles must be RIGID or the tent will collapse.\" \n\"His back had to be kept RIGID after the operation.\" \nThis meaning is extended to apply to anyone or anything that is strict, firm, or hard to change. \n\"They had a RIGID system for teaching arithmetic in that school. Teachers had to follow it exactly.\" \n\"All the rules are RIGIDLY enforced, so you had better not break any.\" \n\"Why do you have to be so RIGID about this? Couldn't you give in just a little?\" \nOther forms of the word: RIGIDITY, n."
      },
      "AUTHENTIC": {
        "word": "AUTHENTIC",
        "phonetic": "(o-then'-tik)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "real, genuine, true \nSomething that is AUTHENTIC is what it is said to be; it is not faked. \n\"If that painting is AUTHENTIC, then it's worth many times what you paid for it.\" \n\"The difference between an AUTHENTIC diamond and a fake one isn't always easy to see.\" \n\"This dog is an AUTHENTIC champion; he has won many awards.\" \nThe noun form of AUTHENTIC is AUTHENTICITY, which means _genuineness_. \n\"I cannot accept the AUTHENTICITY of this coin until I have it examined by an expert.\" \nAUTHENTIC is often confused with _old_. Something that is brand new can be AUTHENTIC, however, if it is genuine or true. \nOther forms of the word: AUTHENTICITY, n."
      },
      "FRANK": {
        "word": "FRANK",
        "phonetic": "(frangk)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "open, sincere, outspoken, candid, undisguised \nSomeone who is FRANK speaks openly about what is on his mind; he doesn't hide or disguise his opinions or feelings out of shyness or politeness. \n\"He was very FRANK in his opinion of my intelligence: he told me I was a total moron.\" \nFRANK can also be used about the opinions or statements of someone who is FRANK. \n\"He made a FRANK confession about why he had really come.\" \n\"Her FRANK criticism was exactly what I needed.\" \nThe most commonly chosen incorrect answer on the Pretest is _good_, probably because FRANKNESS is usually thought to be a good quality."
      },
      "CHAMBER": {
        "word": "CHAMBER",
        "phonetic": "(chAm'-bÔøΩr)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "a room; an enclosed space \nA CHAMBER is a _room_, particularly a private room or a bedroom in a house. \n\"The judge has a special CHAMBER next to the courtroom where he can have private discussions with people.\" \n\"The queen went to her private CHAMBER up near the top of the castle.\" \nCHAMBER is also used about any kind of small enclosed space. A part of a gun is a small CHAMBER that holds the bullet to be fired. \nUsage: CHAMBER is a rather formal word, and would not often be used in everyday speech."
      },
      "EMBRACE": {
        "word": "EMBRACE",
        "phonetic": "(em-brAs'",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to hug, to make use of, come to believe in \nTo EMBRACE a person is to take him or her into your arms, usually to show your friendship or love. EMBRACE can be either a verb or a noun. \n\"We EMBRACED eagerly.\" \n\"They held each other in a long EMBRACE.\" \nEMBRACE is also used in a wider sense, meaning \"to take or accept eagerly,\" as if it were a loved one you were EMBRACING. To EMBRACE an opportunity is to welcome it and make use of it immediately. To EMBRACE a cause is to believe wholeheartedly in it. \n\"Many scientists immediately EMBRACED the new theory.\""
      },
      "JUVENILE": {
        "word": "JUVENILE",
        "phonetic": "(jU'-vÔøΩnll",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "a young person, a youth \nA JUVENILE is a young person. \n\"As a JUVENILE, he had to work every bit as hard as he did when he grew up.\" \n\"The three JUVENILES were sent home and told to obey their parents.\" \nAs an adjective, JUVENILE is often used in a bad sense to mean _immature_, _childish_. \n\"We thought his silly practical jokes were rather JUVENILE.\" \nMany people pick _criminal_ as the meaning of JUVENILE. This is probably because JUVENILE is often used in the phrase \"JUVENILE delinquent.\" A \"JUVENILE delinquent\" is a young person who breaks the law and cannot be controlled by his or her parents. Only a few JUVENILES are \"JUVENILE delinquents,\" however."
      },
      "HANDILY": {
        "word": "HANDILY",
        "phonetic": "(han'-dÔøΩIE)",
        "pos": "adv.",
        "deftext": "easily, expertly \nHANDILY comes from the word HANDY. Someone who is HANDY is clever in using his hands. \n\"He is very HANDY at fixing things around the house.\" \nHANDILY means \"with little trouble,\" _easily_. It is used about anything that happens or is done with no difficulty, not just things that require using your hands. \n\"In spite of falling down at the beginning of the race, he came back to win HANDILY.\" \n\"She passed her final exams HANDILY.\" \nOther forms of the word: HANDY, adj."
      }
    },
    "reviewTest": {
      "wordList": [
        "ACUTE",
        "EMBRACE",
        "ILLITERATE",
        "JUVENILE",
        "PHENOMENAL",
        "AUTHENTIC",
        "FATIGUE",
        "INCOMPARABLE",
        "LOFTY",
        "RELUCTANT",
        "COMPETENT",
        "FRANK",
        "INFALLIBLE",
        "MANEUVER",
        "SECLUSION",
        "CONCEPT",
        "FUGITIVE",
        "INSTRUMENTAL",
        "PARCHED",
        "THRUST",
        "DOMESTIC",
        "AJAR",
        "EXTRACT",
        "PATHETIC",
        "ROVING",
        "STANCE",
        "ALTER",
        "FOOLHARDY",
        "PERSISTENT",
        "SEEK",
        "TEXTILE",
        "CHAMBER",
        "GRATIFY",
        "PIGMENT",
        "SENSATION",
        "TRAITOR",
        "CONSPIRACY",
        "HANDILY",
        "REVIVE",
        "SNARE",
        "TYPHOON",
        "EXERTION",
        "MEMENTO",
        "RIGID",
        "SQUABBLE"
      ],
      "questions": [
        {
          "part1": "The two friends",
          "part2": "each other when they met.",
          "answer": "embraced"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The twenty-mile hike really",
          "part2": "us; we could barely stand up.",
          "answer": "fatigued"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Through a series of skillful",
          "part2": "he managed to become the only possible candidate for president of the company.",
          "answer": "maneuvers"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The shortage of gasoline became so",
          "part2": "that long lines formed at gas stations.",
          "answer": "acute"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Her singing was",
          "part2": "; some say she was the greatest singer who ever lived.",
          "answer": "incomparable"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The",
          "part2": "mountains towered thousands of feet into the air.",
          "answer": "lofty"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Fred was so certain that he was right that he was extremely",
          "part2": "to admit that he might have made a mistake.",
          "answer": "reluctant"
        },
        {
          "part1": "If weather forecasters were",
          "part2": ", then we could always believe their predictions.",
          "answer": "infallible"
        },
        {
          "part1": "That summer all the trees were",
          "part2": "from lack of rainfall.",
          "answer": "parched"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The poor boy was",
          "part2": ". He had never had the chance to go to school and learn how to read.",
          "answer": "illiterate"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Interest in this book is",
          "part2": ". Everyone seems to be talking about it.",
          "answer": "phenomenal"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Ben didn't have any experience in these matters, so he was not",
          "part2": "to solve the problem.",
          "answer": "competent"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Her",
          "part2": "happiness suffered greatly when her husband left home.",
          "answer": "domestic"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The police searched for months before finally capturing the",
          "part2": ".",
          "answer": "fugitive"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The man lived on an island because he wanted to find some",
          "part2": "from the rest of the world.",
          "answer": "seclusion"
        },
        {
          "part1": "I admire the",
          "part2": "way in which he tells you what is bothering him.",
          "answer": "frank"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Because he was fond of young people, the man decided to specialize in the teaching of",
          "part2": ".",
          "answer": "juveniles"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Bill just couldn't understand the",
          "part2": "that students must study in order to learn.",
          "answer": "concept"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Ed wasn't putting on an act; his unhappiness was",
          "part2": ".",
          "answer": "authentic"
        },
        {
          "part1": "A degree in business administration can be",
          "part2": "in getting a good job.",
          "answer": "instrumental"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Tom",
          "part2": "the knife deep into the cushion and ripped it apart.",
          "answer": "thrust"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The plant",
          "part2": "after I watered it.",
          "answer": "revived"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Even after it was proved that he had betrayed his country, it was hard for many people to believe that he really was a(n)",
          "part2": ".",
          "answer": "traitor"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Next to his bedroom he had a small",
          "part2": "where he would sit and study.",
          "answer": "chamber"
        },
        {
          "part1": "He wasn't used to so much",
          "part2": ", so he was very tired after climbing all those stairs.",
          "answer": "exertion"
        },
        {
          "part1": "We put out several",
          "part2": "to trap the rabbits.",
          "answer": "snares"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The criminal tried to",
          "part2": "his appearance so that no one would recognize him.",
          "answer": "alter"
        },
        {
          "part1": "She made a(n)",
          "part2": "attempt to stop the runaway horse and ended up with several broken bones.",
          "answer": "foolhardy"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Ann kept the postcard as a(n)",
          "part2": "of her happy vacation.",
          "answer": "memento"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The runner broke the world's record",
          "part2": "; he had seconds to spare.",
          "answer": "handily"
        },
        {
          "part1": "During the gold rush many miners came to California to",
          "part2": "their fortunes.",
          "answer": "seek"
        },
        {
          "part1": "They would",
          "part2": "over the most unimportant things.",
          "answer": "squabble"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Joe took up a threatening",
          "part2": "in front of the door and dared everyone to try to get by him.",
          "answer": "stance"
        },
        {
          "part1": "It was quite an unpleasant",
          "part2": "to have the cold rain dripping down his neck.",
          "answer": "sensation"
        },
        {
          "part1": "She left the door",
          "part2": "for us so that we could get in without a key.",
          "answer": "ajar"
        },
        {
          "part1": "This factory produces",
          "part2": "that are used in making sheets and pillowcases.",
          "answer": "textiles"
        },
        {
          "part1": "A dozen men secretly joined the",
          "part2": "to kidnap the business leader.",
          "answer": "conspiracy"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The old saying, \"If at first you don't succeed, try, try again,\" advises us to be",
          "part2": ".",
          "answer": "persistent"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The ship sank in the high winds and huge waves of the",
          "part2": ".",
          "answer": "typhoon"
        },
        {
          "part1": "She will give in on some things, but she is",
          "part2": "about this; no one is allowed to smoke in her house.",
          "answer": "rigid"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The beggar told us a(n)",
          "part2": "story about how he had lost all he owned in a fire.",
          "answer": "pathetic"
        },
        {
          "part1": "They could not",
          "part2": "any information from him about the enemy's plans.",
          "answer": "extract"
        },
        {
          "part1": "In days of old there were many",
          "part2": "knights who wandered about the country looking for wrongs to right.",
          "answer": "roving"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The artist mixed together the",
          "part2": "to get the exact shade of green he needed.",
          "answer": "pigments"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Your approval",
          "part2": "us immensely. We had hoped you'd like it.",
          "answer": "gratified"
        }
      ]
    }
  },
  {
    "title": "3.10",
    "pretest": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "He has EXCEEDED our wishes.",
          "answers": [
            "gone beyond",
            "gone against",
            "agreed with",
            "asked about",
            "met"
          ],
          "word": "EXCEED",
          "correct": "gone beyond"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "COMPILE the facts.",
          "answers": [
            "read",
            "need",
            "find",
            "forget",
            "assemble"
          ],
          "word": "COMPILE",
          "correct": "assemble"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The place of the MASSACRE.",
          "answers": [
            "truce",
            "slaughter",
            "religious service",
            "accident",
            "battle"
          ],
          "word": "MASSACRE",
          "correct": "slaughter"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "LAVISH gifts.",
          "answers": [
            "over-generous",
            "cheap",
            "unexpected",
            "very useful",
            "pretty"
          ],
          "word": "LAVISH",
          "correct": "over-generous"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "CONTRADICTS the story.",
          "answers": [
            "believes",
            "confirms",
            "denies",
            "leaves out",
            "dislikes"
          ],
          "word": "CONTRADICT",
          "correct": "denies"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "To OBTAIN it.",
          "answers": [
            "want",
            "get",
            "need",
            "lose",
            "keep"
          ],
          "word": "OBTAIN",
          "correct": "get"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "LINGER for awhile.",
          "answers": [
            "stir",
            "run",
            "stay",
            "stretch",
            "relax"
          ],
          "word": "LINGER",
          "correct": "stay"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "To UTTER lies.",
          "answers": [
            "read",
            "hear",
            "believe",
            "make up",
            "speak"
          ],
          "word": "UTTER",
          "correct": "speak"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Constant AMUSEMENT.",
          "answers": [
            "hope",
            "work",
            "pride",
            "fun",
            "excitement"
          ],
          "word": "AMUSEMENT",
          "correct": "fun"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Many CASUALTIES.",
          "answers": [
            "prisoners",
            "improvements",
            "greetings",
            "mistakes",
            "accidents"
          ],
          "word": "CASUALTY",
          "correct": "accidents"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "CONCEITED men.",
          "answers": [
            "young",
            "humble",
            "dishonest",
            "vain",
            "good-looking"
          ],
          "word": "CONCEITED",
          "correct": "vain"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Saw the GULLY.",
          "answers": [
            "boat",
            "hill",
            "ditch",
            "stream",
            "swamp"
          ],
          "word": "GULLY",
          "correct": "ditch"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Near the CZAR.",
          "answers": [
            "priest",
            "peasant",
            "river",
            "ruler",
            "general"
          ],
          "word": "CZAR",
          "correct": "ruler"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Keep their EQUILIBRIUM.",
          "answers": [
            "balance",
            "interest",
            "position",
            "high spirits",
            "distance"
          ],
          "word": "EQUILIBRIUM",
          "correct": "balance"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "GRIM times.",
          "answers": [
            "busy",
            "harsh",
            "cold",
            "old",
            "dull"
          ],
          "word": "GRIM",
          "correct": "harsh"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_1": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "Does one hundred EXCEED one thousand?",
          "word": "EXCEED",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would a book of famous sayings be a COMPILATION?",
          "word": "COMPILE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Are people usually MASSACRED in hospitals?",
          "word": "MASSACRE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Does a LAVISH person save all his money?",
          "word": "LAVISH",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "If two statements CONTRADICT each other, can they both be true?",
          "word": "CONTRADICT",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can you OBTAIN knowledge by reading books?",
          "word": "OBTAIN",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do people who are in a hurry like to LINGER?",
          "word": "LINGER",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can a baby UTTER sounds?",
          "word": "UTTER",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do people like to be AMUSED?",
          "word": "AMUSEMENT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do people enjoy being CASUALTIES?",
          "word": "CASUALTY",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is CONCEIT usually considered a bad quality?",
          "word": "CONCEITED",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Could a GULLY be dry?",
          "word": "GULLY",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Does Russia still have a CZAR?",
          "word": "CZAR",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Should a tightrope walker keep his EQUILIBRIUM?",
          "word": "EQUILIBRIUM",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do GRIM men laugh a lot?",
          "word": "GRIM",
          "correct": "false"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_2": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "She finally EXCEEDED in getting the car to start.",
          "word": "EXCEED",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The lawyer COMPILED a great deal of evidence that showed the defendant was innocent.",
          "word": "COMPILE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Thousands of people were MASSACRED by the fierce invaders.",
          "word": "MASSACRE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He LAVISHED so many treats on the puppy that it soon became quite fat.",
          "word": "LAVISH",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Bob CONTRADICTED me and said it really wasn't true.",
          "word": "CONTRADICT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Once she had the beautiful painting, she OBTAINED it all her life.",
          "word": "OBTAIN",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Some of these superstitions LINGERED on despite the scientific evidence against them.",
          "word": "LINGER",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "She UTTERED him to wipe his feet before he came into the kitchen.",
          "word": "UTTER",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The teacher showed no sign of AMUSEMENT at the students' practical joke.",
          "word": "AMUSEMENT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He tried to be a CASUALTY but people could tell he was really quite excited.",
          "word": "CASUALTY",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Sarah tried to be CONCEITED and let other people take all the glory.",
          "word": "CONCEITED",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The water flowed rapidly through the long GULLY.",
          "word": "GULLY",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "In the old days, one CZAR would rule the entire industry; now it is so big several people have to run things.",
          "word": "CZAR",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The angrier he got, the more his EQUILIBRIUM increased.",
          "word": "EQUILIBRIUM",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He takes a GRIM delight in tormenting the younger children.",
          "word": "GRIM",
          "correct": "true"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_3": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "EXCEED",
          "answers": [
            "outdo",
            "better",
            "renew"
          ],
          "word": "EXCEED",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "COMPILE",
          "answers": [
            "gather",
            "add",
            "change"
          ],
          "word": "COMPILE",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "MASSACRE",
          "answers": [
            "attack",
            "chase",
            "kill"
          ],
          "word": "MASSACRE",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "LAVISH",
          "answers": [
            "useful",
            "generous",
            "wasteful"
          ],
          "word": "LAVISH",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "CONTRADICT",
          "answers": [
            "dislike",
            "dispute",
            "disprove"
          ],
          "word": "CONTRADICT",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "OBTAIN",
          "answers": [
            "earn",
            "gain",
            "like"
          ],
          "word": "OBTAIN",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "LINGER",
          "answers": [
            "remain",
            "end",
            "delay"
          ],
          "word": "LINGER",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "UTTER",
          "answers": [
            "announce",
            "cry",
            "remember"
          ],
          "word": "UTTER",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "AMUSEMENT",
          "answers": [
            "danger",
            "fun",
            "pleasure"
          ],
          "word": "AMUSEMENT",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "CASUALTY",
          "answers": [
            "problem",
            "death",
            "disaster"
          ],
          "word": "CASUALTY",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "CONCEITED",
          "answers": [
            "self-satisfied",
            "happy",
            "proud"
          ],
          "word": "CONCEITED",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "GULLY",
          "answers": [
            "drain",
            "hill",
            "channel"
          ],
          "word": "GULLY",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "CZAR",
          "answers": [
            "senator",
            "king",
            "dictator"
          ],
          "word": "CZAR",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "EQUILIBRIUM",
          "answers": [
            "stability",
            "softness",
            "steadiness"
          ],
          "word": "EQUILIBRIUM",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "GRIM",
          "answers": [
            "cruel",
            "chilly",
            "severe"
          ],
          "word": "GRIM",
          "correct": "1"
        }
      ]
    },
    "definitions": {
      "EXCEED": {
        "word": "EXCEED",
        "phonetic": "(ek-sEd')",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to go beyond, be greater than, outdo \nTo EXCEED means to _go beyond_. The word is used in various senses of _going beyond_: _going beyond_ what is necessary, for example, or what is allowed, or what someone else has done. \n\"The driver EXCEEDED the speed limit by going ninety miles an hour.\" \n\"The captain EXCEEDED the general's orders when he told his men to attack immediately.\" \n\"Her swimming ability EXCEEDED everyone else's.\" \n\"The price of the car EXCEEDS what we want to pay for it.\" \nOther forms of the word: EXCESS, n. EXCESSIVE, adj."
      },
      "COMPILE": {
        "word": "COMPILE",
        "phonetic": "(kÔøΩm-pll')",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to collect, assemble, gather together \nTo COMPILE is to _collect_. The word is especially applied to collecting information or items of any kind and arranging this material into a book, report, chart, or the like. \n\"They COMPILED a list of voters who might favor their candidate.\" \n\"We COMPILED a chart of average salaries using figures we received from the government.\" \nThe word can also mean to _gather together_ or _pile up_. \n\"He COMPILED all the figures necessary for the report.\" \n\"The candidate COMPILED a huge number of votes in the election.\" \nA COMPILATION is something (like a book or list) that has been put together from other sources. \n\"This book is a COMPILATION of the best sports stories of the year.\" \nOther forms of the word: COMPILATION, n."
      },
      "MASSACRE": {
        "word": "MASSACRE",
        "phonetic": "(mas'-ÔøΩkÔøΩr)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "a general slaughter, mass killing \nA MASSACRE is the cruel killing of a large number of people. The word is especially used about the killing of people who are not able to defend themselves. \n\"The soldiers shot the people in cold blood, but everyone was too scared to talk about the MASSACRE.\" \nMASSACRE is also a verb, meaning \"to kill in a MASSACRE,\" to _slaughter_. \n\"The enemy MASSACRED all the women and children in town.\" \nMASSACRE is often confused with _battle_. Both may involve fighting and killing, but they do not have the same meaning."
      },
      "LAVISH": {
        "word": "LAVISH",
        "phonetic": "(lav'-ish)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "unlimited, profuse, extravagant, overly generous \nLAVISH comes from an old French word meaning \"a downpour of rain.\" To be LAVISH is to give or produce something abundantly, to pour it forth like raindrops. The word often has the sense that too much is being given or produced. LAVISH is used about the person giving something or about the thing being given. \n\"He was LAVISH in his praise of her singing.\" \n\"He wrote some LAVISH praise of her singing.\" \n\"When he struck it rich, he became a LAVISH spender. He wanted to buy everything.\" \nLAVISH is also a verb. \n\"He LAVISHED praise on the new novel.\""
      },
      "CONTRADICT": {
        "word": "CONTRADICT",
        "phonetic": "(kon-trÔøΩdikt')",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to deny, dispute \nCONTRADICT comes from Latin words which mean to _speak against_. To CONTRADICT something is to say or show that it is untrue. \n\"We CONTRADICTED his statement that the Earth is flat.\" \n\"Bill had evidence that CONTRADICTED my theory.\" \nYou can also CONTRADICT a person. \n\"The girl CONTRADICTED him when he said that New York City was the capital of New York.\" \nCONTRADICT can also mean \"to be the opposite of, be contrary to.\" \n\"Your two statements CONTRADICT each other. Which is true?\" \nOther forms of the word: CONTRADICTION, n. CONTRADICTORY, adj."
      },
      "OBTAIN": {
        "word": "OBTAIN",
        "phonetic": "(ob-tAn'",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to get, gain possession of \nTo OBTAIN something is to _get_ it. OBTAIN often suggests more effort or planning or a longer wait than _get_. \n\"I managed to OBTAIN two tickets for the game Saturday night.\" \n\"Jane finally OBTAINED a new pair of skis.\" \n\"He OBTAINED the right book from another library.\" \nThe most commonly chosen wrong answer on the Pretest is _keep_. This may be due to confusion with the word _retain_, which means to _keep_ or _hold on to_. OBTAIN has to do only with _getting_ something, not _keeping_ it."
      },
      "LINGER": {
        "word": "LINGER",
        "phonetic": "(ling'-gar)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to stay, remain, delay; to continue to exist \nTo LINGER is to stay in a place longer than usual or expected. \n\"We LINGERED on the beach long after everyone else had gone home.\" \n\"I LINGERED for a long time over that one beautiful painting before passing on to the next one.\" \nLINGER also means \"to continue to exist although becoming weaker.\" \n\"After his heart attack, he LINGERED for only a few days before dying.\" \n\"A few very old customs still LINGER on among the natives.\" \nUsage: LINGER is sometimes followed by _on_."
      },
      "UTTER": {
        "word": "UTTER",
        "phonetic": "(uht'-ÔøΩ)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to speak, say \nUTTER basically means \"to make a sound with the mouth.\" \n\"She UTTERED a little cry of disappointment.\" \nFrom this, UTTER is usually used to mean _speak_ or _say words_. \n\"Bobby had reached the stage when it seemed that the only word he could UTTER was _no_.\" \n\"The last word he UTTERED was 'Goodbye.'\" \nThe noun form of UTTER is UTTERANCE, which means _something spoken_. \n\"She thought his every UTTERANCE was extremely funny.\" \nIn the Pretest item, _make up_ is the most common incorrect choice. The word UTTER involves only speaking and making sounds, however, not thinking or planning. \nOther forms of the word: UTTERANCE, n."
      },
      "AMUSEMENT": {
        "word": "AMUSEMENT",
        "phonetic": "(ÔøΩmyUz'-mant)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "fun, entertainment \nTo AMUSE someone is to make the time pass pleasantly for him, especially by making him laugh. \n\"We AMUSED ourselves by looking at old photographs.\" \n\"The comedian AMUSED everyone in the audience.\" \nAMUSEMENT is the state of being AMUSED. See _-ment_ under Suffixes. \n\"The kitten's playful actions gave everyone a great deal of AMUSEMENT.\" \nAn AMUSEMENT is also something that AMUSES a person. \n\"There are plenty of AMUSEMENTS for little children at the fair.\" \nMany people choose _excitement_ as the meaning of AMUSEMENT. Something that AMUSES you does not have to be exciting, though. \nOther forms of the word: AMUSE,v."
      },
      "CASUALTY": {
        "word": "CASUALTY",
        "phonetic": "(kazh'-U-al-tE)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "an accident; a victim \nA CASUALTY is an accident in which someone is injured or killed. \n\"The heavy storm caused several traffic CASUALTIES.\" \nThe person who is killed or injured is also called a CASUALTY. \n\"Seven CASUALTIES resulted from the explosion.\" \nThe word is often used about injured or killed soldiers. \n\"Each side suffered hundreds of CASUALTIES during the battle.\""
      },
      "CONCEITED": {
        "word": "CONCEITED",
        "phonetic": "(kÔøΩn-sE'-tid)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "vain, proud, egotistical \nCONCEIT is an overly high opinion of yourself, a feeling that you are superior to everyone else. \n\"His incredible CONCEIT caused him to believe that he was the greatest living writer.\" \nSomeone who is CONCEITED is full of CONCEIT. \n\"Jan was so CONCEITED she wouldn't speak to any of us. She said we weren't good enough for her.\" \n\"Her CONCEITED brother thinks he is the handsomest fellow in the world.\" \nThe most commonly chosen wrong answer is _humble_, which is the exact opposite of CONCEITED. \nOther forms of the word: CONCEIT, n."
      },
      "GULLY": {
        "word": "GULLY",
        "phonetic": "(guhl'-E)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "a ditch, channel \nA GULLY is a ditch or channel, formed by running water, which serves as a natural drain for rainwater. \n\"Several GULLIES in the side of the hill overflowed during the heavy rains.\" \nMany people choose _stream_ as the meaning of GULLY. A GULLY might have been formed by a stream, but it is really the channel in which water is carried, not the water itself."
      },
      "CZAR": {
        "word": "CZAR",
        "phonetic": "(zahr)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "a ruler, emperor \nNote the pronunciation; the _c_ is silent. CZAR is a Russian word which came originally from the name _Caesar_. The CZAR was the ruler of Russia in the days before the Russian Revolution of 1917. \n\"CZAR Ivan the Terrible was a cruel ruler of Russia during the sixteenth century.\" \nCZAR has also come to be used about anyone who has absolute power and authority. \n\"The police said that this man was the CZAR of organized crime in this part of the country.\" \n\"The movie CZAR decided that his studio should also make television shows.\" \nUsage: CZAR is also sometimes spelled _tsar_."
      },
      "EQUILIBRIUM": {
        "word": "EQUILIBRIUM",
        "phonetic": "(E-kwÔøΩlib'-rE-ÔøΩm)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "balance \nEQUILIBRIUM comes from Latin words meaning _equal balance_. EQUILIBRIUM is the state of being balanced, especially when the balance is due to the equal action of opposing forces. The word is often used in science, but it is also in general use. \n\"He lost his EQUILIBRIUM as he walked along the top of the fence, and he tumbled to the ground.\" \nThe word is often used with regard to a person's emotional balance. \n\"She had difficulty recovering her EQUILIBRIUM after someone in the audience yelled an insult at her.\" \nEQUILIBRIUM is also used about balances in society. \n\"The EQUILIBRIUM of the social order was destroyed when the population of one of the two major groups in the country increased dramatically in a short period of time.\""
      },
      "GRIM": {
        "word": "GRIM",
        "phonetic": "(grim)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "harsh, severe, stern, forbidding; ghastly \nGRIM means _stern_, _severe_. The word is used about the way people look. \n\"The GRIM expression on his face told us he was quite angry.\" \nIt is also used about conditions or actions that are harsh or unpleasant. \n\"Neither fighter could stand up at the end of the GRIM struggle.\" \n\"It was his GRIM task to count the dead bodies.\" \nThe phrase \"GRIM necessity\" applies to something that is unpleasant but has to be done. \n\"GRIM necessity forced us to drink the dirty water.\" \nSometimes GRIM has an even stronger sense of _ghastly_, _horrifying_. \n\"It was a GRIM tale of murder and torture.\""
      }
    }
  },
  {
    "title": "3.11",
    "pretest": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "He is the TYRANT.",
          "answers": [
            "dictator",
            "priest",
            "newcomer",
            "president",
            "teacher"
          ],
          "word": "TYRANT",
          "correct": "dictator"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Where do they RESIDE?",
          "answers": [
            "meet",
            "work",
            "perform",
            "live",
            "travel"
          ],
          "word": "RESIDE",
          "correct": "live"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "IMMORTAL fame.",
          "answers": [
            "brief",
            "undying",
            "human",
            "general",
            "great"
          ],
          "word": "IMMORTAL",
          "correct": "undying"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Understood the PACT.",
          "answers": [
            "crowd",
            "argument",
            "result",
            "agreement",
            "article"
          ],
          "word": "PACT",
          "correct": "agreement"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "To RECOIL suddenly.",
          "answers": [
            "draw back",
            "give up",
            "attack",
            "fall down",
            "turn"
          ],
          "word": "RECOIL",
          "correct": "draw back"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "INFLICT the punishment.",
          "answers": [
            "stop",
            "lay on",
            "escape",
            "accept",
            "ask for"
          ],
          "word": "INFLICT",
          "correct": "lay on"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Understood his INTENTION.",
          "answers": [
            "wish",
            "opposition",
            "nervousness",
            "demand",
            "purpose"
          ],
          "word": "INTENTION",
          "correct": "purpose"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Clear OBLIGATION.",
          "answers": [
            "right",
            "duty",
            "statement",
            "opportunity",
            "command"
          ],
          "word": "OBLIGATION",
          "correct": "duty"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "To PORTRAY him.",
          "answers": [
            "deceive",
            "forget",
            "picture",
            "meet",
            "talk to"
          ],
          "word": "PORTRAY",
          "correct": "picture"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "STATIONARY vehicles.",
          "answers": [
            "official",
            "speedy",
            "unmoving",
            "temporary",
            "broken"
          ],
          "word": "STATIONARY",
          "correct": "unmoving"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "RENOVATE the building.",
          "answers": [
            "clean",
            "tear down",
            "sell",
            "leave",
            "restore"
          ],
          "word": "RENOVATE",
          "correct": "restore"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "SKETCHY knowledge.",
          "answers": [
            "new",
            "growing",
            "incomplete",
            "forgotten",
            "misleading"
          ],
          "word": "SKETCHY",
          "correct": "incomplete"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "They TOPPLED the statue.",
          "answers": [
            "pushed over",
            "set up",
            "finished",
            "marked",
            "destroyed"
          ],
          "word": "TOPPLE",
          "correct": "pushed over"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "To YEARN for it.",
          "answers": [
            "work",
            "wait",
            "plan",
            "long",
            "come"
          ],
          "word": "YEARN",
          "correct": "long"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "DRAB rugs.",
          "answers": [
            "colorless",
            "tom",
            "striped",
            "bright",
            "filthy"
          ],
          "word": "DRAB",
          "correct": "colorless"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_1": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "Is a TYRANT cruel?",
          "word": "TYRANT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do people often RESIDE in factories?",
          "word": "RESIDE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Are you IMMORTAL?",
          "word": "IMMORTAL",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can countries make PACTS with one another?",
          "word": "PACT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do you like something that makes you RECOIL?",
          "word": "RECOIL",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is it possible to INFLICT damage on a car if you hit it with a hammer?",
          "word": "INFLICT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Does an INTENTION have to do with the future?",
          "word": "INTENTION",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do parents have an OBLIGATION to care for their children?",
          "word": "OBLIGATION",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can you PORTRAY a person in a story?",
          "word": "PORTRAY",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is a jet STATIONARY when it is in the air?",
          "word": "STATIONARY",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would a brand new building have been RENOVATED?",
          "word": "RENOVATE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would most people want to go to a doctor who has a SKETCHY knowledge of medicine?",
          "word": "SKETCHY",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would it be difficult to TOPPLE a mountain?",
          "word": "TOPPLE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do most people YEARN for happiness?",
          "word": "YEARN",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Are rainbows DRAB?",
          "word": "DRAB",
          "correct": "false"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_2": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "At work he was mild and kind, but at home he was an unjust TYRANT to his children.",
          "word": "TYRANT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "After living in a cottage all summer, he returned to his permanent RESIDENCE.",
          "word": "RESIDE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Mona Lisa was IMMORTALIZED in Leonardo Da Vinci's painting.",
          "word": "IMMORTAL",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The heavy PACT was almost impossible to carry.",
          "word": "PACT",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He RECOILED at the thought of eating raw oysters.",
          "word": "RECOIL",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "I have never been so INFLICTED in my life as when I heard that we had won the lottery.",
          "word": "INFLICT",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "I INTEND to go to Europe some day, no matter how much it costs.",
          "word": "INTENTION",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "I have no OBLIGATION to help you do your homework.",
          "word": "OBLIGATION",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The actor PORTRAYED a character who loved money more than anything else.",
          "word": "PORTRAY",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "We bolted the wobbly table to the wall so that it would remain STATIONARY.",
          "word": "STATIONARY",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The landlord called in a wrecking crew to RENOVATE the building.",
          "word": "RENOVATE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Her SKETCHY voice was very unpleasant to listen to.",
          "word": "SKETCHY",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The ice cream was TOPPLED with a chocolate sauce.",
          "word": "TOPPLE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Mrs. Jones YEARNED to see her children.",
          "word": "YEARN",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "She bought new curtains to brighten up the DRAB room.",
          "word": "DRAB",
          "correct": "true"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_3": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "TYRANT",
          "answers": [
            "dictator",
            "soldier",
            "oppressor"
          ],
          "word": "TYRANT",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "RESIDE",
          "answers": [
            "sleep",
            "live",
            "dwell"
          ],
          "word": "RESIDE",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "IMMORTAL",
          "answers": [
            "endless",
            "deathless",
            "useless"
          ],
          "word": "IMMORTAL",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "PACT",
          "answers": [
            "agreement",
            "refusal",
            "treaty"
          ],
          "word": "PACT",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "RECOIL",
          "answers": [
            "shove",
            "shrink",
            "flinch"
          ],
          "word": "RECOIL",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "INFLICT",
          "answers": [
            "harm",
            "tighten",
            "destroy"
          ],
          "word": "INFLICT",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "INTENTION",
          "answers": [
            "goal",
            "aim",
            "need"
          ],
          "word": "INTENTION",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "OBLIGATION",
          "answers": [
            "must",
            "duty",
            "choice"
          ],
          "word": "OBLIGATION",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "PORTRAY",
          "answers": [
            "paint",
            "describe",
            "hear"
          ],
          "word": "PORTRAY",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "STATIONARY",
          "answers": [
            "standing",
            "unattached",
            "motionless"
          ],
          "word": "STATIONARY",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "RENOVATE",
          "answers": [
            "relieve",
            "repair",
            "rebuild"
          ],
          "word": "RENOVATE",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "SKETCHY",
          "answers": [
            "vague",
            "imperfect",
            "ancient"
          ],
          "word": "SKETCHY",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "TOPPLE",
          "answers": [
            "push",
            "climb",
            "fall"
          ],
          "word": "TOPPLE",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "YEARN",
          "answers": [
            "hope",
            "expect",
            "desire"
          ],
          "word": "YEARN",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "DRAB",
          "answers": [
            "old",
            "gray",
            "dull"
          ],
          "word": "DRAB",
          "correct": "0"
        }
      ]
    },
    "definitions": {
      "TYRANT": {
        "word": "TYRANT",
        "phonetic": "(tl-rÔøΩnt)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "a dictator, cruel ruler \nA TYRANT is a person who seizes power in a country and then proceeds to rule in a very cruel and unfair way. A TYRANT is a _dictator_, a person whose word is law. \n\"The TYRANT grew wealthy by placing taxes on just about everything.\" \n\"The people hated the TYRANT who ruled over them in such a cruel fashion.\" \nThe word TYRANT is also used about any person who rules others unfairly. \n\"He thinks his mother is a TYRANT just because she won't let him drive at night.\" \nOther forms of the word: TYRANNICAL, adj. TYRANNIZE, v. TYRANNY, n."
      },
      "RESIDE": {
        "word": "RESIDE",
        "phonetic": "(ri-zld')",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to live, dwell \nTo RESIDE in a place is to live there, to have your home there. \n\"He RESIDES in Florida now.\" \n\"She RESIDES in one state, but works in another.\" \nA RESIDENCE is a place where someone lives, a _home_, especially a large or dignified one. \n\"Their RESIDENCE is the brick house at the end of the street.\" \nIt is also the act of RESIDING. \n\"After years of living in a house we took up RESIDENCE in an apartment.\" \nOther forms of the word: RESIDENCE, n. RESIDENTIAL, adj."
      },
      "IMMORTAL": {
        "word": "IMMORTAL",
        "phonetic": "(i-mort'-1)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "undying, deathless, lasting forever \nSee _in-2_ under Prefixes and _-al_ under Suffixes. The Latin word __mors means death. It is the source of the words _mortal_ and _mortality_. Someone or something that is IMMORTAL will not die, will last forever. The word is usually applied to people's souls or to their actions and achievements. \n\"Patrick Henry said those IMMORTAL words, 'Give me liberty or give me death!'\" \n\"Everyone should read Shakespeare's IMMORTAL plays.\" \nTo IMMORTALIZE something is to make it last or be remembered forever. \n\"Longfellow's poem IMMORTALIZED Paul Revere's ride.\" \nOther forms of the word: IMMORTALITY, n. IMMORTALIZE, v."
      },
      "PACT": {
        "word": "PACT",
        "phonetic": "(pakt)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "an agreement, compact \nA PACT is an agreement between persons or groups. \n\"We made a PACT that neither of us would tell the secret.\" \nPACT is often used when referring to agreements or treaties between countries. \n\"The two nations signed a PACT that each would help the other in time of war.\" \n\"The PACT limited the size of each nation's army.\""
      },
      "RECOIL": {
        "word": "RECOIL",
        "phonetic": "(ri-koyl')",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to draw back, move backward, shrink \nSee _re-_ under Prefixes. To RECOIL is to draw back or jump back, especially because of fear, horror, or disgust. \n\"I RECOILED when he offered to let me hold the spider.\" \nRECOIL does not always suggest an actual physical movement. You can RECOIL inwardly from something as well. \n\"They RECOILED in horror from the idea of visiting the haunted house.\" \nRECOIL is also used with regard to a gun kicking back when it is fired. \n\"He steadied himself so that he wouldn't be knocked over when the rifle RECOILED.\""
      },
      "INFLICT": {
        "word": "INFLICT",
        "phonetic": "(in-flikt')",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to lay on, impose \nTo INFLICT something is to cause it to be suffered. You always INFLICT something unpleasant or painful, like damage or physical punishment. \n\"The bomb INFLICTED serious damage on the city.\" \n\"The bully INFLICTED a terrible beating on him.\" \nOther forms of the word: INFLICTION, n. \nUsage: INFLICT is usually used with _on_: to INFLICT something on someone."
      },
      "INTENTION": {
        "word": "INTENTION",
        "phonetic": "(in-ten'-shÔøΩn)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "purpose, aim \nINTEND means \"to have in mind as something to be done.\" \n\"I INTEND to go to the beach this summer.\" \nAn INTENTION is something that you have in mind that you want to do, a _purpose_ or _goal_. \n\"I have no INTENTION of watching television tonight.\" \n\"His INTENTIONS were good, but he didn't carry them out.\" \n\"She announced her INTENTION to run for mayor in the next election.\" \nMany people think an INTENTION is a _wish_. The words are close in meaning, but INTENTION suggests a much stronger determination to do something. Anyone can wish to be famous, for example; but if it is your INTENTION, you are going to work hard to see that it happens. \nOther forms of the word: INTEND, v. INTENTIONAL, adj."
      },
      "OBLIGATION": {
        "word": "OBLIGATION",
        "phonetic": "(ob-lÔøΩgA'-shÔøΩn)",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "a duty, responsibility \nAn OBLIGATION is something that you must do (or not do). It is a duty that results from a law, a custom, a promise, or the like. \n\"He felt he had an OBLIGATION to help those less fortunate than he was.\" \n\"You have an OBLIGATION to pay back the money I lent you.\" \n\"He carried out his OBLIGATION to the company, and then felt he didn't have to do anything more.\" \n\"There is no OBLIGATION to buy anything. We just want you to try our product for ten days.\" \nOther forms of the word: OBLIGE, v."
      },
      "PORTRAY": {
        "word": "PORTRAY",
        "phonetic": "(por-trA')",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to picture, describe, represent \nTo PORTRAY means \"to make a picture of\" someone or something. You can PORTRAY by painting. \n\"He PORTRAYED the queen as a beautiful young woman in the painting.\" \nOr you can PORTRAY in words. \n\"The king is PORTRAYED as a villain in this novel.\" \nActors PORTRAY characters on stage; that is, they present a picture of the characters. \n\"She PORTRAYED Hamlet's mother in the play.\" \nA PORTRAIT is a picture, particularly a painting of a person. \n\"Whistler painted a famous PORTRAIT of his mother.\" \nThe most commonly chosen wrong answer in the Pretest item is _deceive_, probably because of confusion with _betray_. \nOther forms of the word: PORTRAIT, n."
      },
      "STATIONARY": {
        "word": "STATIONARY",
        "phonetic": "(stA'-shÔøΩner-E)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "unmoving, fixed in position \nSTATIONARY is related to the word STATION. Both come from a Latin word meaning to _stand_. One meaning of STATION is \"a place where something or someone stands.\" \n\"A guard should never leave his STATION.\" \nSomething that is STATIONARY stands in one place; it cannot or does not move. \n\"Nothing was moving on the whole street. All the cars were STATIONARY.\" \n\"These heavy machines are STATIONARY; once they are set in place they can't be moved.\""
      },
      "RENOVATE": {
        "word": "RENOVATE",
        "phonetic": "(ren'-ÔøΩvAt)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to restore, renew, revive \nSee _re-_ under Prefixes and _-ate1_ under Suffixes. The _nov_ part of the word comes from the Latin word for _new_, also the source of the words _novel_ and _novelty_. To RENOVATE something is to make it new again. The word is usually applied to the restoring and repairing of old buildings so that they are like new again. \n\"We would like to RENOVATE our apartment. We want to fix it up completely.\" \n\"The kitchen was old-fashioned and had to be RENOVATED before they could sell the house.\" \nMany people think RENOVATE means _tear down_, which means just about the opposite. \nOther forms of the word: RENOVATION, n."
      },
      "SKETCHY": {
        "word": "SKETCHY",
        "phonetic": "(skech'-E)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "incomplete, like a SKETCH, without details \nA SKETCH is an outline of something, a quick drawing, not the complete picture. Anything that is SKETCHY is like a SKETCH. It is incomplete, lacking in detail. See _-y_ under Suffixes. The word is used especially about understanding or information that is only vague and incomplete. \n\"Her understanding of algebra is somewhat SKETCHY.\" \n\"He could only give us SKETCHY directions on how to get there.\" \n\"We had only a SKETCHY idea of what the movie was supposed to be about.\" \nOther forms of the word: SKETCH, n., v."
      },
      "TOPPLE": {
        "word": "TOPPLE",
        "phonetic": "(top'-ÔøΩI)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to fall, fall over; to push over, overturn \nTo TOPPLE is to _fall over_, especially from being too heavy on top. \n\"He piled the bricks so high that the stack TOPPLED.\" \n\"The strong winds finally caused the tree to TOPPLE with a crash.\" \nTo TOPPLE something is to push it over or overturn it. \n\"The mean boys TOPPLED the snowman we had just finished.\" \nThe word is often used about the overthrowing of someone in a position of authority. \n\"The rebels TOPPLED the dictator's government.\""
      },
      "YEARN": {
        "word": "YEARN",
        "phonetic": "(yern)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to long, pine \nTo YEARN for something is to desire it strongly, usually with an eager or tender kind of feeling. \n\"He YEARNED for one last chance to see his native land.\" \n\"Billy YEARNED to be a famous baseball player.\" \n\"The prisoner YEARNED to be free.\" \nYEARNING is the noun from YEARN. A YEARNING is a longing or a strong desire. \n\"She felt a deep YEARNING to help humanity.\" \n\"He never satisfied his YEARNING for more money.\" \nOther forms of the word: YEARNING, n."
      },
      "DRAB": {
        "word": "DRAB",
        "phonetic": "(drab)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "dull, monotonous, uninteresting, colorless \nSomething that is DRAB is uninteresting, colorless, lifeless. \n\"His wife's lovely personality lent color to his otherwise DRAB existence.\" \nThe word DRAB is also used in a more specific sense to describe a dull, muddy brown or gray color. \n\"The DRAB color scheme of the room made it lifeless and uninviting.\" \nMany people think DRAB means _filthy_. Something may be colorless and dull, however, and still be perfectly clean."
      }
    }
  },
  {
    "title": "3.12",
    "pretest": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "It was REVOLTING.",
          "answers": [
            "foolish",
            "fascinating",
            "forbidden",
            "disgusting",
            "frightening"
          ],
          "word": "REVOLTING",
          "correct": "disgusting"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "ENTRENCHED in their positions.",
          "answers": [
            "fixed firmly",
            "lowered",
            "supported",
            "expected",
            "left"
          ],
          "word": "ENTRENCH",
          "correct": "fixed firmly"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "IDLE machines.",
          "answers": [
            "slow",
            "busy",
            "perfect",
            "poor",
            "unused"
          ],
          "word": "IDLE",
          "correct": "unused"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "They ERECTED the statue.",
          "answers": [
            "moved",
            "tore down",
            "straightened",
            "raised up",
            "admired"
          ],
          "word": "ERECT",
          "correct": "raised up"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Wanted to EVALUATE it.",
          "answers": [
            "buy",
            "destroy",
            "rate",
            "improve",
            "sell"
          ],
          "word": "EVALUATE",
          "correct": "rate"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "NEGLIGENT parents.",
          "answers": [
            "harsh",
            "helpful",
            "hardworking",
            "easygoing",
            "careless"
          ],
          "word": "NEGLIGENT",
          "correct": "careless"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "SERENE attitude.",
          "answers": [
            "eager",
            "peaceful",
            "disgusting",
            "necessary",
            "hopeful"
          ],
          "word": "SERENE",
          "correct": "peaceful"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "POTENTIAL candidates.",
          "answers": [
            "usual",
            "hopeless",
            "powerful",
            "possible",
            "young"
          ],
          "word": "POTENTIAL",
          "correct": "possible"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "They OBSTRUCTED the corridor.",
          "answers": [
            "built",
            "opened up",
            "blocked",
            "destroyed",
            "stood in"
          ],
          "word": "OBSTRUCT",
          "correct": "blocked"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "RADIANT expressions.",
          "answers": [
            "sorrowful",
            "glowing",
            "unfriendly",
            "confident",
            "cheerful"
          ],
          "word": "RADIANT",
          "correct": "glowing"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Wanted to SCOLD.",
          "answers": [
            "find fault",
            "praise",
            "burn",
            "get out",
            "argue"
          ],
          "word": "SCOLD",
          "correct": "find fault"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He is SINCERE.",
          "answers": [
            "wicked",
            "untrustworthy",
            "honest",
            "polite",
            "innocent"
          ],
          "word": "SINCERE",
          "correct": "honest"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "VICIOUS men.",
          "answers": [
            "strong",
            "silly",
            "cruel",
            "lively",
            "angry"
          ],
          "word": "VICIOUS",
          "correct": "cruel"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Unable to CONFINE it.",
          "answers": [
            "stretch",
            "limit",
            "improve",
            "destroy",
            "hurt"
          ],
          "word": "CONFINE",
          "correct": "limit"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Heard of her DEBUT.",
          "answers": [
            "first appearance",
            "departure",
            "mistake",
            "engagement",
            "acting skill"
          ],
          "word": "DEBUT",
          "correct": "first appearance"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_1": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "Is the smell of roses REVOLTING?",
          "word": "REVOLTING",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is it easy to remove someone who is ENTRENCHED?",
          "word": "ENTRENCH",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would you hire a worker who liked to be IDLE?",
          "word": "IDLE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Are apartment houses ERECTED?",
          "word": "ERECT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is a student's performance in school EVALUATED when he receives a grade?",
          "word": "EVALUATE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is a good worker NEGLIGENT about his job?",
          "word": "NEGLIGENT",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is a football game usually SERENE?",
          "word": "SERENE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Has the POTENTIAL winner of a race already won it?",
          "word": "POTENTIAL",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would a blade of grass OBSTRUCT a highway?",
          "word": "OBSTRUCT",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is the sun RADIANT?",
          "word": "RADIANT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do most people dislike being SCOLDED?",
          "word": "SCOLD",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Are the words of a liar SINCERE?",
          "word": "SINCERE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Are most dogs VICIOUS?",
          "word": "VICIOUS",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Are people ever CONFINED as a punishment?",
          "word": "CONFINE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Could a person be old when he makes a DEBUT?",
          "word": "DEBUT",
          "correct": "true"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_2": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "Everyone was REVOLTED by the brutality of the crime.",
          "word": "REVOLTING",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Walter tried to change their minds, but their views were too firmly ENTRENCHED.",
          "word": "ENTRENCH",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The typewriter is always being used; it is never IDLE.",
          "word": "IDLE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "A new hospital will be ERECTED here next year.",
          "word": "ERECT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The cost of buying a house is EVALUATING every day.",
          "word": "EVALUATE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "We accused him of NEGLIGENCE in not making sure his dog was tied up.",
          "word": "NEGLIGENT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "They were all so SERENE to me that I burst into tears.",
          "word": "SERENE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Your idea for a business has POTENTIAL, but you will have to work hard if you want it to succeed.",
          "word": "POTENTIAL",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "We tried to OBSTRUCT them about the best way to reach the park.",
          "word": "OBSTRUCT",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "A year after her operation she seemed to be in RADIANT good health.",
          "word": "RADIANT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "My mother SCOLDED me for not doing my homework.",
          "word": "SCOLD",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "She sent them a gift to show her SINCERE appreciation for their help.",
          "word": "SINCERE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "This VICIOUS criminal should be put in prison before he harms anyone else.",
          "word": "VICIOUS",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "They were both CONFINED a hundred dollars for the offense.",
          "word": "CONFINE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The DEBUT of the new singer was postponed for a night.",
          "word": "DEBUT",
          "correct": "true"
        }
      ]
    },
    "exercise_3": {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "REVOLTING",
          "answers": [
            "illegal",
            "evil",
            "shocking"
          ],
          "word": "REVOLTING",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "ENTRENCH",
          "answers": [
            "dig",
            "stay",
            "change"
          ],
          "word": "ENTRENCH",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "IDLE",
          "answers": [
            "lonely",
            "lazy",
            "inactive"
          ],
          "word": "IDLE",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "ERECT",
          "answers": [
            "improve",
            "lift",
            "build"
          ],
          "word": "ERECT",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "EVALUATE",
          "answers": [
            "determine",
            "admire",
            "judge"
          ],
          "word": "EVALUATE",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "NEGLIGENT",
          "answers": [
            "sloppy",
            "lazy",
            "silly"
          ],
          "word": "NEGLIGENT",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "SERENE",
          "answers": [
            "late",
            "quiet",
            "happy"
          ],
          "word": "SERENE",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "POTENTIAL",
          "answers": [
            "actual",
            "future",
            "likely"
          ],
          "word": "POTENTIAL",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "OBSTRUCT",
          "answers": [
            "bother",
            "build",
            "hinder"
          ],
          "word": "OBSTRUCT",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "RADIANT",
          "answers": [
            "brilliant",
            "sparkling",
            "smart"
          ],
          "word": "RADIANT",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "SCOLD",
          "answers": [
            "yell",
            "blame",
            "help"
          ],
          "word": "SCOLD",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "SINCERE",
          "answers": [
            "young",
            "open",
            "honest"
          ],
          "word": "SINCERE",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "VICIOUS",
          "answers": [
            "sinful",
            "stupid",
            "evil"
          ],
          "word": "VICIOUS",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "CONFINE",
          "answers": [
            "imprison",
            "limit",
            "release"
          ],
          "word": "CONFINE",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "DEBUT",
          "answers": [
            "introduction",
            "beginning",
            "job"
          ],
          "word": "DEBUT",
          "correct": "2"
        }
      ]
    },
    "definitions": {
      "REVOLTING": {
        "word": "REVOLTING",
        "phonetic": "(ri-vOl'-ting)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "disgusting, shocking, offensive \nThe verb to REVOLT has two meanings: to _rebel_—to REVOLT against the government—and to _disgust_. \n\"The sight of all that garbage REVOLTS me.\" \nREVOLTING comes from this second use and means _disgusting_, _offensive_. \n\"I thought the language in that play was REVOLTING.\" \n\"Their REVOLTING behavior makes me sick.\" \nOther forms of the word: REVOLT, v."
      },
      "ENTRENCH": {
        "word": "ENTRENCH",
        "phonetic": "(en-trench')",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to place inside a trench, surround with a trench; to establish solidly, fix firmly \nA _trench_ is a long narrow ditch, with the earth from the ditch usually piled up in front of it to serve as protection against an enemy. To be ENTRENCHED is to be surrounded with trenches so that it is very difficult for anyone to attack or overrun you. \n\"The army ENTRENCHED itself near the town, and the enemy could do nothing about it.\" \nFrom this military use, ENTRENCH has come to mean to _establish firmly_ in any kind of situation. \n\"With the passage of time, he became more firmly ENTRENCHED in his position.\" \nThe image is always of someone digging in to become strongly or solidly established."
      },
      "IDLE": {
        "word": "IDLE",
        "phonetic": "(Id'-1)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "unused, unemployed, useless; lazy \nIDLE has several meanings, all of which have the idea \"without any purpose or use.\" IDLE thoughts are useless thoughts, ones that have no particular reason or purpose. An IDLE machine is not being used. \n\"During the strike all the factories were IDLE.\" \nAn IDLE person isn't doing anything. \n\"We worked hard during the week, but on the weekends we were IDLE.\" \nIDLE is often used about a person who doesn't _want_ to do anything, who is lazy and avoids work. \n\"He is an IDLE sort of boy. He never wants to do anything.\""
      },
      "ERECT": {
        "word": "ERECT",
        "phonetic": "(i-rekt')",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to set up, raise upright, build, construct \nTo ERECT is to set in an upright position. Someone who stands ERECT is standing up straight, without leaning forward or backward. To ERECT something is to put it in this ERECT position. \n\"He ERECTED the flagpole.\" \nERECT means about the same as _build_, except that it usually adds this sense of raising something upright. \n\"They spent six months building the foundation, and then they ERECTED the ninety-story tower.\" \nThings other than buildings can be ERECTED. \n\"They ERECTED legal barriers against foreigners entering the country.\""
      },
      "EVALUATE": {
        "word": "EVALUATE",
        "phonetic": "(i-val'-yU-At)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to rate, estimate, appraise \nTo EVALUATE something is to judge its value. \n\"They EVALUATED the program at the end of the year and decided that it wasn't worth the expense.\" \n\"The critic EVALUATES several new books in this article.\" \n\"It is difficult to EVALUATE the effect this will have on us.\" \nOn the Pretest, many people choose _improve_ as a synonym for EVALUATE, probably because the word looks like _value_ and _valuable_. To EVALUATE is to _judge_ something's value, however, not to _improve_ its value. \nOther forms of the word: EVALUATION, n."
      },
      "NEGLIGENT": {
        "word": "NEGLIGENT",
        "phonetic": "(neg'-li-j:>nt)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "careless, neglectful \nNEGLIGENT is one of the adjective forms of NEGLECT. To be NEGLIGENT is to be careless; a NEGLIGENT person doesn't pay attention to or do what he is supposed to. \n\"Tom is NEGLIGENT about the way he dresses; he always looks as though he dressed in the dark.\" \n\"The NEGLIGENT waiter forgot to bring the dessert.\" \nNEGLIGENCE is the noun form of NEGLIGENT. \n\"The accident was due to the other driver's NEGLIGENCE. He forgot to look both ways before pulling out into the street.\" \nOther forms of the word: NEGLECT, v. NEGLIGENCE, n."
      },
      "SERENE": {
        "word": "SERENE",
        "phonetic": "(sÔøΩrEn')",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "peaceful, calm, tranquil \nSERENE means _peaceful_ and _calm_. The word often has a noble and dignified sense to it. Someone who is SERENE is above the troubles and cares of the world. \n\"While everyone else was angry and upset she remained SERENE.\" \n\"They were SERENELY happy for the first year of their marriage.\" \n\"We hoped that the weather would be SERENE on the day of our picnic.\" \nThe noun from SERENE is SERENITY, meaning _calmness_, _peacefulness_. \n\"Nothing disturbed the SERENITY of their life together.\" \nOther forms of the word: SERENITY,n."
      },
      "POTENTIAL": {
        "word": "POTENTIAL",
        "phonetic": "(pÔøΩten'-shÔøΩI",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "possible \nPOTENTIAL comes from the Latin word for _power_. Something that is POTENTIAL has the power to exist or develop. \n\"This is a POTENTIAL problem. It isn't a problem now, but it may be one in the future.\" \n\"This boy is a great football player. He is a POTENTIAL All-American.\" \nPOTENTIAL is also a noun. \n\"She has the POTENTIAL to become an opera singer\"—that is, she isn't one now, but she has the talent to become one. \nPOTENTIAL is often confused with _powerful_. The word _potent_ means _powerful_, and the similarity between _potent_ and POTENTIAL probably causes the confusion."
      },
      "OBSTRUCT": {
        "word": "OBSTRUCT",
        "phonetic": "(ob-struhkt')",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to block, hinder, get in the way of \nTo OBSTRUCT something is to get in the way of it or to block it up. \n\"A pile of rocks OBSTRUCTED the road.\" \n\"The brick wall OBSTRUCTED our progress.\" \nTo OBSTRUCT a person's view of something is to cut it off from his or her sight. \n\"The new building OBSTRUCTED our view of the river.\" \nAn OBSTRUCTION is something that blocks or gets in the way. \n\"We must remove all OBSTRUCTIONS from our path.\" \nOther forms of the word: OBSTRUCTION,n."
      },
      "RADIANT": {
        "word": "RADIANT",
        "phonetic": "(rA'-dE-ÔøΩnt)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "shining, bright, glowing \nTo RADIATE is to send out light, heat, or other kinds of rays. Something that is RADIANT is bright and glowing; it looks as if it were sending out rays of light. See _-ant_ under Suffixes. \n\"Her RADIANT smile lights up the room.\" \n\"They all admired the RADIANT beauty of the statue.\" \n\"The children's faces were RADIANT with happiness when they saw their father.\" \nMany people pick _cheerful_ as the meaning of RADIANT. RADIANT is often used to describe people who are feeling positive emotions like joy or love, but it means _bright_ or _shining_, not _cheerful_. \nOther forms of the word: RADIANCE, n. RADIATE, v."
      },
      "SCOLD": {
        "word": "SCOLD",
        "phonetic": "(skOld)",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to find fault with, reproach \nTo SCOLD someone is to find fault with him, usually noisily or angrily. The word suggests an angry or upset parent yelling at a disobedient child. \n\"She SCOLDED him for walking across the clean floor in his dirty boots.\" \n\"The teacher SCOLDED us for not paying attention.\" \nSCOLD is sometimes used as a noun. A SCOLD is someone who is always finding fault. \n\"That woman is just a SCOLD. You can't do anything without her yelling at you.\""
      },
      "SINCERE": {
        "word": "SINCERE",
        "phonetic": "(sin-sEr')",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "honest, not pretended \nSINCERE means _honest_, _open_, _straightforward_. The word is used about people and the way they act. \n\"Were you SINCERE when you said you loved me?\" \n\"He looked at his father with SINCERE admiration.\" \n\"She spoke SINCERELY of her desire to end the strike.\" \nThe noun from SINCERE is SINCERITY. \n\"No one doubted his SINCERITY. He honestly believed he was right.\" \nMany people think SINCERE means _polite_. Sometimes, however, people who are _polite_ are not SINCERE. They say things they don't mean just to be friendly. \nOther forms of the word: SINCERITY, n."
      },
      "VICIOUS": {
        "word": "VICIOUS",
        "phonetic": "(vish'-ÔøΩs)",
        "pos": "adj.",
        "deftext": "cruel, evil, spiteful, immoral \nVICIOUS is related to the word _vice_, which means _evil_ or an _evil habit_. \n\"His only _vice_ is that he gambles too much.\" \nVICIOUS means \"practicing or showing _vice_,\" particularly violent or cruel vices. See _-ous_ under Suffixes. \n\"He is a VICIOUS murderer. He would kill anyone to make a few dollars.\" \n\"She aimed a VICIOUS kick at the dog, but fortunately she missed.\" \n\"He made some VICIOUS remarks about the man's honesty.\" \nThe most common mistakes for VICIOUS are _strong_ and _angry_. A VICIOUS person may be strong and angry, but neither _strong_ nor _angry_ suggests the evil and cruelty that are part of VICIOUS."
      },
      "CONFINE": {
        "word": "CONFINE",
        "phonetic": "(kÔøΩn-fln')",
        "pos": "v.",
        "deftext": "to limit, enclose, restrain \nTo CONFINE something is to keep it within limits. \n\"Please CONFINE your remarks to the subject we are discussing.\" \n\"His interests were CONFINED to the area of foreign policy.\" \nIn a related sense, the word often means \"to keep shut up\" in a particular place, often because of illness, punishment, or the like. \n\"The judge CONFINED him to prison for ten years.\" \n\"She was CONFINED to her bed all week with her cold.\" \nThe noun from CONFINE is CONFINEMENT. \n\"He couldn't stand CONFINEMENT. He liked to be outside, free to do what he pleased.\" \nOther forms of the word: CONFINEMENT, n."
      },
      "DEBUT": {
        "word": "DEBUT",
        "phonetic": "(dA-byU')",
        "pos": "n.",
        "deftext": "first appearance, beginning, introduction \nNote the pronunciation. DEBUT is a French word, and keeps its French pronunciation. A person's DEBUT is his or her first public appearance—on stage, in society, in a job, etc. \n\"He made his DEBUT as an actor in a small part in Hamlet.\" \n\"Dick's DEBUT as a teacher was terrifying for him. For the first time he had to face a class alone.\" \nOther forms of the word: DEBUTANTE, n."
      }
    },
    "reviewTest": {
      "wordList": [
        "CASUALTY",
        "EVALUATE",
        "MASSACRE",
        "RECOIL",
        "SKETCHY",
        "CONCEITED",
        "GRIM",
        "OBSTRUCT",
        "RENOVATE",
        "TOPPLE",
        "DRAB",
        "INFLICT",
        "POTENTIAL",
        "REVOLTING",
        "VICIOUS",
        "ENTRENCH",
        "INTENTION",
        "RADIANT",
        "SINCERE",
        "YEARN",
        "ERECT",
        "AMUSEMENT",
        "DEBUT",
        "IMMORTAL",
        "OBTAIN",
        "SERENE",
        "COMPILE",
        "EQUILIBRIUM",
        "LAVISH",
        "PACT",
        "STATIONARY",
        "CONFINE",
        "EXCEED",
        "LINGER",
        "PORTRAY",
        "TYRANT",
        "CONTRADICT",
        "GULLY",
        "NEGLIGENT",
        "RESIDE",
        "UTTER",
        "CZAR",
        "IDLE",
        "OBLIGATION",
        "SCOLD"
      ],
      "questions": [
        {
          "part1": "The actor only had a small part in the movie, but critics said he was a(n)",
          "part2": "star.",
          "answer": "potential"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The enemy tried to",
          "part2": "themselves in front of our city, but we managed to drive them away.",
          "answer": "entrench"
        },
        {
          "part1": "We can't afford to buy a new house, so we're going to",
          "part2": "this one and make it look like new.",
          "answer": "renovate"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Do you have any",
          "part2": "of carrying out your promise to return my money?",
          "answer": "intention"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Every holiday weekend there are hundreds of",
          "part2": "on our nation's highways.",
          "answer": "casualties"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Hal is very",
          "part2": "about his athletic ability. He thinks he's going to be an All-American his freshman year.",
          "answer": "conceited"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Everyone was killed in the",
          "part2": "which followed the capture of the village.",
          "answer": "massacre"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The",
          "part2": "criminals beat up the man and left him to die in the alley.",
          "answer": "vicious"
        },
        {
          "part1": "John was",
          "part2": "with happiness on the day he was married.",
          "answer": "radiant"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The job of the customs inspector is to",
          "part2": "the worth of articles brought into the country.",
          "answer": "evaluate"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The walls were",
          "part2": "and uninteresting, so he decided to paint them bright blue.",
          "answer": "drab"
        },
        {
          "part1": "I know very little Russian, so my understanding of what they were saying was, at best,",
          "part2": ".",
          "answer": "sketchy"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Even the doctor",
          "part2": "in horror when he first examined the victims of the fire.",
          "answer": "recoiled"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The man told a(n)",
          "part2": "tale of sickness and misery.",
          "answer": "grim"
        },
        {
          "part1": "They decided to",
          "part2": "a huge monument in memory of the king.",
          "answer": "erect"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The sight of all the bugs crawling over the food was",
          "part2": ".",
          "answer": "revolting"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Some people didn't believe Don, but I think he was",
          "part2": "when he said he was sorry.",
          "answer": "sincere"
        },
        {
          "part1": "A huge rock",
          "part2": "our path to the house.",
          "answer": "obstructed"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The blind boy",
          "part2": "to be able to see again.",
          "answer": "yearned"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The earthquake caused large buildings to",
          "part2": "to the ground.",
          "answer": "topple"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The boxer started to",
          "part2": "a great deal of damage on his opponent.",
          "answer": "inflict"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The rebels killed the dictator, but another",
          "part2": "took over the government.",
          "answer": "tyrant"
        },
        {
          "part1": "We found some rainwater to drink flowing slowly downhill in a small",
          "part2": ".",
          "answer": "gully"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Nicholas II, the last",
          "part2": "of Russia, was killed during the Russian Revolution.",
          "answer": "czar"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The cost of the party should not",
          "part2": "fifty dollars, since that is all the money we have.",
          "answer": "exceed"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Mary",
          "part2": "a list of everyone she wanted to invite to the party.",
          "answer": "compiled"
        },
        {
          "part1": "His",
          "part2": "as a third baseman was not very good. He made four errors in that first game.",
          "answer": "debut"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Mr. Allen was",
          "part2": "about paying his bills on time; as a result, his phone service was cut off.",
          "answer": "negligent"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Chet didn't like to be",
          "part2": ". He always wanted to be busy doing something.",
          "answer": "idle"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The marchers in the parade remained",
          "part2": "until they received the signal to move on.",
          "answer": "stationary"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The artist chose to",
          "part2": "her as a peasant girl in his painting.",
          "answer": "portray"
        },
        {
          "part1": "When we went to the bank for a loan, we were asked how long we had",
          "part2": "at our present address.",
          "answer": "resided"
        },
        {
          "part1": "His humorous stories gave us plenty of",
          "part2": ".",
          "answer": "amusement"
        },
        {
          "part1": "He didn't",
          "part2": "his speech to one topic, but talked about a variety of matters.",
          "answer": "confine"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The angry teacher",
          "part2": "Bill for being late for class.",
          "answer": "scolded"
        },
        {
          "part1": "June is always so",
          "part2": ". Nothing ever seems to worry her or make her angry.",
          "answer": "serene"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The judge ruled that the store had a(n)",
          "part2": "to refund Ted's money.",
          "answer": "obligation"
        },
        {
          "part1": "They made a solemn",
          "part2": "to always help each other.",
          "answer": "pact"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The man sought a magic drug that would make him",
          "part2": ", but like everyone else he finally died.",
          "answer": "immortal"
        },
        {
          "part1": "The boat always maintained its",
          "part2": "; whenever it was pushed one way, it would immediately right itself and continue on course.",
          "answer": "equilibrium"
        },
        {
          "part1": "At Thanksgiving, she always prepared a(n)",
          "part2": "meal, with more than enough to feed a dozen families.",
          "answer": "lavish"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Scott dislikes it when people",
          "part2": "him; he thinks if he says it, it must be true, and no one should say otherwise.",
          "answer": "contradict"
        },
        {
          "part1": "Bob tried to",
          "part2": "the record album, but none of the stores carried it.",
          "answer": "obtain"
        },
        {
          "part1": "A few fans",
          "part2": "for hours at the stage door, hoping that the actor would appear.",
          "answer": "lingered"
        },
        {
          "part1": "We were not allowed to",
          "part2": "a single word while we were taking the test.",
          "answer": "utter"
        }
      ]
    }
  }
]
